<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog</id>
    <title>ILLA Cloud Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-01-23T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog"/>
    <subtitle>ILLA Cloud Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/img/public/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>Copyright © 2024 ILLA.</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best tools for it support]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In ordinary companies, the IT department's Technical Support is responsible for managing the company's information system, database, machinery hardware equipment, etc.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>IT Support is divided into Technical Support and Program Support.</p>
<p>Technical Support requires technicians with a broad knowledge structure. Companies of a certain size all have an IT department, commonly referred to as network management, but not all companies have Program Support.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="job-content-of-it-support">Job Content of IT Support<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#job-content-of-it-support" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Job Content of IT Support" title="Direkter Link zu Job Content of IT Support">​</a></h2>
<p>In ordinary companies, the IT department's Technical Support is responsible for managing the company's information system, database, machinery hardware equipment, etc. If the company needs any special software or to update a new system, it is usually done by forming a team with programmers from a technology company and the company's own Program Support.</p>
<p>Technical Support is more like a consultant, guiding the more macroscopic direction, so they generally know a lot.</p>
<p>Program Support specializes more in coding.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="recommended-tools">Recommended Tools<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#recommended-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Recommended Tools" title="Direkter Link zu Recommended Tools">​</a></h2>
<p>In the course of IT Support work, we definitely need many tools to help us better complete our tasks, as every IT has many common needs. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>Handling work orders</li>
<li>Project management</li>
<li>Code management</li>
<li>Document management</li>
<li>Notifications</li>
<li>Meetings</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some recommended tools to help everyone better complete their work.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>If you're considering building a business-logic oriented tool and only require a beautiful UI without pursuing complex animations and flashy pages, ILLA Cloud is recommended for development and construction.</p>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
<li>CRM</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA Cloud lets you quickly build tools through drag-and-drop without needing to write code, boosting your work efficiency by 10 times. It also natively supports team collaboration, allowing you and your colleagues to edit and build together.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud also features connector capabilities, enabling quick connections to other SaaS tools you use. It supports scheduled tasks, Webhooks, parameter passing, and more.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud also includes an AI Agent feature, helping you quickly build AI-driven tools, such as text analysis, voice analysis, image analysis, and more.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/it-support/agent.png" alt="agent" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="linear">Linear<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#linear" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Linear" title="Direkter Link zu Linear">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/it-support/linear.png" alt="linear" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Linear is a project management tool that helps streamline software projects, sprints, tasks, and bug tracking. It is a simple, fast, and powerful tool built for high-performance teams.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#advantages" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Streamlined Project Management</strong>: Linear's focus on streamlining software projects suggests a user-friendly interface that simplifies complex project management tasks, making it easier for teams to follow through on project goals and deadlines.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Efficient Sprint and Task Management</strong>: With features tailored for managing sprints and tasks, Linear likely offers effective tools for Agile methodologies, facilitating better planning, tracking, and execution of software development cycles.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Effective Bug Tracking</strong>: The emphasis on bug tracking indicates that Linear provides robust tools for identifying, documenting, and resolving software bugs, which is crucial for maintaining software quality and reliability.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Speed and Simplicity</strong>: Being described as simple and fast, Linear might offer quick setup and ease of use, which can be particularly beneficial for teams looking to implement a tool without a steep learning curve.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Suitability for High-Performance Teams</strong>: Built for high-performance teams, Linear is likely optimized for efficiency and scalability, supporting teams in managing complex projects without performance degradation.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="disadvantages">Disadvantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#disadvantages" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages" title="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Potential Over-Simplification</strong>: While simplicity is an advantage, it might also mean that Linear lacks certain advanced features required by very large or complex projects, possibly limiting its utility for some specialized applications.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focus on Software Projects</strong>: Linear’s specific focus on software projects suggests it may not be as well-suited for other types of project management, limiting its versatility for non-software teams.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Learning Curve for New Users</strong>: Despite its simplicity, new users, especially those not familiar with Agile methodologies, might still face a learning curve in understanding how to best utilize the tool for their specific needs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Limited Customization</strong>: Fast and simple tools sometimes offer limited customization options, which might not meet the needs of teams that require highly tailored project management solutions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Dependence on Team Discipline</strong>: The effectiveness of any project management tool, including Linear, often depends on the team's discipline in using it consistently and correctly, which can be a challenge in some organizational cultures.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="gitlab">Gitlab<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#gitlab" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Gitlab" title="Direkter Link zu Gitlab">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/it-support/gitlab.png" alt="gitlab" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>GitLab is a complete DevOps platform, delivered as a single application. It enables Concurrent DevOps to make the software lifecycle 200% faster, radically improving the speed of business.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-1">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#advantages-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Integrated DevOps Workflow</strong>: As a single application offering a complete DevOps solution, GitLab provides an integrated environment for all stages of software development, from planning to monitoring, which can greatly simplify the workflow.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Increased Efficiency</strong>: GitLab's emphasis on Concurrent DevOps suggests it supports simultaneous actions in the development cycle, which can lead to a 200% faster software lifecycle, thereby accelerating the pace of business.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>All-in-One Platform</strong>: The platform's all-in-one nature means that teams can avoid the hassle of integrating multiple separate tools, which can reduce complexity and potential compatibility issues.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Streamlined Collaboration</strong>: GitLab likely facilitates better collaboration among team members by providing a unified platform for code repository, issue tracking, CI/CD, and more, which can enhance teamwork and productivity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Visibility and Transparency</strong>: Having all aspects of the DevOps cycle in one place can provide better visibility and transparency across the development process, enabling more informed decision-making.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="disadvantages-1">Disadvantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#disadvantages-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages" title="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Learning Curve</strong>: The comprehensive nature of GitLab may present a steep learning curve, especially for teams not accustomed to such an all-encompassing platform or those transitioning from simpler tools.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resource Intensiveness</strong>: Given its wide range of functionalities, GitLab could be resource-intensive, requiring significant server resources, which might be a challenge for smaller organizations or teams with limited IT infrastructure.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Overwhelming for Small Projects</strong>: For smaller projects or teams, the extensive features of GitLab might be more than what is necessary, potentially leading to underutilization of the platform.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Potential for Vendor Lock-in</strong>: Relying on a single platform for all DevOps needs may lead to vendor lock-in, where teams become dependent on GitLab and might face challenges if they decide to switch to another tool in the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cost Considerations</strong>: While GitLab offers a variety of plans, including a free tier, the more advanced features, essential for larger teams and complex projects, are often part of their paid plans, which could be a significant expense for some organizations.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="notion">Notion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#notion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Notion" title="Direkter Link zu Notion">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/it-support/notion.png" alt="notion" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Notion is an all-in-one workspace for your notes, tasks, wikis, and databases. It is a simple, fast, and powerful tool built for high-performance teams.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-2">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#advantages-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Versatility</strong>: As an all-in-one workspace, Notion offers a versatile platform where you can manage a variety of content types like notes, tasks, wikis, and databases. This versatility can streamline different aspects of work within a single application.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Ease of Use</strong>: Described as simple and fast, Notion likely has a user-friendly interface, allowing for quick adoption and ease of use. This can reduce the learning curve and increase productivity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Customizability</strong>: Notion's platform generally allows for a high degree of customization, enabling users to tailor it to their specific workflow needs, whether for individual use or team collaboration.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Collaboration Features</strong>: Being built for high-performance teams, Notion is expected to have robust collaboration features, facilitating effective teamwork, information sharing, and project management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Integration Capabilities</strong>: Notion often integrates well with other tools, which is beneficial for teams that use a variety of applications and services for their work.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="disadvantages-2">Disadvantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#disadvantages-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages" title="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Potentially Overwhelming for New Users</strong>: The vast array of features and customization options in Notion can be overwhelming for new users, particularly those who are looking for a more straightforward, plug-and-play type solution.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Limited Offline Capabilities</strong>: Notion's functionality can be limited when offline, which could be a drawback for users who need to access their workspace in areas with poor or no internet connectivity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Performance Issues with Large Databases</strong>: As databases grow in size, some users have reported performance issues with Notion, such as slower loading times and lag, which can hinder efficiency.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Limited Export Options</strong>: While Notion is great for accumulating and organizing information, exporting this data out of Notion can sometimes be a challenge, potentially causing issues with data portability.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cost Factor for Premium Features</strong>: While Notion offers a free tier, more advanced features and larger usage limits are gated behind their paid plans, which could be a consideration for budget-conscious individuals or small teams.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-flow">ILLA Flow<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#illa-flow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Flow" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Flow">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/it-support/connector.png" alt="connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA Flow is a low-code workflow tool that helps you automate your business processes. It is a simple, fast, and powerful tool built for high-performance teams.</p>
<p>You can build your own workflow through a drag-and-drop interface, and then execute your workflow by scheduling triggers or Webhook triggers.</p>
<p>The smooth drag-and-drop experience allows you to quickly build workflows without worrying about any integration issues. The entire system is driven by JavaScript, ensuring flexibility while also being developer-friendly.</p>
<p>ILLA Flow supports multiple trigger types, including scheduled triggers and Webhook triggers.</p>
<p>We use ILLA Flow to do lots of things, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Send a message to Slack when a new user registers</li>
<li>Report the number of stars on GitHub every day</li>
<li>Book a meeting room every day</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>Our engineers use ILLA Flow to automate many tasks, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Read some business data from databases and send to Slack every day</li>
<li>Build a CI/CD report system</li>
<li>Send email when some warning occurs</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/it-support#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>For IT Support, simple and easy-to-use tools are key to enhancing work efficiency. Choosing the right tools for your needs is crucial. Hopefully, everyone can find useful tools and become an outstanding IT Support.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="workflow" term="workflow"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Die besten Tools für Bürgerentwickler im Jahr 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In den letzten Jahrzehnten war die Anwendungsentwicklung ausschließlich das Gebiet von IT-Programmierern, aber dies könnte sich in der Zukunft ändern!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In den letzten Jahrzehnten war die Anwendungsentwicklung ausschließlich das Gebiet von IT-Programmierern, aber dies könnte sich in der Zukunft ändern!</p>
<p>Angesichts der zunehmend wettbewerbsintensiven Geschäftsanforderungen ist der einzige Weg für Unternehmen, sich zu entwickeln, ihre Geschäftsfähigkeiten zu erhöhen und die Liefergeschwindigkeit zu beschleunigen, ohne zusätzliche Kosten zu verursachen.</p>
<p>Um den digitalen Herausforderungen, denen Unternehmen gegenüberstehen, gerecht zu werden, ebnet die Bürgerentwicklung (CD) den Weg für nicht-technische Geschäftsanwender (auch als Bürgerentwickler bekannt). Mit von der IT genehmigten Low Code/No Code (LCNC) Plattformen ist es möglich, unternehmensweite Anwendungen in einer effizienten, flexiblen und benutzerfreundlichen Umgebung intuitiv zu erstellen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="der-wert-der-bürgerentwicklung">Der Wert der Bürgerentwicklung<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#der-wert-der-b%C3%BCrgerentwicklung" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Der Wert der Bürgerentwicklung" title="Direkter Link zu Der Wert der Bürgerentwicklung">​</a></h2>
<p>Laut dem Project Management Institute (PMI) wird die Bürgerentwicklung ein Störfaktor dieser neuen Norm sein, und viele Low-Code/No-Code-Plattformen haben dies bereits ihren Kunden und Partnern gezeigt. In der praktischen Anwendung hat LCNC seine Fähigkeit bewiesen, die Komplexität der Anwendungsentwicklung bei minimalen Kosten erheblich zu reduzieren. Bisher haben viele Organisationen mit der Einführung der Bürgerentwicklung in ihren Betriebsabläufen begonnen, um schnelle Veränderungen zu stimulieren und einen einzigartigen Fußabdruck in der Gemeinschaft zu hinterlassen und so die Gesamtproduktivität zu steigern. Besonders in der heutigen digitalen Welt spielt Low-Code/No-Code eine wichtige Rolle dabei, Unternehmen dabei zu helfen, das unbegrenzte Potenzial dieses neuen digitalen Raums zu nutzen und Innovationen leicht zu entfachen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="empfohlene-tools">Empfohlene Tools<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#empfohlene-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Empfohlene Tools" title="Direkter Link zu Empfohlene Tools">​</a></h2>
<p>Als Bürgerentwickler mit grundlegenden Computerkenntnissen benötigen Sie verschiedene Tools, um Ihre Arbeit zu unterstützen. Hier sind einige empfohlene Tools, um Ihre Arbeit effizienter zu gestalten.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p>Wenn Sie darüber nachdenken, ein geschäftslogikorientiertes Tool zu erstellen und nur eine schöne Benutzeroberfläche ohne komplexe Animationen und auffällige Seiten benötigen, wird ILLA Cloud für die Entwicklung und Konstruktion empfohlen.</p>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> ist ein sofort einsatzbereites Low-Code-Tool, mit dem Sie interne Tools schnell und einfach mit einfachem JS erstellen können, ohne neue Projekte erstellen zu müssen.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Daten-Dashboard</li>
<li>Anpassbare B2B-Tools</li>
<li>CRM</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA Cloud ermöglicht es Ihnen, schnell Tools per Drag-and-Drop zu erstellen, ohne Code schreiben zu müssen, wodurch Ihre Arbeitseffizienz um das 10-fache gesteigert wird. Es unterstützt auch nativ die Zusammenarbeit im Team, sodass Sie und Ihre Kollegen gemeinsam bearbeiten und erstellen können.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud verfügt auch über Connector-Funktionen, mit denen Sie schnell Verbindungen zu anderen von Ihnen verwendeten SaaS-Tools herstellen können. Es unterstützt geplante Aufgaben, Webhooks, Parameterübergabe und mehr.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/connector.png" alt="connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA Cloud enthält auch eine KI-Agentenfunktion, die Ihnen beim schnellen Aufbau KI-gesteuerter Tools wie Textanalyse, Sprachanalyse, Bildanalyse und mehr hilft.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/agent.png" alt="agent" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="webflow">Webflow<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#webflow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Webflow" title="Direkter Link zu Webflow">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/webflow.png" alt="webflow" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Wenn Sie darüber nachdenken, ein benutzerorientiertes Tool mit hohen UI-Anforderungen zu erstellen, das komplexe Animationen und coole Seiten sucht, wird Webflow für die Entwicklung und Konstruktion empfohlen.</p>
<p>Webflow unterstützt natürlicherweise eine Vielzahl von Animationsfunktionen und leistungsstarken UI-Konfigurationen, die es Ihnen ermöglichen, in kürzester Zeit atemberaubende Seiten zu erstellen. Es passt sich auch nativ an mobile Geräte an.</p>
<p>Die Community von Webflow bietet eine Fülle von Vorlagen, die verschiedene Geschäftsanforderungen unterstützen, wie E-Commerce, Blogs, Unternehmenswebsites und mehr.</p>
<p>Webflow enthält auch ein CRM-Backend zur Verwaltung von Website-Besuchern, was die Notwendigkeit für sekundäre Entwicklungen bei grundlegenden Verwaltungsaufgaben beseitigt und eine schnelle Nutzung ermöglicht.</p>
<p>Natürlich unterstützt Webflow auch Hosting-Services ohne jegliche Betriebskosten.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="supabase">Supabase<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#supabase" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Supabase" title="Direkter Link zu Supabase">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool/supabase.png" alt="supabase" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Wenn Sie eine Online-Site erstellt haben, verwenden Sie Webflow für die benutzerorientierten Teile und ILLA Cloud für interne Tools. Aber Ihnen fehlt immer noch ein wichtiges Element.</p>
<p>Für die Daten in Ihrer Geschäftsentwicklung benötigen Sie einen Ort zur Speicherung.</p>
<p>Supabase wird für die Speicherung empfohlen und bietet folgende Vorteile:</p>
<ul>
<li>Entwicklerfreundlich, für super komplexe und einfache Geschäftsanforderungen geeignet.</li>
<li>Skalierbar, wächst dynamisch mit Ihrem Unternehmen, sodass Sie sich keine Gedanken über technische Probleme aufgrund schnellen Geschäftswachstums machen müssen.</li>
<li>Unterstützt verschiedene SDKs zur Kompatibilität mit verschiedenen Technologien.</li>
<li>Einfache Bedienung mit SQL, da Supabase auf PostgreSQL basiert und schnelle Datenmanipulation ermöglicht.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="fazit">Fazit<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-citizen-developer-tool#fazit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Fazit" title="Direkter Link zu Fazit">​</a></h2>
<p>Für Bürgerentwickler sind einfache und benutzerfreundliche Tools entscheidend, um die Arbeitseffizienz zu steigern. Die Auswahl der richtigen Tools für Ihre Anforderungen ist entscheidend. Hoffentlich können alle nützliche Tools finden und herausragende Bürgerentwickler werden.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Bürgerentwickler" term="Bürgerentwickler"/>
        <category label="Bürgerentwicklung" term="Bürgerentwicklung"/>
        <category label="Bürgerentwicklungs-Tool" term="Bürgerentwicklungs-Tool"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Appsmith vs Retool: Welche Open-Source Low-Code-Plattform ist besser?]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In der sich ständig weiterentwickelnden Welt der Low-Code-Entwicklungsplattformen haben sich Appsmith und Retool als starke Konkurrenten etabliert, die jeweils einzigartige Funktionen und Fähigkeiten bieten. Diese Plattformen zielen darauf ab, die Anwendungsentwicklung zu vereinfachen und Organisationen zu befähigen, benutzerdefinierte interne Tools effizient zu erstellen. In diesem umfassenden Vergleich werden wir die Stärken und Schwächen beider Plattformen erkunden und eine erstklassige Alternative, ILLA Cloud, vorstellen, um Ihnen bei Ihrer Low-Code-Entwicklungsaufgabe eine informierte Entscheidung zu ermöglichen.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In der sich ständig weiterentwickelnden Welt der Low-Code-Entwicklungsplattformen haben sich Appsmith und Retool als starke Konkurrenten etabliert, die jeweils einzigartige Funktionen und Fähigkeiten bieten. Diese Plattformen zielen darauf ab, die Anwendungsentwicklung zu vereinfachen und Organisationen zu befähigen, benutzerdefinierte interne Tools effizient zu erstellen. In diesem umfassenden Vergleich werden wir die Stärken und Schwächen beider Plattformen erkunden und eine erstklassige Alternative, ILLA Cloud, vorstellen, um Ihnen bei Ihrer Low-Code-Entwicklungsaufgabe eine informierte Entscheidung zu ermöglichen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-das-beste-softwareentwicklungswerkzeug">ILLA Cloud: Das beste Softwareentwicklungswerkzeug<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#illa-cloud-das-beste-softwareentwicklungswerkzeug" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: Das beste Softwareentwicklungswerkzeug" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: Das beste Softwareentwicklungswerkzeug">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> ist ein sofort einsatzbereites Low-Code-Tool, das schnelles Erstellen interner Tools mit einfachem JS ermöglicht, ohne neue Projekte erstellen zu müssen.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web- &amp; App-Admin-Panel</li>
<li>Daten-Dashboard</li>
<li>Anpassbare B2B-Tools</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Im Vergleich zur Verwendung einer Komponentenbibliothek ermöglicht ILLA Cloud eine 10-mal schnellere Tool-Erstellung und unterstützt die gemeinsame Bearbeitung innerhalb von Teams.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="appsmith">Appsmith<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Appsmith" title="Direkter Link zu Appsmith">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/appsmith.png" alt="appsmith" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Appsmith, eine Open-Source-Plattform mit Sitz in Indien, hat sich schnell in der Low-Code-Entwicklungswelt einen Namen gemacht. Es kann in vielen Aspekten mit dem Retool-Anwendungsersteller konkurrieren, was es zu einem ernsthaften Mitbewerber macht. Es ist jedoch wichtig, sich mit den spezifischen Eigenschaften auseinanderzusetzen, die Appsmith auszeichnen:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="vorteile-von-appsmith">Vorteile von Appsmith:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#vorteile-von-appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Vorteile von Appsmith:" title="Direkter Link zu Vorteile von Appsmith:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Open-Source-Vorteil: Appsmith ist eine Open-Source-Plattform und stellt Entwicklern den Zugriff auf den Quellcode der Plattform zur Verfügung. Diese Offenheit fördert die Zusammenarbeit und Anpassung und macht es zur bevorzugten Wahl für diejenigen, die mehr Kontrolle über ihre Entwicklungsumgebung benötigen.</li>
<li>Cloud- und On-Premise-Bereitstellung: Appsmith bietet Flexibilität, da es sowohl Cloud- als auch vollständige On-Premise-Bereitstellungen unterstützt. Diese Dualität ermöglicht es Organisationen, die Hosting-Option zu wählen, die ihren Sicherheits- und Compliance-Anforderungen entspricht.</li>
<li>Aktive Entwicklergemeinschaft: Appsmith verzeichnet ein wachsendes Entwickler-Community auf Plattformen wie Github. Diese Community-Unterstützung führt zu kontinuierlichen Verbesserungen, rechtzeitigen Fehlerbehebungen und der Entwicklung neuer Funktionen, um sicherzustellen, dass die Plattform aktuell bleibt und auf die Bedürfnisse der Benutzer reagiert.</li>
<li>Umfangreiche Integrationsmöglichkeiten: Appsmith erleichtert die Integration mit einer breiten Palette von Datenbanken und APIs und ermöglicht Unternehmen eine nahtlose Verbindung zu ihren Datenquellen. Diese Vielseitigkeit stellt sicher, dass Ihre Anwendungen mit den notwendigen Datenressourcen interagieren können.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="nachteile-von-appsmith">Nachteile von Appsmith:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#nachteile-von-appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Nachteile von Appsmith:" title="Direkter Link zu Nachteile von Appsmith:">​</a></h3>
<p>Fehlende Automatisierte Workflows: Eine bemerkenswerte Einschränkung ist das Fehlen von Unterstützung für automatisierte Workflows oder geplante Aufgaben innerhalb von Appsmith. Dies könnte ein Nachteil für Organisationen sein, die komplexe Automatisierungsprozesse in ihren internen Tools benötigen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retool-ein-vorreiter-bei-internen-tools">Retool: Ein Vorreiter bei internen Tools<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#retool-ein-vorreiter-bei-internen-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool: Ein Vorreiter bei internen Tools" title="Direkter Link zu Retool: Ein Vorreiter bei internen Tools">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/retool.png" alt="retool" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Retool ist eine etablierte Entwicklungsplattform zur Erstellung benutzerdefinierter interner Software. Es bietet einen intuitiven Drag-and-Drop-Anwendungsersteller und eine Bibliothek von vordefinierten UI-Komponenten. Es ist jedoch wichtig, sowohl seine Stärken als auch seine Schwächen zu erkennen:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="vorteile-von-retool">Vorteile von Retool:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#vorteile-von-retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Vorteile von Retool:" title="Direkter Link zu Vorteile von Retool:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Drag &amp; Drop-Anwendungsersteller: Retool bietet einen intuitiven Drag-and-Drop-Anwendungsersteller, der auch Benutzern mit unterschiedlicher technischer Expertise zugänglich ist.</li>
<li>Integrationsbibliothek: Mit einer umfangreichen Integrationsbibliothek vereinfacht Retool den Prozess der Verbindung mit Datenbanken und APIs und ermöglicht Unternehmen den effizienten Zugriff und die Manipulation ihrer Daten.</li>
<li>Granulare Berechtigungen: Retool unterstützt rollenbasierte Zugriffskontrollen, die eine sichere Umgebung bieten und sicherstellen, dass Benutzer angemessenen Zugriff auf Tools und Daten haben.</li>
<li>Enterprise-Funktionen: Retool richtet sich an Unternehmensanforderungen und bietet Funktionen wie Single Sign-On (SSO), Audit-Protokollierung und dedizierte Unternehmensunterstützung.</li>
<li>Native Mobile Apps: Retool Mobile bietet eine dedizierte Lösung für die Erstellung von nativen iOS- und Android-Mobilanwendungen innerhalb der Retool-Umgebung.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="nachteile-von-retool">Nachteile von Retool:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#nachteile-von-retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Nachteile von Retool:" title="Direkter Link zu Nachteile von Retool:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Begrenzte Erweiterbarkeit mit Code: Die Erweiterbarkeit von Retool ist begrenzt und unterstützt hauptsächlich JavaScript. Diese Einschränkung kann Herausforderungen für Entwickler darstellen, die vielfältigere Codierungsoptionen benötigen.</li>
<li>Schlechte Leistung: Benutzer berichten häufig von Leistungsproblemen bei Retool-Anwendungen aufgrund der ausführungsbasierten Codeausführung im Browser, einzelner Schrittabfragen und fehlendem globalen Edge-Caching.</li>
<li>Begrenzte Workflows &amp; Geplante Aufgaben: Das Workflow-Angebot von Retool befindet sich noch in der Beta-Phase und bietet keine volle Funktionalität. Außerdem ist es nur auf Retool Cloud verfügbar, was den Zugang für selbst gehostete Kunden einschränkt.</li>
<li>Nur SQL-basierte Generative KI: Die generative KI-Funktionalität von Retool ist auf SQL beschränkt, was möglicherweise nicht den Anforderungen von Entwicklern für Codegenerierung und -optimierung in verschiedenen Sprachen und Anwendungsfällen entspricht.</li>
<li>Legacy On-Premise-Bereitstellung: Das On-Premise-Bereitstellungsmodell von Retool ist ressourcenintensiv und erschwert es Unternehmen, Tools zu warten und zu aktualisieren. Dies kann Ressourcen von der Tool-Entwicklung ablenken.</li>
<li>Hohe Kosten: Retool verwendet ein unflexibles Preismodell mit hohen Plattformgebühren, was es für viele Organisationen teuer macht.</li>
<li>Langsame Einführung neuer Funktionen: Neue Funktionen werden manchmal langsam eingeführt, insbesondere für selbst gehostete Kunden, was zu Verzögerungen bei der Nutzung der neuesten Technologien führt.</li>
<li>Geschlossener Quellcode: Retool ist Closed-Source, was Code-Prüfungen und Erweiterungsoptionen begrenzt.</li>
<li>Nur US-Cloud: Retool Cloud wird in den USA gehostet, was zu Leistungseinbußen für Benutzer und Rechenzentren außerhalb der USA führen kann.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-bietet-das-beste-aus-beiden-welten">ILLA Cloud bietet das Beste aus beiden Welten<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#illa-cloud-bietet-das-beste-aus-beiden-welten" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud bietet das Beste aus beiden Welten" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud bietet das Beste aus beiden Welten">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA ist eine der schnellsten Plattformen für die Entwicklung interner Tools. Es spart Entwicklern wertvolle Zeit bei der Webgestaltung und anderen Aspekten ihrer Arbeit. Einer der Hauptgründe, warum Entwickler zunehmend ILLA wählen, ist die Bibliothek. Die Plattform hat eine reiche Sammlung von Codekomponenten konzipiert, die Sie einfach ziehen und ablegen können, um komplexe Anwendungen in wenigen Minuten zu erstellen.</p>
<p>Sie können auch Anwendungsprogrammierschnittstellen verwenden, um ILLA mit einer Datenbank Ihrer Wahl zu verknüpfen. Die Plattform kann Backend- und Frontend-Daten hervorragend integrieren. Dadurch können Entwickler umfangreiche Informationen mit einfachen Datenaufträgen ermöglichen.</p>
<p>Jeder Entwickler wird ILLA aus zwei Gründen lieben - Freiheit und die Möglichkeit, gleichzeitig mit anderen Entwicklern zu arbeiten. Erstens können Entwickler überall JavaScript schreiben. Dies ermöglicht mehr Flexibilität in ihrer Arbeit und eine größere Vielfalt bei den Ergebnissen.</p>
<p>Zweitens können Entwickler in ILLA Builder Links mit anderen Fachleuten in Echtzeit teilen. Sie können also ihre Arbeit gemeinsam bearbeiten und kommentieren. Mit anderen Worten, Entwickler können in einer unterhaltsamen und kollaborativen Arbeitsumgebung arbeiten. Natürlich führt dies zu schnelleren und besseren Ergebnissen.</p>
<p>Schließlich können Entwickler ihre Arbeit immer bei sich tragen, wenn sie ILLA Cloud verwenden. Mit nur einem Klick von jedem Gerät aus haben sie Zugriff auf die Cloud und gelangen zur Benutzeroberfläche von ILLA.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="schlüsselfunktionen-von-illa">Schlüsselfunktionen von ILLA<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#schl%C3%BCsselfunktionen-von-illa" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Schlüsselfunktionen von ILLA" title="Direkter Link zu Schlüsselfunktionen von ILLA">​</a></h3>
<p>Hier sind die Schlüsselfunktionen von ILLA, die Sie kennen sollten:</p>
<ul>
<li>ILLA verfügt über eine einsatzbereite Bibliothek für React-Komponenten.</li>
<li>Am erstaunlichsten ist, dass das ILLA-Design-Tool eine TypeScript-Typisierungsfunktion bietet und eine vorhersehbare statische Typisierung unterstützt.</li>
<li>ILLA Design bietet eine schnelle und einfache Importfunktion, die die Produktivität von Entwicklern verbessert.</li>
<li>Sie können auf wunderschön gestaltete und leistungsstarke Themes und Komponenten zugreifen.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="aktualisierte-illa-funktionen">Aktualisierte ILLA-Funktionen<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#aktualisierte-illa-funktionen" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Aktualisierte ILLA-Funktionen" title="Direkter Link zu Aktualisierte ILLA-Funktionen">​</a></h3>
<p>Hier sind einige aktualisierte Funktionen von ILLA, die Sie kennen sollten:</p>
<ul>
<li>Schnelle Integration mit jeder Datenquelle</li>
<li>Sie können ILLA mit jeder gängigen Datenbank oder einer anderen Datenquelle verbinden. Dieses Tool ermöglicht es Ihnen, Daten aus dem Backend mit Frontend-Komponenten abzurufen.</li>
<li>Echtzeit-Zusammenarbeit zur Steigerung der Effizienz</li>
<li>ILLA Builder ermöglicht Entwicklern die Zusammenarbeit an einem Projekt. Sie können Links zu verschiedenen Entwicklern erstellen und teilen, um ihre Tools gemeinsam zu bearbeiten und in Echtzeit mit anderen Teammitgliedern zu kommunizieren.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="responsive-ui-bibliothek-um-ihre-bedürfnisse-zu-erfüllen">Responsive UI-Bibliothek, um Ihre Bedürfnisse zu erfüllen<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#responsive-ui-bibliothek-um-ihre-bed%C3%BCrfnisse-zu-erf%C3%BCllen" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI-Bibliothek, um Ihre Bedürfnisse zu erfüllen" title="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI-Bibliothek, um Ihre Bedürfnisse zu erfüllen">​</a></h3>
<p>ILLA Builder bietet auch zahlreiche Komponenten, um die Bedürfnisse jedes Entwicklers effizient zu erfüllen. Entwickler können auf den Drag-and-Drop-Builder zugreifen, um schnell ihre gewünschten internen Tools zu entwickeln.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="fazit">Fazit<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/appsmith-vs-retool#fazit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Fazit" title="Direkter Link zu Fazit">​</a></h2>
<p>Zusammenfassend sind Retool und Appsmith beide ausgezeichnete Low-Code-Plattformen, die Ihnen helfen können, Anwendungen schnell und effizient zu erstellen. Sie haben jedoch jeweils ihre eigenen Stärken und Schwächen, daher ist es wichtig, Ihre Anforderungen zu berücksichtigen, bevor Sie sich für eine entscheiden. Wenn Sie eine umfassende Plattform mit leistungsstarken Managementfunktionen suchen, ist Tooljet möglicherweise die bessere Option für Sie. Wenn Sie andererseits eine benutzerfreundliche Plattform suchen, die keine Programmierkenntnisse erfordert, ist Appsmith möglicherweise die bessere Wahl. Letztendlich hängt alles davon ab, welche Art von Entwickler Sie sind und welche Art von Anwendung Sie erstellen möchten.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="tooljet" term="tooljet"/>
        <category label="appsmith" term="appsmith"/>
        <category label="retool" term="retool"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tooljet vs Appsmitm: Which open-source low-code platform is better?]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re considering using a low-code development platform to build applications, you may wonder whether Tooljet or Appsmith is the better option.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re considering using a low-code development platform to build applications, you may wonder whether Tooljet or Appsmith is the better option. Both are open-source platforms with various features to choose from, but they each have their own strengths and weaknesses. This blog post will compare Tooljet and Appsmith to help you decide which is suitable for your needs.</p>
<p>Tooljet is excellent for those who prefer working with visual elements and drag-and-drop tools. Its user interface allows you to quickly create applications by simply dragging and dropping different components into place, making it easy and fast to build applications from the ground up. Additionally, Tooljet has powerful management features that allow you to collaborate with other users in real-time and monitor project progress.</p>
<p>Appsmith is an excellent option for developers who want more control over their applications. It offers a wide range of great features, such as API integration, triggers, and scripts that can add complex functionality to your apps. Moreover, Appsmith also provides an intuitive code editor, making it easy to write custom code in your projects if needed.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-the-best-software-development-tool">ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#illa-cloud-the-best-software-development-tool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Compared to building with a component library, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing within teams.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet-and-appsmith-are-two-popular-software-development-tools">Tooljet and Appsmith are two popular software development tools.<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#tooljet-and-appsmith-are-two-popular-software-development-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet and Appsmith are two popular software development tools." title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet and Appsmith are two popular software development tools.">​</a></h2>
<p>Tooljet and Appsmith are two extremely powerful software development tools that enable developers to create applications with data sources quickly and efficiently without too much hand coding. Both tools use intuitive drag-and-drop elements, code tools, data connectors, and a visual development process to help streamline business process management.</p>
<p>With their extensive feature sets, both Tooljet and Appsmith have successfully served many developers as they continue to rapidly develop data-driven applications. They prove time and time again that they are essential tools for any software developer with coding knowledge looking to create advanced data-driven applications in just a few simple steps.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet---better-for-those-who-want-more-control-over-their-project">Tooljet - better for those who want more control over their project<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#tooljet---better-for-those-who-want-more-control-over-their-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet - better for those who want more control over their project" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet - better for those who want more control over their project">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/tooljet.png" alt="tooljet" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Both Tooljet and Appsmith are powerful for citizen developers to do rapid application development. Tooljet provides flexibility with a more hands-on approach, allowing business users the control they need to create total admin panels with custom UI components.</p>
<p>It offers an intuitive user interface that allows users to rapidly design, develop, and manage applications through a series of drag-and-drop tools, visual elements, and data sources. Beyond its easy UI, Tooljet also boasts powerful features such as real-time collaboration, comprehensive project management capabilities, and built-in components.</p>
<p>This comprehensive suite of features makes it easier for developers to quickly build robust apps without worrying about coding from scratch. Tooljet also supports various coding languages, including Java, JavaScript, Python, and Ruby, giving developers even more freedom when creating custom applications. Additionally, Tooljet has extensive documentation for users looking for additional support when working on their projects.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="pros-of-tooljet">Pros of Tooljet:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#pros-of-tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Pros of Tooljet:" title="Direkter Link zu Pros of Tooljet:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intuitive and easy-to-use user interface that makes it simple to create applications quickly with drag-and-drop tools</li>
<li>Powerful management features to help collaborate with other users in real-time and monitor project progress</li>
<li>Built-in analytics and reporting tools to measure the performance, usage, and reliability of applications</li>
<li>A feature-rich platform that supports webhooks, API integration, and custom code for added complexity</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="cons-of-tooljet">Cons of Tooljet:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#cons-of-tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Cons of Tooljet:" title="Direkter Link zu Cons of Tooljet:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The visual approach means it can be difficult to troubleshoot problems without an understanding of the underlying code</li>
<li>Visual elements are limited, which may not provide enough flexibility for more complex projects</li>
<li>Limited support for third-party integrations, which could restrict the use cases for certain applications</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="appsmith---more-user-friendly">Appsmith - more user-friendly<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#appsmith---more-user-friendly" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Appsmith - more user-friendly" title="Direkter Link zu Appsmith - more user-friendly">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/appsmith.png" alt="appsmith" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>On the other hand, Appsmith is ideal for those who don’t have coding experience but still want to craft an app - it makes app development more accessible than ever with user-friendly tools that require no technical knowledge. Appsmith is an intuitive, user-friendly low-code platform for non-technical users to build robust data-driven applications quickly. With a simple drag-and-drop interface, you can easily create custom UI components and manage your projects with comprehensive project management capabilities.</p>
<p>Appsmith also offers advanced security features such as role-based access control to ensure that only authorized personnel access sensitive information. Additionally, Appsmith integrates with third-party services and supports webhooks, API integration, and custom code, which makes it a great choice for creating robust applications without the need to code from scratch.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="pros-of-appsmith">Pros of Appsmith:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#pros-of-appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Pros of Appsmith:" title="Direkter Link zu Pros of Appsmith:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Highly customizable features so developers can add complex functionality to their apps easily</li>
<li>Intuitive code editor makes it easy to write custom code into your projects if needed</li>
<li>Supports multiple programming languages such as JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, etc.</li>
<li>Flexible API integration allows users to connect various services together quickly and securely</li>
<li>A wide range of predefined templates and components make it easier to create new applications from scratch</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="cons-of-appsmith">Cons of Appsmith:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#cons-of-appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Cons of Appsmith:" title="Direkter Link zu Cons of Appsmith:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Not as beginner-friendly compared to other low-code platforms, which could limit its usefulness for certain users</li>
<li>Code changes can be tricky as they require manual adjustments every time they are made</li>
<li>More expensive than Tooljet, which may not make it a viable option for some budgets</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-offers-the-best-of-both-worlds">ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#illa-cloud-offers-the-best-of-both-worlds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA is one of the fastest platforms for internal tool development. It saves developers precious time on web design and other aspects of their job. One of the main reasons developers are increasingly choosing ILLA is the library. The platform has conjured a rich collection of code components that you can simply drag and drop and build complex applications within minutes.</p>
<p>You can also use application programming interfaces to join ILLA with a database of your choice. The platform can excellently integrate back-end and front-end data. As a result, developers can make vast information interactions possible with basic data calls.</p>
<p>Any developer will love ILLA for two reasons- freedom and the chance to work simultaneously with other developers. Firstly, developers can write JavaScript wherever they want. This permits more flexibility in their job and increased variety in results.</p>
<p>Secondly, developers can share links in ILLA Builder with other professionals in real time. Consequently, they can edit and comment on each other’s work as they go along. In other words, developers get to work in a fun and collaborative workspace. Naturally, this yields faster and improved results.</p>
<p>Lastly, developers can always carry their work with them when using ILLA cloud. Just one click from any device will give them access to the cloud and bring them to ILLA’s user interface.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="key-features-of-illa">Key features of ILLA<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#key-features-of-illa" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Key features of ILLA" title="Direkter Link zu Key features of ILLA">​</a></h3>
<p>Here are the key features of ILLA you must know:</p>
<ul>
<li>ILLA has a ready-to-use library for React components.</li>
<li>Most amazingly, the ILLA design tool has a typescript typing feature and supports predictable static typing.</li>
<li>ILLA Design provides quick and easy import, which helps in improving developers’ productivity.</li>
<li>You can access beautifully designed and powerful themes and components.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="upgraded-illa-features">Upgraded ILLA features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#upgraded-illa-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Upgraded ILLA features" title="Direkter Link zu Upgraded ILLA features">​</a></h3>
<p>Here are some upgraded features of ILLA that you must know:</p>
<ul>
<li>Quick integration with any data source</li>
<li>You can connect ILLA to any mainstream database or any other data source. This tool allows you to get data from the backend using front-end components.</li>
<li>Real-time collaboration for enhanced efficiency</li>
<li>ILLA Builder allows developers to work collaboratively on a project. They can create and share links to different developers to co-edit their tools and communicate with other team members in real time.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="responsive-ui-library-to-meet-your-needs">Responsive UI library to meet your needs<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#responsive-ui-library-to-meet-your-needs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI library to meet your needs" title="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI library to meet your needs">​</a></h3>
<p>ILLA Builder also has numerous components to meet every developer’s needs efficiently. So, developers can access the drag-and-drop builder to develop their desired internal tools quickly.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>In conclusion, Tooljet and Appsmith are both excellent low-code platforms that can help you build applications quickly and efficiently. However, they each have their own strengths and weaknesses, so it’s important to consider your needs before deciding which one is right for you. If you’re looking for a more hands-on approach with powerful management features, then Tooljet may be the better option for you. On the other hand, if you want a user-friendly platform that doesn’t require any coding experience, then Appsmith may be the better choice. Ultimately, it all comes down to what type of developer you are and what type of application you want to build.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="tooljet" term="tooljet"/>
        <category label="appsmith" term="appsmith"/>
        <category label="retool" term="retool"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tooljet vs Retool: Which open-source low-code platform is better?]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The demand for efficient and easy-to-use internal tools is on the rise, and low-code platforms have emerged as the go-to solution for businesses looking to streamline their internal processes.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Introduction" title="Direkter Link zu Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>The demand for efficient and easy-to-use internal tools is on the rise, and low-code platforms have emerged as the go-to solution for businesses looking to streamline their internal processes. Retool and Tooljet are two popular low-code platforms that have attracted attention for their ability to build internal tools with ease. In this blog, we'll compare Retool and Tooljet, exploring their key features, use cases, and performance, and introduce ILLA Cloud as a supporting platform for app development and deployment.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-the-best-software-development-tool">ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#illa-cloud-the-best-software-development-tool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud: The best software development tool">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Compared to building with a component library, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing within teams.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retool">Retool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool" title="Direkter Link zu Retool">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/retool.png" alt="retool" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Retool is a widely-used low-code platform that makes it easy to build custom internal tools, including SQL GUIs and Airtable dashboards. With its extensive integration capabilities, Retool allows users to connect to various databases and APIs, making it a popular choice for developing Redis UIs and Airtable admin panels. Retool offers both self-hosted and cloud-based solutions, making it a flexible option for businesses of all sizes. However, some users may find Retool's pricing a bit steep, which has led to a search for open-source Retool alternatives.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retools-key-features-and-use-cases">Retool's key features and use cases:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#retools-key-features-and-use-cases" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool's key features and use cases:" title="Direkter Link zu Retool's key features and use cases:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Extensive Integration Capabilities: Retool supports a wide range of databases and APIs, such as SQL, Redis, and Airtable, making it a popular choice for developing Redis UIs, SQL GUIs, and Airtable admin panels.</li>
<li>User Interface and Experience: Retool features a drag-and-drop interface, which enables users to build internal tools without extensive coding knowledge. The platform also provides a range of pre-built components, such as tables, forms, and charts, to speed up the development process.</li>
<li>Customizability: With Retool custom components, users can create bespoke solutions tailored to their specific needs. This feature allows for greater flexibility and control over the appearance and functionality of internal tools.</li>
<li>Security and Compliance: Retool offers robust security features, including role-based access control, audit logs, and SSO. In addition to its cloud-based solution, Retool's self-hosted and on-premise options provide businesses with even more control over their data and infrastructure.</li>
<li>Pricing: Retool offers a range of pricing plans, but its relatively higher costs may lead some users to search for more affordable open-source Retool alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet">Tooljet<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/tooljet-vs-appsmith-vs-retool/tooljet.png" alt="tooljet" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Tooljet is another powerful low-code platform that enables users to build and deploy internal tools and software quickly. Like Retool, Tooljet offers a wide range of integrations, making it easy to create GUIs for Redis and MySQL, as well as handle Redis queries. Tooljet's open-source nature makes it an appealing choice for businesses looking for Retool alternatives. In addition to its ease of use and customizability, Tooljet offers a secure and compliant environment for developing internal tooling, with features like SSO and Docker support.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljets-key-features-and-use-cases">Tooljet's key features and use cases:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#tooljets-key-features-and-use-cases" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet's key features and use cases:" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet's key features and use cases:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Integration Capabilities: Like Retool, Tooljet offers a wide range of integrations, allowing users to connect to various databases and APIs, such as SQL, Redis, and Airtable. This makes it easy to create GUIs for Redis and MySQL and handle Redis queries.</li>
<li>User Interface and Experience: Tooljet provides an intuitive interface with a drag-and-drop builder, making it easy for users to create and customize their internal tools. It also includes a rich library of pre-built components to facilitate rapid development.</li>
<li>Customizability: Tooljet's open-source nature allows for greater customization and flexibility than Retool. Users can modify the source code and contribute to the platform's development, ensuring that their internal tools align with their unique requirements.</li>
<li>Security and Compliance: Tooljet prioritizes security, offering features like SSO, Docker support, and role-based access control. This ensures that your internal tools remain secure and compliant while using Tooljet.</li>
<li>Pricing: Tooljet's open-source model is free to use and modify, making it an attractive and cost-effective alternative to Retool, especially for smaller businesses or those with limited budgets.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="comparing-retool-and-tooljet">Comparing Retool and Tooljet<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#comparing-retool-and-tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Comparing Retool and Tooljet" title="Direkter Link zu Comparing Retool and Tooljet">​</a></h2>
<p>When comparing Retool and Tooljet, several key factors come into play:</p>
<ul>
<li>Integration Capabilities: Both platforms offer extensive integrations, allowing users to connect to various databases and APIs, including SQL, Redis, and Airtable. While both platforms excel in this area, your choice may depend on specific integration requirements or preferences.</li>
<li>User Interface and Experience: Retool and Tooljet both provide intuitive drag-and-drop interfaces and a library of pre-built components, making it easy for users to build internal tools like Google internal tools and Airtable dashboards. Personal preferences and ease of use will play a role in determining the best option for your needs.</li>
<li>Customizability: Retool offers custom components, while Tooljet's open-source nature allows for even greater customization. Consider the level of customization required for your internal tools when choosing between the two platforms.</li>
<li>Security and Compliance: Both platforms prioritize security, with Retool providing self-hosted and on-premise options, while Tooljet offers SSO and Docker support. Evaluate your organization's specific security and compliance requirements when making a decision.</li>
<li>Pricing: Retool's pricing may be a barrier for some users, while Tooljet's open-source model offers a more budget-friendly alternative. Consider your organization's budget and financial constraints when selecting the most suitable platform.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="choosing-the-right-low-code-platform-for-your-needs">Choosing the Right Low-Code Platform for Your Needs<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#choosing-the-right-low-code-platform-for-your-needs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Choosing the Right Low-Code Platform for Your Needs" title="Direkter Link zu Choosing the Right Low-Code Platform for Your Needs">​</a></h2>
<p>To choose between Retool and Tooljet, consider the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>Integration Requirements: Both platforms offer extensive integration options, so your choice may depend on specific needs or preferences. Evaluate which platform best supports the databases and APIs essential to your internal tools.</li>
<li>Customizability: If custom components are a priority, Retool may be the better choice. However, if you prefer an open-source platform with greater flexibility, Tooljet could be more suitable.</li>
<li>Security and Compliance: Both Retool and Tooljet offer robust security features, so consider your specific compliance requirements when making a decision. Assess which platform best aligns with your organization's security policies and standards.</li>
<li>Budget: If you're searching for a cost-effective solution, Tooljet's open-source model may be more appealing than Retool's pricing structure. Take into account the long-term costs associated with each platform, including potential updates and maintenance.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-offers-the-best-of-both-worlds">ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#illa-cloud-offers-the-best-of-both-worlds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud offers the best of both worlds">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA is one of the fastest platforms for internal tool development. It saves developers precious time on web design and other aspects of their job. One of the main reasons developers are increasingly choosing ILLA is the library. The platform has conjured a rich collection of code components that you can simply drag and drop and build complex applications within minutes.</p>
<p>You can also use application programming interfaces to join ILLA with a database of your choice. The platform can excellently integrate back-end and front-end data. As a result, developers can make vast information interactions possible with basic data calls.</p>
<p>Any developer will love ILLA for two reasons-freedom and the chance to work simultaneously with other developers. Firstly, developers can write JavaScript wherever they want. This permits more flexibility in their job and increased variety in results.</p>
<p>Secondly, developers can share links in ILLA Builder with other professionals in real time. Consequently, they can edit and comment on each other’s work as they go along. In other words, developers get to work in a fun and collaborative workspace. Naturally, this yields faster and improved results.</p>
<p>Lastly, developers can always carry their work with them when using ILLA cloud. Just one click from any device will give them access to the cloud and bring them to ILLA’s user interface.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="key-features-of-illa">Key features of ILLA<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#key-features-of-illa" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Key features of ILLA" title="Direkter Link zu Key features of ILLA">​</a></h3>
<p>Here are the key features of ILLA you must know:</p>
<ul>
<li>ILLA has a ready-to-use library for React components.</li>
<li>Most amazingly, the ILLA design tool has a typescript typing feature and supports predictable static typing.</li>
<li>ILLA Design provides quick and easy import, which helps in improving developers’ productivity.</li>
<li>You can access beautifully designed and powerful themes and components.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="upgraded-illa-features">Upgraded ILLA features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#upgraded-illa-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Upgraded ILLA features" title="Direkter Link zu Upgraded ILLA features">​</a></h3>
<p>Here are some upgraded features of ILLA that you must know:</p>
<ul>
<li>Quick integration with any data source</li>
<li>You can connect ILLA to any mainstream database or any other data source. This tool allows you to get data from the backend using front-end components.</li>
<li>Real-time collaboration for enhanced efficiency</li>
<li>ILLA Builder allows developers to work collaboratively on a project. They can create and share links to different developers to co-edit their tools and communicate with other team members in real time.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="responsive-ui-library-to-meet-your-needs">Responsive UI library to meet your needs<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#responsive-ui-library-to-meet-your-needs" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI library to meet your needs" title="Direkter Link zu Responsive UI library to meet your needs">​</a></h3>
<p>ILLA Builder also has numerous components to meet every developer’s needs efficiently. So, developers can access the drag-and-drop builder to develop their desired internal tools quickly.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/tooljet-vs-retool#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>In conclusion, Tooljet and Appsmith are both excellent low-code platforms that can help you build applications quickly and efficiently. However, they each have their own strengths and weaknesses, so it’s important to consider your needs before deciding which one is right for you. If you’re looking for a more hands-on approach with powerful management features, then Tooljet may be the better option for you. On the other hand, if you want a user-friendly platform that doesn’t require any coding experience, then Appsmith may be the better choice. Ultimately, it all comes down to what type of developer you are and what type of application you want to build.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="tooljet" term="tooljet"/>
        <category label="appsmith" term="appsmith"/>
        <category label="retool" term="retool"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Open-Source Low-Code Platform for Building Internal Tools]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ILLA Cloud is an open-source low-code development platform that helps users quickly build internal tools, including data dashboards, management backends, and AI tools.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ILLA Cloud is an open-source low-code development platform that helps users quickly build internal tools, including data dashboards, management backends, and AI tools. As an open-source low-code platform, using ILLA Cloud to create internal tools is a very good choice.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-is-internal-tools">What is Internal Tools<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool#what-is-internal-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What is Internal Tools" title="Direkter Link zu What is Internal Tools">​</a></h2>
<p>Internal Tools refer to tools used within a team, including but not limited to various data dashboards, admin panels, etc. These tools can help the team better manage business operations and improve work efficiency. Tools drive the team's efficiency, and Internal Tools are an important part of these tools.</p>
<p>Every team needs to create a large number of non-standardized Internal Tools based on their own needs, making their team more efficient in managing business operations and data-driven decision-making.</p>
<p>Regardless of whether it's a large or small company, Internal Tools are very important, and each company's Internal Tools are different. Therefore, a flexible tool is needed to create Internal Tools.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-illa-cloud-can-do">What ILLA Cloud Can Do<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool#what-illa-cloud-can-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What ILLA Cloud Can Do" title="Direkter Link zu What ILLA Cloud Can Do">​</a></h2>
<p>Github: <a href="https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder</a></p>
<p>Official Website: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com</a></p>
<p>The main users of ILLA Cloud are backend engineers, which might be different from what most people think. A large number of backend engineers have used ILLA Cloud to build numerous data panels and management backends. After all, web development has always been a headache for backend engineers. The tools built with ILLA Cloud are indeed quite aesthetically pleasing and fast.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA also supports collaboration, allowing multiple people to edit a project together. Backend engineers no longer need to worry about building various internal backends. We all know the pain and tears of relying on front-end engineers.</p>
<p>The official website also has some solutions, which currently seem to focus mainly on management backends, data panels, etc.</p>
<ul>
<li>AI text-to-image panel</li>
<li>AI voice processing panel</li>
<li>Data analysis panel</li>
<li>Content management CMS</li>
<li>Custom CRM</li>
<li>Management backend</li>
</ul>
<p>They also support building workflows, and it seems they have done a lot of work in the low-code field, looking like a well-rounded product. It basically meets various common cases.</p>
<p>For instance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sending a message to Slack when a new user registers</li>
<li>Daily reporting of the number of stars on GitHub</li>
<li>Daily booking of meeting rooms</li>
</ul>
<p>Engineers use ILLA Flow to automatically execute many tasks, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reading business data from a database daily and sending it to Slack</li>
<li>Building CI/CD reporting systems</li>
<li>Sending emails when certain warnings occur</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/internal-tool/connector.png" alt="connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="user-experience">User Experience<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool#user-experience" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu User Experience" title="Direkter Link zu User Experience">​</a></h2>
<p>I briefly experienced it, and they have really put a lot of effort into the editor's smoothness and overall experience. The overall editing experience is quite good. It includes smooth drag-and-drop capabilities and also supports collaboration.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/internal-tool/team.gif" alt="collabration" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Various database integration capabilities are also supported, allowing quick data reading and writing from various data sources and databases. For backend engineers, integrating various services is indeed a nightmare. In this case, ILLA has already done the work. They also support integration with Huggingface, which seems like an official collaboration. It allows for quick use of the model capabilities on Huggingface, which is indeed interesting. You can quickly create some AI-driven tools.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/internal-tool/resource.png" alt="resource" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/internal-tool#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>If you are choosing an open-source low-code platform, ILLA Cloud is an excellent option. It can help you quickly build Internal Tools, enhancing your team's work efficiency.</p>
<p>Finally, it is hoped that every team can use Internal Tools to drive their business growth and build the most efficient team.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="nvm" term="nvm"/>
        <category label="nodejs" term="nodejs"/>
        <category label="mac" term="mac"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create AI Tools like building with blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-ai-tools</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-ai-tools"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI development has reached a point today where it's no longer a novelty, but rather widely applied in various fields.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AI development has reached a point today where it's no longer a novelty, but rather widely applied in various fields. However, for most people, AI remains a high-barrier technology, requiring a significant amount of time and effort to learn before it can be applied effectively in practical work.</p>
<p>Each of us has our own unique needs, such as building text-to-image tools or writing tools specific to our work chains. There are numerous interesting models on HuggingFace, allowing us to quickly create our own AI tools based on these models, thereby making our work more intelligent!</p>
<p>Here is a recommended tool that allows users to build AI tools like assembling blocks:</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-ai-tools#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>The official website is: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com</a></p>
<p>Github: <a href="https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder</a></p>
<p>This open-source low-code tool's slogan is: <strong>Build AI Driven Business Tools</strong>. It focuses on helping users quickly build AI-driven tools. Users can construct pages through drag-and-drop. Then, by using three major functions, they can connect to AI:</p>
<ul>
<li>ILLA AI Agent</li>
<li>Models from HuggingFace</li>
<li>RestAPI to call OpenAI's interface</li>
</ul>
<p>This allows for the quick creation of personalized AI tools.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="building-smart-applications">Building Smart Applications<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-ai-tools#building-smart-applications" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Building Smart Applications" title="Direkter Link zu Building Smart Applications">​</a></h2>
<p>Here we use OpenAI's text-to-image interface to build our own text-to-image panel, using tools built with ILLA Cloud, which offers certain advantages:</p>
<p>Example here: <a href="https://illacloud.com/image-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com/image-generator</a></p>
<ul>
<li>The generated images can be sent to any system or SaaS using the ILLA Flow feature.</li>
<li>The models used later can be called via RestAPI or through HuggingFace's models.</li>
<li>Built-in prompts can be added to ensure that the generated content is sufficiently customized.</li>
<li>The ILLA AI Agent feature can enrich the content's prompts, as not everyone is familiar with writing prompts.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/build-ai-tools/image_generate_content.webp" alt="image_generate_content" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>I used several components here, quickly creating my own web panel through drag-and-drop, and then connected the logic through JavaScript, making it available for use by my team.</p>
<p>I built two examples; another is an AI voice processing panel.</p>
<p>Example here: <a href="https://illacloud.com/ai-voice-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com/ai-voice-generator</a></p>
<p>This panel has the following functions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Meeting minutes transcription</li>
<li>Generation of meeting minutes</li>
<li>Translation and dubbing of meeting minutes</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/build-ai-tools/mix_ai_voice.webp" alt="mix_ai_voice" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>It primarily uses OpenAI's Whisper capability. There are thousands of AI capabilities, but the most important is to find what suits you. Using ILLA Cloud, you can quickly build AI applications like building blocks. Start using it now!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-ai-tools#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>From the above introduction, we can see that using ILLA Cloud, you can quickly build your own AI tools, and ILLA Cloud has a rich array of components, basically meeting a large number of everyday business needs.</p>
<p>ILLA's self-developed component library has made the above functions flexible enough. Come and use ILLA Cloud to build your own AI tools!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="ai" term="ai"/>
        <category label="tools" term="tools"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Das beste entwicklerfreundliche Tool zur Automatisierung von Nachrichtenversand an Slack]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/automatisieren-sendung-nach-slack</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/automatisieren-sendung-nach-slack"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slack, als wichtigstes Kommunikationstool für die Arbeit vieler Menschen, ist zu einem der unverzichtbaren Tools geworden, die täglich geöffnet werden müssen. Mit Unterstützung leistungsstarker Text- und Medienformate ermöglicht uns Slack, verschiedene Nachrichten zu senden. Als Entwickler haben wir eine Vielzahl von Aufgaben, die automatisiert werden müssen.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Slack, als wichtigstes Kommunikationstool für die Arbeit vieler Menschen, ist zu einem der unverzichtbaren Tools geworden, die täglich geöffnet werden müssen. Mit Unterstützung leistungsstarker Text- und Medienformate ermöglicht uns Slack, verschiedene Nachrichten zu senden. Als Entwickler haben wir eine Vielzahl von Aufgaben, die automatisiert werden müssen, wie zum Beispiel:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Code-Kompilierung und Erstellung</strong>: Die Automatisierung des Prozesses der Code-Kompilierung, insbesondere bei großen Projekten, kann die Effizienz erheblich steigern.</li>
<li><strong>Testausführung</strong>: Automatisches Ausführen von Unit-Tests, Integrationstests und Leistungstests zur Sicherstellung der Code-Qualität.</li>
<li><strong>Code-Bereitstellung</strong>: Automatisierung der Code-Bereitstellung in Produktions- oder Testumgebungen, eine gängige Praxis in Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) Prozessen.</li>
<li><strong>Datensicherung und Wiederherstellung</strong>: Regelmäßige Automatisierung von Datenbank- und Anwendungsdatensicherungen und Wiederherstellung bei Bedarf.</li>
<li><strong>Überwachung und Benachrichtigungen</strong>: Automatisierung der Überwachung von System- und Anwendungsleistung und Versenden von Benachrichtigungen bei Problemen.</li>
<li><strong>Protokollverwaltung</strong>: Automatisierung der Sammlung, Analyse und Archivierung von Protokollen.</li>
<li><strong>Umgebungskonfiguration</strong>: Verwendung von Konfigurationsmanagement-Tools zur automatischen Einrichtung und Pflege von Entwicklungs-, Test- und Produktionsumgebungen.</li>
<li><strong>Dokumentationserstellung</strong>: Automatisches Generieren von Dokumentation aus Code-Kommentaren oder Datenbankstrukturen.</li>
<li><strong>Batch-Verarbeitung von Daten oder Dateien</strong>: Automatisches Durchführen von Datenumwandlungen, Migrationen oder anderen Batch-Verarbeitungsaufgaben.</li>
<li><strong>Abhängigkeitsmanagement</strong>: Automatisches Verwalten von Projektabhängigkeiten, um die neuesten und kompatiblen Versionen von Bibliotheken und Frameworks sicherzustellen.</li>
</ul>
<p>Diese Aufgaben werden in der Regel mithilfe verschiedener Tools und Skripte automatisiert, wie beispielsweise die Verwendung von Jenkins oder GitHub Actions für CI/CD-Prozesse oder Ansible, Puppet für die Konfiguration und Verwaltung von Umgebungen. Entwickler verwenden viele Tools, um diese Aufgaben zu erledigen, aber diese Tools sind normalerweise unabhängig voneinander. Nach Abschluss ihrer Aufgaben würden meiner Meinung nach alle eine umfassende Benachrichtigung über Updates zu schätzen wissen.</p>
<p>Studien zeigen, dass die Behebung von Problemen, die über Slack zum Zeitpunkt ihrer Entstehung benachrichtigt werden, die Auflösungszeit um 50 % reduzieren kann. Daher benötigen wir ein Tool, um uns beim automatischen Versenden von Nachrichten an Slack zu unterstützen und uns zu ermöglichen, alle Nachrichten an einem Ort zu sehen, anstatt verschiedene Tools überprüfen zu müssen.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/automate-send-to-slack/connector.png" alt="Verbindung" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="wie-man-das-problem-löst">Wie man das Problem löst<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/automatisieren-sendung-nach-slack#wie-man-das-problem-l%C3%B6st" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Wie man das Problem löst" title="Direkter Link zu Wie man das Problem löst">​</a></h2>
<p>Hier wählen wir ein Tool aus, um dieses Problem zu lösen, namens ILLA Flow. Es handelt sich um ein Connector-Tool, das sich an Entwickler richtet und ihnen dabei hilft, schnell verschiedene Automatisierungsaufgaben zu erstellen, einschließlich des automatischen Versendens von Nachrichten an Slack.</p>
<p>ILLA Flow bietet verschiedene Integrationen, darunter RestAPI, GraphQL und eine Vielzahl von Datenbankverbindungen und verschiedene Fähigkeiten von SaaS-Plattformen, die es Ihnen ermöglichen, Ihre Produkte schnell mit denen zu verbinden, die von Ihren Kunden verwendet werden. ILLA Flow unterstützt auch geplante Aufgaben, Webhooks und die Übergabe von Parametern.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/automate-send-to-slack/resource.png" alt="Ressource" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Das einzigartige Merkmal von ILLA Flow ist die Möglichkeit, einen KI-Agenten in den Workflow zu integrieren. Dadurch können Sie einen KI-Agenten verwenden, der von OpenAI's Modell erstellt wurde, um Ihre Benachrichtigungen vor dem Versenden zu verarbeiten und sie intelligenter und interessanter zu gestalten. Sie können den KI-Agenten auch für komplexe Analysen verwenden, um zuvor herausfordernde Zusammenfassungen zu vereinfachen.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/automate-send-to-slack/agent.png" alt="Agent" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="erreichte-ergebnisse">Erreichte Ergebnisse<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/automatisieren-sendung-nach-slack#erreichte-ergebnisse" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Erreichte Ergebnisse" title="Direkter Link zu Erreichte Ergebnisse">​</a></h2>
<p>Wir können einen Workflow in ILLA Flow erstellen und dann Slack's Webhook im Workflow aufrufen, um den automatisierten Nachrichtenversand an Slack zu erreichen.</p>
<p>Nach Abschluss von CI/CD-Tools oder nach täglich geplanten Aufgaben können wir die Nachrichten in Slack sehen.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/automate-send-to-slack/connector.png" alt="Verbindung" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Wir können auch ILLA Flow mit GitHub verbinden, um die von ILLA Flow gesendeten Nachrichten in GitHub Issues zu sehen.</p>
<p>Wir können auch ILLA Flow mit dem Alarmüberwachungssystem verbinden, sodass wir bei einem Alarm oder einer Anomalie Nachrichten in Slack sehen können.</p>
<p>Schließlich unterstützt ein weiteres Produkt von ILLA, ILLA Builder, das Erstellen von benutzerdefinierten Panels, sodass wir direkt zu ILLA Builder springen können, um über die in Slack gesendeten Links weitere Informationen anzuzeigen, was Benachrichtigungen sehr intelligent und detailliert macht.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="fazit">Fazit<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/automatisieren-sendung-nach-slack#fazit" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Fazit" title="Direkter Link zu Fazit">​</a></h2>
<p>In der täglichen Arbeit gibt es zahlreiche Automatisierungss</p>
<p>zenarien, und ILLA Flow ist ein Tool, das sich an Entwickler richtet. Die meisten anderen Automatisierungsverbindungstools sind auf allgemeine Benutzer ausgerichtet, was die Konfiguration für Entwickler komplexer machen kann.</p>
<p>Mit ILLA Flow können Sie KI-Agenten und verschiedene SaaS-Integrationen mit einem Klick integrieren, um interne Teamprozesse stärker zu automatisieren und Benachrichtigungen intelligenter zu gestalten.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Workflow" term="Workflow"/>
        <category label="Slack" term="Slack"/>
        <category label="Automatisierung" term="Automatisierung"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I developed a product that enables freelancers to create admin panels with lightning speed]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/boost-freelancer</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/boost-freelancer"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am currently a freelancer and once took on a web development project on a freelancer platform.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I'm Owen, a full-stack engineer with previous experience at TikTok. My role there involved developing the platform, known for its engaging short video content, and ensuring a delightful user experience.</p>
<p>I am currently a freelancer and once took on a web development project on a freelancer platform. The frontend part of this project didn't take much of my time, but the extensive requirements for Admin Panels consumed a lot of it.</p>
<p>All my data was stored on Supabase, and I developed a complete set of REST APIs for backend management. I realized that most of the work involved CRUD operations on Supabase. I needed a tool to help me quickly develop these Admin Panels.</p>
<p>So, I created an open-source project to assist in the rapid development of Admin Panels. This project is named ILLA Cloud.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-is-illa-cloud">What is ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/boost-freelancer#what-is-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What is ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu What is ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA is a low-code tool designed for developers, allowing you to rapidly develop Admin Panels and Dashboards through a drag-and-drop interface. ILLA Cloud integrates with a wide range of common databases and data sources, including REST APIs and GraphQL.</p>
<p>Official Website: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com</a></p>
<p>With ILLA, you can quickly build various tools such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panels</li>
<li>Data Dashboards</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>These can be created with drag-and-drop ease, requiring only a minimal amount of JavaScript for logical connections.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/boost-freelancer/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA also features a comprehensive set of connector tools, capable of integrating AI, databases, and various SaaS platforms. This enables your clients to quickly link the products you build with the ones they use. It supports scheduled tasks, Webhooks, and also allows for parameter passing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/boost-freelancer/connector.png" alt="connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-i-created-illa-cloud">Why I created ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/boost-freelancer#why-i-created-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why I created ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Why I created ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>For freelancers, the most important thing is undoubtedly time, as time is money. I don't want to spend too much time on Admin Panels; I need a tool that helps me develop Admin Panels quickly. Additionally, for my clients, usability and aesthetic appeal are paramount. Therefore, using a low-code tool for development offers a very user-friendly experience.</p>
<p>With drag-and-drop, I can rapidly construct an Admin Panel that directly interacts with Supabase, without needing to write any code. This tool helps me quickly develop Admin Panels, allowing me to focus on developing business logic.</p>
<p>The reason I use Supabase is that it's an extremely user-friendly open-source project, which aids in swiftly setting up backend services. Moreover, its documentation is very accessible, making it easy for me to get started.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud has an integration with Supabase. With SQL, I can quickly query and modify data in Supabase, facilitating rapid development of both Dashboards and Admin Panels.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-i-recommend-illa-cloud">Why I recommend ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/boost-freelancer#why-i-recommend-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why I recommend ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Why I recommend ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>You only need to pay $20 per month for ILLA, and this fee is solely for the use of ILLA's editor, which is very freelancer-friendly. You might need to interact with numerous clients, but you don't have to pay for the users; you only pay for yourself.</p>
<p>Additionally, ILLA comes with a ready-to-use Drive service. For file storage needs during development, you can directly use the Drive service, which aids in rapid development. Moreover, if your client has a high usage volume, you can have them recharge their account themselves, or they can come back to you for more. This can be very beneficial for closing follow-up deals.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="freelancer" term="freelancer"/>
        <category label="freelance" term="freelance"/>
        <category label="upwork" term="upwork"/>
        <category label="fiverr" term="fiverr"/>
        <category label="freelancer.com" term="freelancer.com"/>
        <category label="freelancer jobs" term="freelancer jobs"/>
        <category label="freelance jobs" term="freelance jobs"/>
        <category label="freelance work" term="freelance work"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 7 Database GUIs for SQL databases]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Database GUI tools make working with SQL databases much simpler and more efficient for developers. Many great database GUIs are available, each with different features and capabilities.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Database GUI tools make working with SQL databases much simpler and more efficient for developers. Many great database GUIs are available, each with different features and capabilities. In this blog post, we'll look at seven of the best database GUIs to help you choose the right one.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="database-guis-and-why-they-are-important">Database GUIs and why they are important<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#database-guis-and-why-they-are-important" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Database GUIs and why they are important" title="Direkter Link zu Database GUIs and why they are important">​</a></h2>
<p>Database GUIs are essential tools for database developers, database administrators, and database management systems users. Database management tools enable database developers to edit and manage MySQL and PostgreSQL databases and browse the database schema on Windows, Linux, and macOS operating systems.</p>
<p>Popular databases such as Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle MySQL Database, and Oracle MySQL server also benefit from this technology through comprehensive cross-platform GUI database management tools. GUI database management tools allow users to construct complex query builders for their databases with just a mouse click instead of manually entering complex SQL statements.</p>
<p>Web-based GUIs are becoming increasingly popular as they allow those with access to a web browser to easily manage their databases from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac. Using a database GUI is a much quicker way of managing your databases. It is also far more comprehensive when compared to entering SQL statements by hand. Allowing developers easy access to any database system's functionality makes database management significantly more accessible.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA is a top-notch low-code solution that allows developers to create a feature-rich internal tool within no time. Moreover, developers using the ILLA cloud will have to spend less effort and time on web designs and other integrations.</p>
<p>The creators of ILLA have developed numerous inserts for the tool. So, the tool can quickly meet the requirements and needs of developers in any scenario. Moreover, developers can use drag and drag-and-drop builder of ILLA to improve their productivity in the best possible way. You can also connect this tool to any data source through APIs.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud is also one of the most popular Graphical User Interfaces (GUI) for managing SQL databases. It offers a user-friendly and intuitive interface, allowing developers to quickly change their database without manually entering complex SQL statements. ILLA Cloud also provides comprehensive cross-platform support, making it accessible from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac.</p>
<p>With ILLA Cloud, users can quickly construct complex query builders with a mouse click. In addition to its great features, ILLA Cloud offers enterprise level security protocols protecting the user's data. Furthermore, users can easily extend their database by creating custom web services with ILLA's REST API platform. ILLA Cloud is the perfect choice for those looking for an easy way to manage their databases.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="dbeaver">DBeaver<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#dbeaver" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu DBeaver" title="Direkter Link zu DBeaver">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/dbeaver.avif" alt="dbeaver" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>DBeaver is an excellent choice for SQL Database GUI, particularly for those looking to avoid subscription-based models. It is a free and open-source database management tool that provides cross-platform support, allowing users to access their databases from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac.</p>
<p>With DBeaver, users can quickly create complex queries and edit the database schema with a mouse click. It also features an extensive set of tools that make it easy to manage large SQL databases. These tools include an ER Diagram generator, data export/import features, and a powerful query builder that helps users construct complex queries.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retool">Retool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool" title="Direkter Link zu Retool">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/retool.avif" alt="retool" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Retool is an intuitive Graphical User Interface (GUI) for managing SQL databases that offers a wide range of features and benefits. It provides an clean interface with drag-and-drop features to construct complex queries without needing to manually enter SQL statements. Retool makes it easier for developers to interact with their databases, enabling them to make changes quickly and efficiently.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Retool's advanced security protocols help protect users' data from unauthorized access. It also offers cross-platform support, making it accessible from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet">Tooljet<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/tooljet.avif" alt="tooljet" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Tooljet is an advanced Graphical User Interface (GUI) for managing SQL databases that offer users a comprehensive suite of features and tools to manage their databases efficiently. It has an intuitive drag-and-drop interface, allowing developers to quickly change their database without manually entering complex SQL statements.</p>
<p>Tooljet also provides powerful query builders that enable users to construct complex queries in a few clicks and built-in reporting capabilities for generating reports quickly and easily. Furthermore, users can take advantage of the extensive cross-platform support provided by Tooljet and access their database from any system.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="dbvisualizer">DbVisualizer<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#dbvisualizer" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu DbVisualizer" title="Direkter Link zu DbVisualizer">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/dbvisualizer.avif" alt="DbVisualizer" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>DbVisualizer is a powerful and comprehensive GUI tool for managing SQL databases. It offers users an easy-to-use drag-and-drop interface for making changes to their database and robust query builders for constructing complex queries without manually entering SQL statements. DbVisualizer provides extensive cross-platform support, allowing users to access their database from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac.</p>
<p>It also features advanced security protocols to help protect users' data from unauthorized access. Overall, DbVisualizer is an excellent choice.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="appsmith">Appsmith<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Appsmith" title="Direkter Link zu Appsmith">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/appsmith.avif" alt="appsmith" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Appsmith is an incredibly powerful graphical user interface (GUI) that makes it easy to manage large SQL databases. It features a comprehensive set of tools that make managing such databases simpler and more intuitive than ever. The drag-and-drop interface allows developers to quickly construct complex queries without manually entering long strings of SQL statements.</p>
<p>Appsmith also offers numerous advanced security protocols, such as user authentication and secure connection encryption. Moreover, Appsmith's cross-platform support enables users to access their data from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="dronahq">Dronahq<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#dronahq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Dronahq" title="Direkter Link zu Dronahq">​</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases/dronahq.avif" alt="dronahq" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Dronahq is a powerful and feature-rich graphical user interface (GUI) for managing SQL databases. It offers users an intuitive drag-and-drop interface that makes creating complex queries simple without manually entering SQL statements.</p>
<p>Dronahq provides extensive cross-platform support, enabling users to access their database from any system, including Windows, Linux, and Mac. It also features advanced security protocols such as role-based authentication and secure connection encryption. Furthermore, Dronahq has a powerful query builder that allows users to quickly create custom reports with the built-in reporting capabilities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="find-the-one-that-best-suits-you">Find the one that best suits you<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-database-guis-for-sql-databases#find-the-one-that-best-suits-you" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Find the one that best suits you" title="Direkter Link zu Find the one that best suits you">​</a></h2>
<p>With the wide range of Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) available, it is important to try out different options to find the one that best suits you. Each GUI has unique features, so users should take the time to research and weigh the pros and cons.</p>
<p>Ultimately, choosing the right GUI is a long-term investment that can significantly improve a person’s computing experience. Why not check out ILLA Cloud today? Its excellent features, user-friendly interface, and optimized performance could be just the right solution you need!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="database" term="database"/>
        <category label="gui" term="gui"/>
        <category label="tools" term="tools"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Tools for Building Crud Applications in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CRUD applications are a type of software that allows users to create, read, update, and delete data using various interfaces such as web pages or mobile apps.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CRUD applications are a type of software that allows users to create, read, update, and delete data using various interfaces such as web pages or mobile apps. CRUD stands for Create, Read, Update, and Delete, which are the four basic operations that models should be able to do on data. CRUD applications are very common in web development, as they allow users to perform basic operations on data without writing complex code.</p>
<p>CRUD applications consist of three main components: a database, a user interface, and an API. The database is where the data is stored and retrieved. The user interface is the front end that users interact with. The API contains the code and methods that communicate with the database. Each component can use different technologies and frameworks, depending on the needs and preferences of the developer.</p>
<p>In this blog post, we will review some of the best tools for building CRUD applications, covering each component separately. We will also provide some examples and tips on how to use them effectively.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="database">Database<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#database" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Database" title="Direkter Link zu Database">​</a></h2>
<p>The database is the core of any CRUD application, as it stores the data that users can create, read, update, and delete. There are many types of databases available, but they can be broadly categorized into two groups: relational (SQL) and non-relational (NoSQL).</p>
<p>Relational databases use tables to store data; each table has a predefined schema and each row represents a record. Relational databases are good for structured and consistent data that requires complex queries and transactions. Some of the most popular relational databases are MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, and SQL Server.</p>
<p>Non-relational databases use collections to store data, where each collection can have a flexible schema and each document represents a record. Non-relational databases are good for unstructured and dynamic data that require high scalability and performance. Some of the most popular non-relational databases are MongoDB, CouchDB, Firebase, and DynamoDB.</p>
<p>Choosing the right database for your CRUD application depends on several factors, such as the type and volume of data you need to store, the level of consistency and reliability you need to ensure, and the complexity and frequency of queries you need to perform. You should also consider the compatibility and integration of your database with your user interface and API tools.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="user-interface">User Interface<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#user-interface" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu User Interface" title="Direkter Link zu User Interface">​</a></h2>
<p>The user interface is the front end of your CRUD application, where users can see and manipulate the data stored in your database. The user interface can be built using various technologies and frameworks, depending on the type and complexity of your application.</p>
<p>One of the most common ways to build a user interface for a CRUD application is by using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. HTML defines the structure and content of your web page, CSS styles the appearance and layout of your web page, and JavaScript adds interactivity and functionality to your web page. You can use plain HTML, CSS, and JavaScript or use libraries and frameworks that simplify and enhance your development process.</p>
<p>Some of the most popular libraries and frameworks for building user interfaces are React, Angular, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, jQuery, etc. These tools provide various features and benefits for creating dynamic and responsive web pages that can communicate with your API and database.</p>
<p>Another way to build a user interface for a CRUD application is by using low-code or no-code platforms. These platforms allow you to create web pages using drag-and-drop components and visual editors without writing much or any code. Some of the most popular low-code or no-code platforms are Budibase, Appsmith, Bubble.io, Webflow, etc. These tools are great for beginners or non-developers who want to create simple and fast CRUD applications without learning complex technologies.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="api">API<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#api" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu API" title="Direkter Link zu API">​</a></h2>
<p>The API is the bridge between your user interface and your database. It defines how your user interface can request data from your database or send data to your database using HTTP methods such as GET (read), POST (create), PUT (update), or DELETE (delete). The API also handles authentication, authorization, validation, error handling, etc.</p>
<p>There are many ways to build an API for your CRUD application, but one of the most common ways is using REST (Representational State Transfer). REST is an architectural style that defines how resources (data) can be accessed and manipulated using standard HTTP methods and formats such as JSON or XML. REST APIs are easy to understand and use by both humans and machines.</p>
<p>Some of the most popular tools for building REST APIs are Node.js, Express.js, Flask, Django, Ruby on Rails, Laravel, etc. These tools are frameworks that provide various features and libraries for creating and managing web servers and APIs.</p>
<p>Another way to build an API for your CRUD application is using GraphQL. GraphQL is a query language and a runtime that allows you to define and execute queries and mutations (operations) on your data using a single endpoint. GraphQL APIs are more flexible and efficient than REST APIs, as they allow you to request or send only the data you need, avoiding over-fetching or under-fetching.</p>
<p>Some of the most popular tools for building GraphQL APIs are Apollo Server, Prisma, Hasura, Graphene, etc. These tools are libraries or platforms that help you create and manage GraphQL servers and schemas.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tools-for-building-crud-applications">Tools For Building Crud Applications<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#tools-for-building-crud-applications" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tools For Building Crud Applications" title="Direkter Link zu Tools For Building Crud Applications">​</a></h2>
<p>You will find many software claiming to provide ease in building useful CRUD Applications, but you need to be careful to find the ones that help in making the most compatible CRUD Applications. Let us discuss the top 7 software that can help you. We short-listed these seven tools according to client’s preferences and feasibility. We will mention their features and drawbacks so that you can choose wisely and according to your demands.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/illa.png" alt="illa" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA  Cloud is an open-source low-code platform for building internal tools. Its main aim is to help programmers develop modules to monitor data, which is one of the most tedious jobs for a developer. Another new feature in this open-source low-code app is that you can make your own customized block of code and then later put it up for sale in the marketplace.</p>
<p>It gets connected to the mainstream database, or, alternatively, it can connect to any database through APIs. It can even add action to the chain of user events. Its backend and front-end data components are tightly integrated; hence developers can write data calls for massive information interaction.</p>
<p>It is doubly useful for developers because it offers them the freedom to implement richer functionality. They can use {{template syntax}} for richer content.</p>
<p>It allows real-time collaboration, making it easier for developers to interact at different ends of the world to work on it simultaneously. They can use ILLA Builder by sharing links, co-editing, and communicating for improved development efficiency.</p>
<p>ILLA Builder has a comprehensive UI library. It has several useful components that developers can use to drop and drag to build attractive interfaces without wasting much time</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It can easily be integrated with any database.</li>
<li>You can download ILLA CLI for any of these operating systems: Windows, Linux, and MAC.</li>
<li>It offers real-time collaboration which enables the developers to communicate for better development.</li>
<li>It provides flexible deployment. You can use ILLA Cloud, ILLA CLI, Kubernetes, and Docker.</li>
<li>You can easily integrate third-party APIs.</li>
<li>It is free to share, use, copy, and update.</li>
<li>It is constantly being polished with new updates and features.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ILLA Cloud has basically been developed for the convenience of programmers.</li>
<li>You need to be proficient in either of the four languages to fully utilize it. JavaScript, RUST, and Forlang are its major languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="appsmith">AppSmith<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu AppSmith" title="Direkter Link zu AppSmith">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/appsmith.png" alt="appsmith" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>AppSmith was the first open-source low-code tool. It introduced the developers to a whole new world of click-and-drag programming. The standard plan consists of unlimited apps and widgets that are immensely useful for building live dashboards. This standard plan is free. It has many features; a summary of these is below:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-1">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It easily gets connected to your supported database.</li>
<li>Instinctive drag-and-drop widgets prove to be very helpful and make coding even easier.</li>
<li>A complete guide, including documentation and videos, is available for guidance.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-1">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>To fully utilize this app, you need to know JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="knack">Knack<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#knack" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Knack" title="Direkter Link zu Knack">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/knack.png" alt="knack" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Knack is another no-code app that is used generally used for automating manual processes. It will be problematic if you try to plug it in with an existing database. It has certain limitations, which is why it is best used for internal processes only. It will allow you to view, manage, update, analyze, and share data. The application templates for different cases start quickly. Here are a few features of this application.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-2">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It supports a built-in database as well as user management, authentication, email, and notification automation workflows.</li>
<li>Developers can easily customize it with JavaSript and CSS.</li>
<li>A complete guide, including documentation and videos, is available for guidance.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-2">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<p>The most severe drawback is its incapability to interact with other databases.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="budibase">Budibase<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#budibase" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Budibase" title="Direkter Link zu Budibase">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/budibase.png" alt="budibase" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Budibase is another popular low-code tool extensively used for CRUD applications. You can easily integrate it with major databases. Below are a few prominent features of the tool.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-3">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-3" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It has a load of widgets and other features to beautify your page.</li>
<li>It supports an internal database but supports by connecting to an external database as well.</li>
<li>In the shape of extensive documentation, a complete guide is also available for guidance.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-3">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-3" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>JavaScript, as well as technical skills, are required.</li>
<li>No templates are available.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="bubble">Bubble<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#bubble" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Bubble" title="Direkter Link zu Bubble">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/bubble.png" alt="bubble" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>This much more complicated tool is not recommended for smaller internal apps.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-4">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-4" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Widgets and designs are available.</li>
<li>Perfectly capable of deployment.</li>
<li>The volume of traffic, users, and data is unlimited.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-4">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-4" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is complicated to learn.</li>
<li>You cannot host it on your infrastructure</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="ui-bakery">UI Bakery<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#ui-bakery" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu UI Bakery" title="Direkter Link zu UI Bakery">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/uibakery.png" alt="bakery" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>This app is a relatively new product but is still the perfect no-code tool for building internal tools and CRUD apps because of the predefined widgets and ready-made templates. It can easily connect to SQL Databases like MySQL, Google Datasheets, and Postgres.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-5">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-5" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It supports user management through Google, Twitter, and Facebook.</li>
<li>Developers can do app hosting on a unique URL</li>
<li>You can customize the widgets and templates.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-5">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-5" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not suitable for public-facing apps, customer-facing websites, and mobile apps.</li>
<li>You need technical staff to deal with this, as it requires a moderate level of knowledge to deal with JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retool">Retool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool" title="Direkter Link zu Retool">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications/retool.png" alt="retool" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Though last on the list, retool is also an excellent choice as a CRUD application. It is a drag-and-drop building blocks platform. You need to customize JavaScript in order to fetch your data from an external database.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-6">Features:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#features-6" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features:" title="Direkter Link zu Features:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It supports built-in authorization and authentication.</li>
<li>You can customize it with JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks-6">Drawbacks:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#drawbacks-6" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Its free plan is minimal and charges at a per-end user base.</li>
<li>You cannot use it for public-facing apps.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/the-best-tools-for-build-crud-applications#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>CRUD applications are a type of software that allows users to create, read, update, and delete data using various interfaces. CRUD applications consist of three main components: a database, a user interface, and an API. Each component can use different technologies and frameworks, depending on the needs and preferences of the developer.</p>
<p>In this blog post, we reviewed some of the best tools for building CRUD applications, covering each component separately. We also provided some examples and tips on how to use them effectively. We hope this post helped you learn more about CRUD applications and how to build them.</p>
<p>If you are looking for a tool that can help you build CRUD applications quickly and easily, we recommend you check out ILLA Cloud. ILLA Cloud is a cloud-based platform that lets you create CRUD applications without coding. You can connect to any database or API, design your user interface with drag-and-drop components, and deploy your application with one click. ILLA Cloud also provides features such as authentication, authorization, validation, error handling, etc. ILLA Cloud is the best tool for building CRUD applications in minutes.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="crud" term="crud"/>
        <category label="tools" term="tools"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10,000 Stars! This open-source low-code tool is wildly popular overseas.]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/popular-tool</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/popular-tool"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Open-source tools are common, but it's rare to see one with 10,000 stars.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Open-source tools are common, but it's rare to see one with 10,000 stars. I'm sharing a product that has seen a crazy growth of 10,000 stars overseas. There are many low-code tools, but few are truly useful. This tool is primarily used by developers in North America, and their Discord community is very active.</p>
<p>The community indeed has some good reviews.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/good.png" alt="good" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-illa-cloud-can-do">What ILLA Cloud Can Do<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/popular-tool#what-illa-cloud-can-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What ILLA Cloud Can Do" title="Direkter Link zu What ILLA Cloud Can Do">​</a></h2>
<p>Github: <a href="https://illacloud.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com/illacloud/illa-builder</a></p>
<p>Official Website: <a href="https://illa.cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illa.cloud</a></p>
<p>The main users of ILLA Cloud are backend engineers, which might be different from what most people think. A large number of backend engineers have used ILLA Cloud to build numerous data panels and management backends. After all, web development has always been a headache for backend engineers. The tools built with ILLA Cloud are indeed quite aesthetically pleasing and fast.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA also supports collaboration, allowing multiple people to edit a project together. Backend engineers no longer need to worry about building various internal backends. We all know the pain and tears of relying on front-end engineers.</p>
<p>The official website also has some solutions, which currently seem to focus mainly on management backends, data panels, etc.</p>
<ul>
<li>AI text-to-image panel</li>
<li>AI voice processing panel</li>
<li>Data analysis panel</li>
<li>Content management CMS</li>
<li>Custom CRM</li>
<li>Management backend</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/solution.png" alt="solution" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>They also support building workflows, and it seems they have done a lot of work in the low-code field, looking like a well-rounded product. It basically meets various common cases.</p>
<p>For instance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sending a message to Slack when a new user registers</li>
<li>Daily reporting of the number of stars on GitHub</li>
<li>Daily booking of meeting rooms</li>
</ul>
<p>Engineers use ILLA Flow to automatically execute many tasks, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reading business data from a database daily and sending it to Slack</li>
<li>Building CI/CD reporting systems</li>
<li>Sending emails when certain warnings occur</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/flow.jpeg" alt="flow" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="user-experience">User Experience<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/popular-tool#user-experience" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu User Experience" title="Direkter Link zu User Experience">​</a></h2>
<p>I briefly experienced it, and they have really put a lot of effort into the editor's smoothness and overall experience. The overall editing experience is quite good. It includes smooth drag-and-drop capabilities and also supports collaboration.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/team.gif" alt="collabration" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Various database integration capabilities are also supported, allowing quick data reading and writing from various data sources and databases. For backend engineers, integrating various services is indeed a nightmare. In this case, ILLA has already done the work. They also support integration with Huggingface, which seems like an official collaboration. It allows for quick use of the model capabilities on Huggingface, which is indeed interesting. You can quickly create some AI-driven tools.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/popular-tool/resource.png" alt="resource" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/popular-tool#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>There are many low-code tools, but few can be practically used and implemented. ILLA seems to have been maintained for two years now, and their company is currently fully committed to this one thing. Unlike some low-code tools produced for certain purposes, they are directly addressing the needs of developers. Everyone can try it out!"</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="nvm" term="nvm"/>
        <category label="nodejs" term="nodejs"/>
        <category label="mac" term="mac"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ILLA Flow: A javascript-driven, developer-friendly product for creating automate workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ILLA Flow is a workflow product that allows you to construct a complete workflow in a manner similar to mind mapping, thereby enabling connections and scheduling with various databases and APIs.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone, I'm Owen, and we are a startup company focused on low-code solutions. Our team is quite small, consisting of only 7 people.</p>
<p>Today, we launched our new product: ILLA Flow.</p>
<p>Website: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com</a> (You can find it after login, at the left of dashboard -&gt; Flow)</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-flow">ILLA Flow<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow#illa-flow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Flow" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Flow">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Flow is a workflow product that allows you to construct a complete workflow in a manner similar to mind mapping, thereby enabling connections and scheduling with various databases and APIs.</p>
<p>You can build your own workflow through a drag-and-drop interface, and then execute your workflow by scheduling triggers or Webhook triggers.</p>
<p>The smooth drag-and-drop experience allows you to quickly build workflows without worrying about any integration issues. The entire system is driven by JavaScript, ensuring flexibility while also being developer-friendly.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/launch-flow/flow.jpeg" alt="flow" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="integrate-everything">Integrate Everything<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow#integrate-everything" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Integrate Everything" title="Direkter Link zu Integrate Everything">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Flow can connect to any</p>
<ul>
<li>RestAPI</li>
<li>MySQL</li>
<li>MariaDB,</li>
<li>PostgreSQL</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/launch-flow/resource.jpeg" alt="resource" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>We will strive to expand support for more connectivity features.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-examples">Some examples<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow#some-examples" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some examples" title="Direkter Link zu Some examples">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Flow supports multiple trigger types, including scheduled triggers and Webhook triggers.</p>
<p>We use ILLA Flow to do lots of things, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Send a message to Slack when a new user registers</li>
<li>Report the number of stars on GitHub every day</li>
<li>Book a meeting room every day</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>Our engineers use ILLA Flow to automate many tasks, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Read some business data from databases and send to Slack every day</li>
<li>Build a CI/CD report system</li>
<li>Send email when some warning occurs</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/launch-flow#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Flow supports scheduled triggers and the use of Webhooks for triggering. As a low-code tool, ILLA also enables the construction of panels to drive multiple workflows, forming a complete business process. Currently, the product is entirely free and requires no costs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/launch-flow/dashboard.jpeg" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Our initial intention in creating this product was to address the lack of developer-friendly workflow products on the market. We aim to build a complete low-code matrix product to provide a better experience. Moreover, we have achieved multi-person real-time collaboration, similar to the experience of editing in Figma, ensuring that a team can edit workflows together.</p>
<p>As an early-stage product, there are still many features that are not perfect, and we hope everyone can provide valuable feedback to help us optimize it.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="workflow" term="workflow"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Best Low Code Platform in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the software industry evolves, low-code tools are increasingly gaining popularity. Implementing the right low-code tools in various business scenarios can lead to remarkable efficiency and productivity gains.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the software industry evolves, low-code tools are increasingly gaining popularity. Implementing the right low-code tools in various business scenarios can lead to remarkable efficiency and productivity gains. This article delves into the most popular low-code tool products in 2024, offering insights and reliable recommendations for making informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-low-code-tools">Why Choose Low-Code Tools<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#why-choose-low-code-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Low-Code Tools" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Low-Code Tools">​</a></h2>
<p>Low-code tools offer several compelling advantages, which include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Zero operational maintenance costs</li>
<li>Ultra-fast development speed</li>
<li>Reduced need for extensive developer teams</li>
<li>Accelerated time-to-market for new applications</li>
</ul>
<p>Typically, low-code tools are particularly well-suited for developing internal tools and Portal scenarios.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="the-spectrum-of-choices">The Spectrum of Choices<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#the-spectrum-of-choices" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu The Spectrum of Choices" title="Direkter Link zu The Spectrum of Choices">​</a></h2>
<p>We have compiled a list of currently popular low-code platforms for your consideration, with detailed introductions to follow.</p>
<ul>
<li>ILLA Cloud: Open-source</li>
<li>Budibase: Open-source</li>
<li>Tooljet: Open-source</li>
<li>SuperBlocks: Proprietary</li>
<li>Retool: Proprietary</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>GitHub link: <a href="https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder</a></p>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an innovative low-code tool that facilitates the swift creation of internal tools using simple JavaScript, eliminating the need to start new projects from scratch.</p>
<p>Key offerings include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Administration Panels</li>
<li>Data Dashboards</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>ILLA Cloud boasts a development speed up to 10 times faster than traditional component library building, and it also supports collaborative editing, enhancing teamwork efficiency.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/crm.webp" alt="crm" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="best-choice">Best Choice<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#best-choice" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Best Choice" title="Direkter Link zu Best Choice">​</a></h3>
<p>Unique advantages of ILLA Cloud over other low-code tools:</p>
<ul>
<li>Multi-user collaboration support</li>
<li>Comprehensive workflow capabilities</li>
<li>Open-source product with options for private deployment</li>
<li>Compatibility with various mainstream integrations, enabling quick connection to diverse data sources</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/team.gif" alt="team" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Furthermore, ILLA Cloud incorporates an AI Agent feature. This unique functionality allows for rapid AI-powered writing, seamlessly integrating into any product developed using low-code tools.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="budibase">Budibase<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#budibase" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Budibase" title="Direkter Link zu Budibase">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/budibase.png" alt="budibase" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>In the realm of rapid application development, Budibase emerges as a powerful low-code platform, tailored to equip developers with the tools they need to swiftly craft bespoke applications. At its core, Budibase offers a user-friendly visual development environment that simplifies the creation process. This environment is enriched with a diverse selection of pre-built components, catering to a range of application needs, from data entry forms to interactive dashboards. Beyond the pre-built offerings, Budibase extends a unique flexibility — the freedom to design custom CSS styles. This empowers developers to infuse their applications with distinct visual identities, reflecting the essence of their projects.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="opensource">Opensource<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#opensource" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Opensource" title="Direkter Link zu Opensource">​</a></h3>
<p>While Budibase doesn’t explicitly advertise itself as open source, a significant hint lies in its foundation. The platform proudly boasts its utilization of open-source technologies, fostering a sense of community-driven innovation. The absence of a clear open-source declaration doesn’t undermine its commitment to collaborative development, tapping into the power of shared knowledge and expertise. However, prospective users keen on an established open-source ecosystem might need to dig deeper into Budibase’s architecture to assess its alignment with their preferences.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#advantages" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h3>
<p>An undeniable highlight of Budibase is its prowess in integration. The platform recognizes the contemporary need for applications to communicate seamlessly with diverse external services. Enter plugins — a mechanism that empowers Budibase to integrate with a variety of third-party services. This feature propels the platform’s utility, enabling developers to harness the capabilities of external tools and services while staying within the Budibase environment. This integration-friendly approach fosters efficiency and unleashes the potential for sophisticated, multifunctional applications.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="drawbacks">Drawbacks<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#drawbacks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks" title="Direkter Link zu Drawbacks">​</a></h3>
<p>As with any powerful tool, there’s a learning curve to conquer, and Budibase is no exception. While it holds the promise of accelerated application development, some users, particularly those new to low-code development, might initially find the learning curve a bit steep. The platform’s array of features and capabilities demands a certain investment of time and effort to master fully. However, for those who persevere through this initial phase, Budibase opens the doors to a world of creative possibilities, enabling the realization of innovative application ideas with remarkable efficiency.</p>
<p>In the competitive landscape of low-code platforms, Budibase shines as a promising contender, offering a balance between user-friendly visual development, flexibility, integration capabilities, and an array of pricing plans. Whether you’re a seasoned developer seeking to expedite your workflow or a newcomer exploring the realm of application development, Budibase presents itself as a canvas for your creative ideas, enabling you to bring applications to life with agility and finesse.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet">Tooljet<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/tooljet.png" alt="tooljet" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>In the ever-evolving landscape of low-code development, Tooljet emerges as a dynamic contender, offering a platform that empowers users to craft sophisticated web applications without delving into the intricacies of coding. At its core, Tooljet introduces a versatile toolkit equipped with an array of features aimed at streamlining the application development process. Central to its offerings is a seamless drag-and-drop interface, enabling users to intuitively assemble components and design intricate layouts.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features">Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features" title="Direkter Link zu Features">​</a></h3>
<p>Database modeling, a cornerstone of modern application development, finds its place within Tooljet’s arsenal. Users can shape and mold their data structures with ease, aligning their applications with specific use cases and business needs. The platform’s emphasis on API integrations extends the boundaries of what’s achievable, allowing applications to seamlessly connect with external services and data sources. This integration prowess opens doors to dynamic, data-rich applications that respond seamlessly to real-world scenarios.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="opensource-1">Opensource<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#opensource-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Opensource" title="Direkter Link zu Opensource">​</a></h3>
<p>While Tooljet refrains from explicitly branding itself as open source, a notable feature stands out — the ability for users to export their generated code. This distinctive attribute empowers developers to take ownership of their creations fully, hosting applications on their servers. This approach combines the efficiency of low-code development with the freedom and control typically associated with traditional coding practices.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-1">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#advantages-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h3>
<p>Feedback from users highlights Tooljet’s user-friendly interface as a significant advantage. The platform’s intuitive nature accelerates the learning curve, enabling even those with limited technical expertise to bring their application visions to life. Moreover, Tooljet’s capacity to facilitate the creation of complex workflows amplifies its utility, allowing users to orchestrate intricate sequences of actions within their applications.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="disadvantages">Disadvantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#disadvantages" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages" title="Direkter Link zu Disadvantages">​</a></h3>
<p>However, no tool is without its limitations. While Tooljet empowers users with an array of features, some might find themselves yearning for advanced customization options. The platform’s focus on user-friendliness and efficiency might occasionally result in constraints for users seeking highly specialized functionalities or intricate design nuances. As with any technology, users must strike a balance between the ease of use and the extent of customization based on their specific project requirements.</p>
<p>In the realm of low-code development, Tooljet emerges as a formidable contender, offering a blend of intuitive design, data modeling prowess, API integration capabilities, and a flexible pricing model. The platform’s unique approach to exporting code and hosting applications on personal servers adds a touch of versatility, bridging the gap between low-code convenience and coding control. Whether you’re an individual exploring the application development landscape or a business seeking streamlined solutions, Tooljet invites you to navigate its feature-rich toolkit and embark on a journey of creativity and innovation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="superblocks">SuperBlocks<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#superblocks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu SuperBlocks" title="Direkter Link zu SuperBlocks">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/superblocks.png" alt="superblocks" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Superblocks is a leading low-code development platform that empowers businesses to create robust and customized internal tools with ease. With its intuitive interface and powerful features, Superblocks offers a range of benefits for organizations seeking efficient and flexible solutions for their development needs.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="key-features-of-superblocks">Key Features of Superblocks<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#key-features-of-superblocks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Key Features of Superblocks" title="Direkter Link zu Key Features of Superblocks">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Drag-and-Drop Interface: Superblocks provides a user-friendly drag-and-drop interface, allowing users to visually design and build their applications without the need for extensive coding knowledge. This feature simplifies the development process, enabling even non-technical users to create complex internal tools.</li>
<li>Extensive Component Library: Superblocks offers a vast library of pre-built components and templates that can be easily customized and integrated into applications. This saves time and effort by providing ready-made solutions for common functionalities, such as data visualization, form inputs, and workflow automation.</li>
<li>Seamless Integrations: Superblocks seamlessly integrates with various third-party services and APIs, enabling users to incorporate external tools and data sources into their applications. This ensures compatibility with existing systems and enhances the functionality and versatility of the developed tools.</li>
<li>Collaboration and Version Control: Superblocks includes collaboration features that facilitate teamwork and streamline the development process. Multiple team members can work on a project simultaneously, making it easy to collaborate, share feedback, and track changes. Additionally, version control capabilities enable developers to revert to previous versions of the application if needed.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="benefits-of-superblocks">Benefits of Superblocks<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#benefits-of-superblocks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Benefits of Superblocks" title="Direkter Link zu Benefits of Superblocks">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rapid Development: With its intuitive interface and extensive component library, Superblocks accelerates the development process. The visual approach and ready-to-use components reduce the need for manual coding, enabling faster prototyping and deployment of internal tools.</li>
<li>Customizability: Superblocks allows users to tailor their applications to specific requirements. The platform offers flexibility in designing user interfaces, workflows, and data integrations, ensuring that the developed tools align with the organization's unique needs and branding.</li>
<li>Cost-Effectiveness: By providing a low-code solution, Superblocks reduces the reliance on traditional development resources and expensive coding efforts. This translates into significant cost savings, as organizations can create and maintain internal tools without the need for extensive development teams or specialized expertise.</li>
<li>Scalability: Superblocks is designed to scale alongside growing businesses. Whether an organization needs to build a simple internal tool or a complex enterprise-grade application, Superblocks can accommodate the scalability requirements, ensuring that the developed tools can handle increased data volumes and user demand.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="retool">Retool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Retool" title="Direkter Link zu Retool">​</a></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/best-low-code-platform/retool.png" alt="retool" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Retool is a popular low-code development platform that empowers organizations to build internal tools with speed and efficiency. With its intuitive interface and powerful features, Retool enables businesses to create customized applications without the need for extensive coding knowledge.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="key-features-of-retool">Key Features of Retool<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#key-features-of-retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Key Features of Retool" title="Direkter Link zu Key Features of Retool">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Drag-and-Drop Interface: Retool offers a user-friendly drag-and-drop interface, allowing users to visually design and assemble their applications. This simplifies the development process, enabling both technical and non-technical users to build functional internal tools quickly.</li>
<li>Extensive Integration Capabilities: Retool seamlessly integrates with a wide range of data sources and APIs, including databases, REST APIs, and third-party services. This allows users to leverage existing data and systems within their applications, streamlining workflows and enhancing functionality.</li>
<li>Pre-Built Components and Templates: Retool provides a vast library of pre-built components and templates that users can leverage to accelerate development. These components cover common functionalities such as data tables, forms, charts, and authentication, saving time and effort in building these features from scratch.</li>
<li>Real-Time Collaboration: Retool offers real-time collaboration features that enable team members to work together on projects simultaneously. This promotes collaboration, facilitates knowledge sharing, and streamlines the development process by eliminating version control issues and bottlenecks.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-of-retool">Advantages of Retool:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#advantages-of-retool" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Retool:" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Retool:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Speed and Efficiency: Retool's intuitive interface and pre-built components allow for rapid development, reducing time-to-market for internal tools. The platform eliminates the need to start from scratch, enabling developers to focus on customizing and fine-tuning applications rather than building basic functionalities.</li>
<li>Customizability: Despite its low-code approach, Retool offers extensive customization options. Users can tailor the appearance, behavior, and workflows of their applications to align with specific business requirements and branding guidelines.</li>
<li>Integration Flexibility: Retool's robust integration capabilities make it suitable for organizations with diverse tech stacks. The platform can seamlessly connect with a wide range of data sources and APIs, ensuring compatibility with existing systems and allowing for seamless data flow between applications.</li>
</ul>
<p>Though last on the list, retool is also an excellent choice as a CRUD application. It is a drag-and-drop building blocks platform. You need to customize JavaScript in order to fetch your data from an external database.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/best-low-code-platform#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>These are the most promising low-code tools in 2024, each with its own characteristics. Different scenarios call for different problem-solving approaches, and we hope readers can choose the most efficient solutions for development in suitable situations. Speed up your work, go home early using low-code tools.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="low code" term="low code"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build core app dashboard at lightning speed]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-is-the-core-app-dashboard">What is the Core App Dashboard?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#what-is-the-core-app-dashboard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What is the Core App Dashboard?" title="Direkter Link zu What is the Core App Dashboard?">​</a></h2>
<p>The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.</p>
<p>Think of it as the dashboard in a car—it presents the driver with all the essential data at a glance, ensuring efficient navigation and vehicle performance. Similarly, a Core App Dashboard does the same, but for the application realm.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-should-we-use-the-core-dash-app">Why should we use the Core Dash app?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#why-should-we-use-the-core-dash-app" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why should we use the Core Dash app?" title="Direkter Link zu Why should we use the Core Dash app?">​</a></h2>
<p>The use of Core Dash apps, or more commonly known as core dashboard applications, has become increasingly prevalent in today's tech-driven world. These dashboards play a pivotal role in simplifying complex processes, providing insights, and enhancing user experience. Here's why you should consider using a Core Dash app:</p>
<p>Centralized Control: A core dashboard application offers a unified platform where users can access, monitor, and control various functionalities and features of an application. This centralization minimizes the need to jump between multiple interfaces, thus improving efficiency.</p>
<p>Real-time Data Visualization: Dashboards provide real-time data visualization, allowing users to quickly grasp the current status, trends, and performance metrics. This can aid in making informed decisions promptly.</p>
<p>Enhanced User Experience: A well-designed dashboard provides an intuitive user interface, making it easier for users to navigate and access the information they need. This contributes to a more seamless and enhanced user experience.</p>
<p>Customization: Core Dash apps can often be tailored to meet specific needs. Users can customize views, metrics, and even the layout to suit their preferences or job functions.</p>
<p>Improved Productivity: By consolidating essential data and functionalities in one place, dashboards reduce the time spent searching for information, leading to increased productivity.</p>
<p>Integrated Analytics: Many Core Dash apps come with integrated analytics tools that offer insights into user behavior, application performance, and other critical metrics. This data can be invaluable for driving growth and optimization.</p>
<p>Security: Dashboards can provide robust security features, including user access controls, encryption, and audit trails. This ensures that sensitive data is protected and only accessible to authorized users.</p>
<p>Collaboration: Some dashboards come with collaborative tools, enabling teams to work together more effectively, share insights, and communicate seamlessly within the platform.</p>
<p>Scalability: As organizations grow, their data and processes can become more complex. Core Dash apps are designed to be scalable, ensuring they remain effective and efficient even as demands increase.</p>
<p>Cost-Effective: By integrating multiple functionalities and data sources into one platform, dashboards can reduce the need for multiple standalone tools. This consolidation can lead to cost savings in both software procurement and training.</p>
<p>Alerts and Notifications: Dashboards can be set up to send alerts or notifications based on specific criteria or thresholds. This ensures that users are promptly informed about any critical events or changes.</p>
<p>Support for Decision-making: With all the relevant data and analytics at their fingertips, decision-makers can derive actionable insights, helping them make more informed and strategic decisions.</p>
<p>In summary, a Core Dash app provides a powerful and comprehensive tool for businesses and individuals alike. Whether it's for monitoring, analytics, collaboration, or decision-making, these dashboards offer a range of benefits that can significantly enhance efficiency, productivity, and overall user experience. If you're looking for a way to consolidate data, gain insights, and improve operational efficiency, a Core Dash app might be the solution you need.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="functions-of-the-core-app-dashboard">Functions of the Core App Dashboard<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#functions-of-the-core-app-dashboard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Functions of the Core App Dashboard" title="Direkter Link zu Functions of the Core App Dashboard">​</a></h2>
<p>While the specific functionalities might differ based on the nature of the application, universally, a Core App Dashboard is expected to deliver the following capabilities:</p>
<p>Comprehensive Analytics: A bird's-eye view of the application's performance metrics, user activity, and other pivotal data, enabling users to understand and optimize app usage.</p>
<p>User Administration: A crucial feature for multi-user platforms, the dashboard provides tools for the seamless management of users—enabling add-ons, edits, deletions, and role definitions.</p>
<p>Configurational Controls: Whether it's changing the interface's aesthetics or adjusting the application's backend mechanics, the dashboard allows for intuitive, centralized control over various settings.</p>
<p>Notification Hub: This consolidates all alerts, ensuring users never miss out on essential updates, messages, or tasks.</p>
<p>Task Management: Some dashboards integrate task management tools to enable users to allocate, track, and manage projects and responsibilities.</p>
<p>Integration and Extensions: Dashboards might provide interfaces for integrating third-party tools or extending the application's capabilities.</p>
<p>Utilizing the Core App Dashboard: What to Keep in Mind</p>
<p>Harnessing the potential of a Core App Dashboard necessitates understanding and addressing a few critical considerations:</p>
<p>Intuitive Design: A cluttered or convoluted dashboard can deter users. Ensuring a clean, intuitive, and user-friendly design is paramount.</p>
<p>Robust Security: Given the control and insights a dashboard offers, its security cannot be compromised. Regular updates, strong encryption, and multi-factor authentication can enhance security.</p>
<p>Scalability: As applications evolve, dashboards should scale accordingly. This includes accommodating additional data, users, and functionalities.</p>
<p>Customization: Every organization or user has unique needs. Offering customization options ensures the dashboard remains relevant and effective.</p>
<p>Regular Updates: The digital realm is dynamic. Dashboards should regularly update to incorporate new features, fix bugs, and enhance performance.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-build-a-core-dashboard-using-illa-cloud">How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#how-to-build-a-core-dashboard-using-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?" title="Direkter Link zu How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?">​</a></h2>
<p>In the ever-evolving digital realm, the ability to visualize and act upon data quickly is crucial. A well-structured core app dashboard can be your central hub for all pivotal information. Combining this with the innovative prowess of ILLA Cloud can make your dashboard not just functional but transformative. Here's how you can embark on this transformative journey:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/core-app-dashboard/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-1-getting-started-with-illa-cloud">Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-1-getting-started-with-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p>Your first stop is the official ILLA Cloud website. Register and create an account. With this step, you open the gateway to a dashboard replete with tools tailored for intuitive application development.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-2-creating-a-new-project">Step 2: Creating a New Project<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-2-creating-a-new-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 2: Creating a New Project" title="Direkter Link zu Step 2: Creating a New Project">​</a></h3>
<p>Spot the "Create New Project" button? Click on it. Now, christen your project with a name and sprinkle in a description. Given our focus, you'd want to select a core app dashboard as your project type.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-3-designing-the-user-interface">Step 3: Designing the User Interface<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-3-designing-the-user-interface" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 3: Designing the User Interface" title="Direkter Link zu Step 3: Designing the User Interface">​</a></h3>
<p>Harness the strength of ILLA Cloud's low-code environment. Crafting a user interface becomes a game of drag-and-drop. Be it buttons, charts, or widgets, position them as you deem fit and give them a makeover to resonate with your brand's identity.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-4-integrating-data-sources">Step 4: Integrating Data Sources<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-4-integrating-data-sources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 4: Integrating Data Sources" title="Direkter Link zu Step 4: Integrating Data Sources">​</a></h3>
<p>ILLA Cloud makes data integration a breeze. Using the no-code API connector, you can seamlessly fetch data from various repositories, be it intricate databases, versatile external APIs, or humble spreadsheets. Your dashboard now thrives with real-time data.ILLA Cloud supports a myriad of data sources to ensure it caters to a wide range of business needs.For example,</p>
<p>Airtable: Known for its spreadsheet-database hybrid functionalities, businesses can leverage Airtable's structured data with ILLA Cloud.</p>
<p>Google Sheets: Many organizations use Google Sheets due to its collaboration features. Directly integrate these sheets into your dashboard for an efficient workflow.</p>
<p>MySQL &amp; PostgreSQL: These popular relational database management systems hold vast amounts of structured data. ILLA Cloud’s connectors ensure this data can be visualized seamlessly.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-5-creating-data-automation-workflows">Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-5-creating-data-automation-workflows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows" title="Direkter Link zu Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows">​</a></h3>
<p>Accuracy is key. With ILLA Cloud's data automation workflows and the robust Event Handler feature, say goodbye to inconsistencies. Set the stage for meticulous data validation, apt transformation, and synchronized updates. The Event Handler acts as an event processing function, allowing you to create dynamic triggering mechanisms in the workflow. Simply put, its logic operates on the principle of 'when something happens, then something else will happen.' This ensures that your dashboard always responds in real-time and reflects the absolute truth."</p>
<p>This revision emphasizes the importance of the Event Handler within the context of ensuring data accuracy and real-time responsiveness.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-6-operations-automation">Step 6: Operations Automation<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-6-operations-automation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 6: Operations Automation" title="Direkter Link zu Step 6: Operations Automation">​</a></h3>
<p>Routine tasks can be automated. Let ILLA Cloud's operation automation features take the helm. Design workflows that are proactive, initiating actions based on set criteria. The result? A reduction in manual tasks and a boost in overall efficiency.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-7-testing-and-deployment">Step 7: Testing and Deployment<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-7-testing-and-deployment" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 7: Testing and Deployment" title="Direkter Link zu Step 7: Testing and Deployment">​</a></h3>
<p>Before you unveil your masterpiece, test it. Use the ILLA Cloud environment to ensure every cog in your dashboard machine runs smoothly. Once you're content with its performance, roll out your dashboard to the desired environment, and let your stakeholders revel in its capabilities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Building a core app dashboard might seem daunting, but with ILLA Cloud, it's akin to weaving a story—with data as your language. This guide laid down a structured path, taking you from initiation to deployment, ensuring your journey is seamless. The core app dashboard you create with ILLA Cloud won't just be a repository of data; it'll be a hub of insights, driving informed decisions and fostering growth. Dive into the world of ILLA Cloud, and make app development an experience, not just a task.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="low code" term="low code"/>
        <category label="core app dashboard" term="core app dashboard"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to build a custom low code CRM in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the evolution of low-code platforms, an increasing number of businesses are turning to these platforms to build their operational systems.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the evolution of low-code platforms, an increasing number of businesses are turning to these platforms to build their operational systems. The main advantage of low-code platforms lies in their ability to rapidly iterate. This rapid iteration is key to swiftly responding to market changes, which in turn leads to quick market share acquisition. Gaining market share rapidly is essential for fast capital acquisition, and this swift capital influx fuels further rapid iteration. This cycle positions low-code platforms as the preferred choice for businesses to develop their operational systems in the coming years.</p>
<p>Customer Relationship Management (CRM), a system essential for every business, stands as a significant application scenario for low-code platforms. This article will explore how to build a CRM system using a low-code platform.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-build-your-own-crm">Why Build Your Own CRM?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#why-build-your-own-crm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Build Your Own CRM?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Build Your Own CRM?">​</a></h2>
<p>While every business requires a CRM system, the ones currently available in the market are either too complex or overly simplistic, making it hard to meet specific business needs. As a result, many businesses opt to build their own CRM systems.</p>
<p>Using low-code tools to build a CRM system allows for rapid iteration and swift response to market changes. This cycle cements the future of low-code platforms as the go-to solution for businesses developing operational systems.</p>
<p>The flexible capabilities of low-code allow for quick, from-the-ground-up construction of fully customized CRM tools tailored to a company's unique requirements.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-of-low-code-platforms">Advantages of Low-Code Platforms<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#advantages-of-low-code-platforms" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Low-Code Platforms" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Low-Code Platforms">​</a></h2>
<p>The primary advantage of low-code platforms is their ability to facilitate rapid iteration. This rapid iteration is crucial for quick response to market changes, which leads to swift market share and capital acquisition, feeding back into more rapid iteration. This cycle ensures that low-code platforms will remain the preferred choice for businesses building operational systems in the near future.</p>
<p>Building a CRM with low-code means focusing solely on business logic without worrying about operational costs or design styles. It empowers everyone to develop customized systems for their company and team.</p>
<p>Moreover, these systems are aesthetically pleasing and easily modifiable.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="building-crm-with-illa-cloud">Building CRM with ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#building-crm-with-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Building CRM with ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Building CRM with ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Cloud is a low-code platform that helps businesses quickly build their operational systems. It offers a wide range of components, enabling the rapid construction of business systems.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/crm.webp" alt="crm" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>The system built with ILLA Cloud offers several features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Customer management</li>
<li>Progress tracking</li>
<li>Data report management</li>
</ul>
<p>As a low-code tool, ILLA Cloud allows for unlimited customization, enabling the creation of bespoke features unique to a company.</p>
<p>With drag-and-drop simplicity, ILLA Cloud enables rapid construction of custom UIs, allowing users to create a fully-functional low-code CRM in just minutes. This platform boasts an extensive array of common components, coupled with the ability to pull data from any database or data source. Therefore, choosing ILLA Cloud for building a low-code CRM is an exceptionally sound decision.</p>
<p>The platform's user-friendly interface simplifies the CRM creation process, making it accessible even to those with minimal technical expertise. The vast selection of components ensures that every necessary feature can be easily integrated into the CRM system, tailored to specific business requirements.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the seamless integration with various databases and data sources empowers businesses to consolidate and utilize their data efficiently, enhancing the CRM's effectiveness. This capability is crucial for businesses aiming to maintain a comprehensive and up-to-date customer database, which is at the core of any successful CRM system.</p>
<p>In summary, ILLA Cloud's combination of ease-of-use, comprehensive component selection, and robust data integration capabilities makes it a top-tier choice for businesses looking to implement a low-code CRM solution.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-of-illa-cloud">Advantages of ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#advantages-of-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages of ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages of ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Cloud enables quick Web UI construction through drag-and-drop, eliminating the need for complex web technology skills. This accessibility allows anyone to create their own business systems.</p>
<p>It requires no operational skills, as all products are fully hosted on the ILLA Cloud, eliminating operational costs.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud supports collaborative team updates without any additional tools.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/team.gif" alt="team" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA also integrates complete AI capabilities. If there's a need to send text messages to customers, users can directly use the latest AI Agent within the product.</p>
<p>We believe that building AI-Driven Business Tools is the future's preferred method.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/send.gif" alt="send" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Flexibility has always been a strength of low-code tools, and we offer industry-leading solutions to help users quickly create their corresponding products. We hope that low-code can assist every developer in building their own low-code CRM.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Every company should have its own low-code CRM, as customized needs and capabilities are key to flexible operations. We hope everyone can rapidly build business tools using low-code tools.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="low code crm" term="low code crm"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ich habe ein Produkt entwickelt, das Backend-Ingenieuren dabei hilft, Admin-Panels, Daten-Dashboards und Web-Benutzeroberflächen schnell zu erstellen]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trotz meiner Erfahrung als Backend-Ingenieur fand ich mich oft damit beschäftigt, zahlreiche Daten-Dashboards und Admin-Panels zu erstellen, um den vielfältigen Anforderungen meiner Kollegen gerecht zu werden. Vom Präsentieren komplexer Geschäftsdaten bis zur Visualisierung von CI/CD-Aufgaben und der Erstellung eines speziellen Admin-Panels für ein Weihnachtsereignis konnte ich all dies in nur 14 Tagen bewältigen.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hallo, ich bin Owen. Als Backend-Ingenieur bin ich nicht besonders talentiert darin, Web-Benutzeroberflächen zu erstellen, aber ich muss oft verschiedene Datenpanels und Admin-Backends entwickeln, um den vielfältigen Anforderungen meiner Kollegen gerecht zu werden.</p>
<p>Dies reicht von der Darstellung komplexer Geschäftsdaten bis zur Visualisierung von CI/CD-Aufgaben und sogar zur Erstellung spezieller Admin-Backends für Weihnachtsveranstaltungen. Ich kann diese Aufgaben alleine nicht bewältigen und muss mit einem Frontend-Ingenieur zusammenarbeiten, um kontinuierliche Iterationen durchzuführen. Dies hat meine Arbeitsweise erheblich beeinflusst.</p>
<p>Ich hoffe, verschiedene Tools für den internen Teamgebrauch sowie einfache Tools für den persönlichen Gebrauch und einige zeitkritische Tools unabhängig entwickeln zu können. Meine größten Anforderungen sind, dass diese Tools ästhetisch ansprechend, benutzerfreundlich und schnell zu erstellen sind. Daher engagiere ich mich nun voll und ganz für ein Projekt, das Backend-Ingenieuren dabei hilft, maßgeschneiderte Tools schnell zu erstellen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="was-ist-illa-cloud">Was ist ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui#was-ist-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Was ist ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Was ist ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA ist ein Low-Code-Tool, das für Entwickler entwickelt wurde und es ermöglicht, Admin-Panels und Dashboards schnell über eine Drag-and-Drop-Benutzeroberfläche zu entwickeln. ILLA Cloud integriert sich nahtlos mit einer breiten Palette von gängigen Datenbanken und Datenquellen, einschließlich REST-APIs und GraphQL.</p>
<p>Offizielle Website: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illacloud.com</a></p>
<p>Mit ILLA können Sie schnell verschiedene Tools erstellen, wie zum Beispiel:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web- und App-Admin-Panels</li>
<li>Daten-Dashboards</li>
<li>Maßgeschneiderte B2B-Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Diese können mit nur wenig JavaScript für logische Verbindungen einfach per Drag &amp; Drop erstellt werden.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/dashboard.png" alt="Dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA verfügt auch über eine umfassende Sammlung von Connector-Tools, die in der Lage sind, KI, Datenbanken und verschiedene SaaS-Plattformen zu integrieren. Dies ermöglicht es Ihren Kunden, die von Ihnen erstellten Produkte schnell mit den von ihnen verwendeten Produkten zu verknüpfen. Es unterstützt geplante Aufgaben, Webhooks und ermöglicht auch die Parameterübergabe.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/connector.png" alt="Connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="warum-ich-illa-cloud-empfehle">Warum ich ILLA Cloud empfehle<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui#warum-ich-illa-cloud-empfehle" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Warum ich ILLA Cloud empfehle" title="Direkter Link zu Warum ich ILLA Cloud empfehle">​</a></h2>
<p>Nach kontinuierlichen Iterationen durch unser Team unterstützt ILLA nun eine große Anzahl von gängigen Datenquellen und APIs. Backend-Entwickler können mit ILLA mithilfe von Drag &amp; Drop-Methoden schnell maßgeschneiderte Tools erstellen, was die Geschwindigkeit bei der Erstellung einer großen Anzahl von internen Tools in der täglichen Arbeit grundlegend verbessert.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/resource.png" alt="Ressource" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Niemand muss mehr ein Mikroservice für einen bestimmten Datenbanktyp erstellen, bei dem der Mikroservice nur dazu dient, eine SQL-Abfrage auszuführen. ILLA unterstützt direkte SQL-Datenbankabfragen, was sehr benutzerfreundlich für Backend-Entwickler ist.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/sql.png" alt="SQL" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA bietet auch eine integrierte Connector-Funktionalität, die es Tools ermöglicht, Nachrichten einfach an Slack zu senden, E-Mails zu versenden oder sogar mit anderen Systemen zu kommunizieren. Diese können mithilfe von Webhooks und geplanten Aufgaben aufgerufen werden.</p>
<p>Dies verbessert grundlegend die Entwicklungseffizienz einer großen Anzahl von Automatisierungsaufgaben am Arbeitsplatz.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/connector.png" alt="Connector" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Darüber hinaus unterstützt ILLA jetzt die Integration von KI-Modellen, was die einfache Verwendung von Huggingface-KI-Modellen ermöglicht. Dies ist besonders interessant für den Aufbau von KI-gesteuerten Tools. ILLA enthält auch eine KI-Agenten-Funktion, die bequem für Textanalyse, Sprachanalyse, Bildanalyse und mehr verwendet werden kann.</p>
<p>Mit ILLA erstellte Tools können schnell mit LLMs (Large Language Models) verbunden werden, sodass die von Ihnen erstellten Tools intelligenter werden.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/agent.png" alt="Agent" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="abschließend">Abschließend<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui#abschlie%C3%9Fend" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Abschließend" title="Direkter Link zu Abschließend">​</a></h2>
<p>Ich hoffe, dass ILLA Cloud Ihnen dabei helfen kann, verschiedene Tools schnell zu erstellen, damit Sie sich auf die Entwicklung von Geschäftslogik konzentrieren können. ILLA Cloud befindet sich derzeit in der Beta-Phase, und wir sammeln aktiv Feedback von Benutzern. Wenn Sie Fragen oder Anregungen haben, zögern Sie bitte nicht, mich zu kontaktieren.</p>
<p>Ich hoffe, dass jeder Ingenieur effizient arbeiten kann, ohne sich mit bestimmten Frontend-Aufgaben herumschlagen zu müssen.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="interne Tools" term="interne Tools"/>
        <category label="Daten-Dashboard" term="Daten-Dashboard"/>
        <category label="Admin-Panel" term="Admin-Panel"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low Code vs Traditionelle Entwicklung: Optimale Effizienz in der Auswahl]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mit der kontinuierlichen Entwicklung der Entwicklungspraktiken hat das Aufkommen von Low-Code-Tools innovative Lösungen für verschiedene Entwicklungsszenarien eingeführt. Dies hat die Notwendigkeit verringert, Projekte von Grund auf neu zu beginnen, was erhebliche Zeit für wichtigere Geschäftsbestrebungen spart. Es ist jedoch entscheidend zu erkennen, dass Low Code die Entwicklung beschleunigt, dies jedoch auf Kosten einer gewissen Flexibilität geschieht. Infolgedessen sind nicht alle Lösungen gut für die Low-Code-Entwicklung geeignet. Lassen Sie uns tiefer in die Analyse von Szenarien eintauchen, die Low-Code-Tools gegenüber denen bevorzugen, bei denen die traditionelle Codeentwicklung angemessener bleibt. Während dieser Untersuchung bleibt der Schlüsselvergleich von Low Code gegenüber traditioneller Entwicklung von größter Bedeutung und betont die kritische Wichtigkeit, den effizientesten Ansatz zu wählen.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mit der kontinuierlichen Entwicklung der Entwicklungspraktiken hat das Aufkommen von Low-Code-Tools innovative Lösungen für verschiedene Entwicklungsszenarien eingeführt. Dies hat die Notwendigkeit verringert, Projekte von Grund auf neu zu beginnen, was erhebliche Zeit für wichtigere Geschäftsbestrebungen spart. Es ist jedoch entscheidend zu erkennen, dass Low Code die Entwicklung beschleunigt, dies jedoch auf Kosten einer gewissen Flexibilität geschieht. Infolgedessen sind nicht alle Lösungen gut für die Low-Code-Entwicklung geeignet. Lassen Sie uns tiefer in die Analyse von Szenarien eintauchen, die Low-Code-Tools gegenüber denen bevorzugen, bei denen die traditionelle Codeentwicklung angemessener bleibt. Während dieser Untersuchung bleibt der Schlüsselvergleich von Low Code gegenüber traditioneller Entwicklung von größter Bedeutung und betont die kritische Wichtigkeit, den effizientesten Ansatz zu wählen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="bei-der-einführung-einer-vorübergehenden-geschäftsinitiative">Bei der Einführung einer vorübergehenden Geschäftsinitiative<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#bei-der-einf%C3%BChrung-einer-vor%C3%BCbergehenden-gesch%C3%A4ftsinitiative" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Bei der Einführung einer vorübergehenden Geschäftsinitiative" title="Direkter Link zu Bei der Einführung einer vorübergehenden Geschäftsinitiative">​</a></h2>
<p>In der dynamischen Landschaft von häufigen Feiertagen und besonderen Anlässen wird das Schaffen einzigartiger Online-Erlebnisse unerlässlich. Jedes Unternehmen kann seine eigenen Marketingtage haben, die ansprechende Aktivitäten erfordern. Das Entwerfen dieser Online-Marketingkampagnen stellt unweigerlich eine Entwicklungs-Herausforderung dar und erfordert eine erhebliche Ressourcenzuweisung. Während der Bedarf an visuell ansprechenden Designs offensichtlich ist, rechtfertigt die Gesamtkomplexität möglicherweise nicht erhebliche Entwicklungskosten, insbesondere wenn der Lebenszyklus auf 1-2 Wochen begrenzt ist. In solchen Fällen erweist sich die Wahl von Low-Code-Tools als finanziell kluge Entscheidung. Hier befürworten wir eine spezifische Low-Code-Lösung.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="behandlung-von-benutzerorientierten-komponenten-webflow">Behandlung von benutzerorientierten Komponenten: Webflow<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#behandlung-von-benutzerorientierten-komponenten-webflow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Behandlung von benutzerorientierten Komponenten: Webflow" title="Direkter Link zu Behandlung von benutzerorientierten Komponenten: Webflow">​</a></h3>
<p>Webflow, mit seiner intuitiven Drag-and-Drop-Schnittstelle und designerfreundlichen Anpassungen, erleichtert das Erstellen von visuell beeindruckenden Landing-Pages. Dieser Ansatz ermöglicht es den Nutzern, mit einer ästhetisch ansprechenden Website zu interagieren, und erfordert bemerkenswerterweise nur die Expertise eines einzelnen Designers. Darüber hinaus bietet Webflow eine Reihe von Vorlagen, die leicht angepasst werden können, und ermöglicht so den schnellen Aufbau einer exquisiten Website.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/webflow.png" alt="webflow" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="verwaltung-von-geschäftsoperationen-illa-cloud">Verwaltung von Geschäftsoperationen: ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#verwaltung-von-gesch%C3%A4ftsoperationen-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Verwaltung von Geschäftsoperationen: ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Verwaltung von Geschäftsoperationen: ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p>Unabhängig von der verwendeten Frontend-Technologie ist ein effektives Verwaltungswerkzeug unverzicht</p>
<p>bar für die Überwachung von Geschäftsabläufen.</p>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a>, als Low-Code-Tool direkt aus der Box, ermöglicht es Entwicklern, interne Werkzeuge schnell mit einfachem JavaScript zu konstruieren und eliminiert die Notwendigkeit, neue Projekte zu erstellen.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web- &amp; App-Admin-Panel</li>
<li>Daten-Dashboard</li>
<li>Angepasste B2B-Werkzeuge</li>
</ul>
<p>Verglichen mit Szenarien, die auf Komponentenbibliotheken basieren, bietet ILLA Cloud eine 10x schnellere Konstruktionsgeschwindigkeit für die oben genannten Werkzeuge. Zusätzlich unterstützt ILLA Cloud kollaboratives Bearbeiten unter mehreren Teammitgliedern und fördert effiziente Teamarbeit.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Die Synergie dieser beiden Werkzeuge beschleunigt die Erstellung von Geschäftsanforderungen in Marketing-Szenarien. Dieser synergistische Ansatz minimiert den Bedarf an umfangreichen Entwicklungsressourcen und adressiert die Nachfrage nach schneller Reaktion und Bereitstellung. Folglich treibt er die Geschäftsiterationsgeschwindigkeit auf neue Höhen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="bei-der-initiierung-eines-neuen-geschäftsunternehmens">Bei der Initiierung eines neuen Geschäftsunternehmens<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#bei-der-initiierung-eines-neuen-gesch%C3%A4ftsunternehmens" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Bei der Initiierung eines neuen Geschäftsunternehmens" title="Direkter Link zu Bei der Initiierung eines neuen Geschäftsunternehmens">​</a></h2>
<p>Der Beginn eines Projekts erfordert eine gründliche Bewertung seiner Eigenschaften. Für umfassende toC-Produkte wie soziale Plattformen, Gaming-Anwendungen oder IM-Dienste neigt die Empfehlung zu traditionellen Entwicklungsmethoden. Dies gewährleistet ein hohes Maß an Flexibilität bei der Anpassung an sich entwickelnde Anforderungen.</p>
<p>Für Unternehmungen, die sich auf Einzelhandel oder Dienstleistungen konzentrieren, erweist sich die Nutzung von Shopify für die Frontend-Präsentation als vorteilhaft. Diese Wahl garantiert eine weit verbreitete Verbreitung von Produkten und senkt gleichzeitig die Entwicklungskosten. Darüber hinaus unterstützt Shopify die Anpassung und bedient so effektiv vielfältige Geschäftsbedürfnisse.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/shopify.png" alt="shopify" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>In Fällen, in denen eine schnelle Entwicklung einer App oder Website von größter Bedeutung ist, kann direkte Codierung eine schnellere Lösung bieten. Daher hängt die Auswahl einer geeigneten Lösung stark von den einzigartigen Merkmalen des Szenarios ab.</p>
<p>Wenn die Backend-Funktionalität von Shopify den Anforderungen nicht entspricht, kann die Integration von ILLA Cloud die Lücke schließen und eine Plattform für angepasste Verwaltung bereitstellen.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="schlussfolgerung">Schlussfolgerung<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#schlussfolgerung" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Schlussfolgerung" title="Direkter Link zu Schlussfolgerung">​</a></h2>
<p>Im Entscheidungsprozess zur Auswahl von Entwicklungswerkzeugen wird ein vielschichtiger Ansatz empfohlen. Während direkte Codierung unvergleichliche Flexibilität bietet, kommt sie jedoch auf Kosten der Entwicklungsgeschwindigkeit. Die strategische Integration von Low-Code-Werkzeugen und SaaS-Lösungen kann erhebliche Produktivitätsgewinne erzielen.</p>
<p>Für Operationen, die Flexibilität erfordern und für das Kerngeschäft wesentlich sind, bleiben traditionelle Entwicklungsmethoden die bevorzugte Wahl. Die Agilität und Kontrolle, die durch traditionelle Entwicklungsmethoden geboten werden, führen zu Produkten, die speziell auf spezifische Bedürfnisse zugeschnitten sind.</p>
<p>Letztendlich gibt es keine Einheitslösung; die beste Wahl ist diejenige, die am engsten mit den einzigartigen Anforderungen des jeweiligen Szenarios übereinstimmt.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Low Code" term="Low Code"/>
        <category label="traditionelle Entwicklung" term="traditionelle Entwicklung"/>
        <category label="JavaScript" term="JavaScript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, should I choose MUI?]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every company has its own exclusive online business, and as the business continues to update and iterate, the complexity of the business will continuously increase over time.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains highly prosperous. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from various perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make more informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-a-component-library">Why Choose a Component Library?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#why-choose-a-component-library" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?">​</a></h2>
<p>In general, every company building web applications tends to select a component library. These libraries address a significant amount of repetitive work, offering readily usable components such as Select, Input, CheckBox, and more. These components, customizable through styles or pre-existing attractive styles, enable the rapid creation of beautiful websites without the need to build extensive foundational features from scratch.</p>
<p>To summarize, component libraries are typically used in two scenarios:</p>
<ul>
<li>External tools: Directly targeted at company users, usually adhering to the company's style, more aesthetically pleasing, and responsive.</li>
<li>Internal tools: Aimed at internal use by company employees, focusing on aesthetic design while prioritizing rapid functionality implementation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next, we will analyze two component libraries based on the following points:</p>
<ol>
<li>Design</li>
<li>Richness of Features</li>
<li>How to Choose in Different Scenarios</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios">Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios" title="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to building with a component library, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing within teams.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/mui-2024/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-of-mui">Features of MUI<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#features-of-mui" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI" title="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI">​</a></h2>
<p>Some detailed data about MUI:</p>
<ul>
<li>⭐ Github Stars: 90k</li>
<li>⏬ NPM Downloads: 3,263,852 downloads per week</li>
<li>💪🏼 First Release Date: Nov 6, 2014</li>
</ul>
<p>MUI, as a longstanding project maintained since 2014, boasts almost a decade of stability. Its high star count and weekly download numbers ensure that the community remains consistently active.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/mui-2024/mui.png" alt="mui" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="design">Design<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Design" title="Direkter Link zu Design">​</a></h3>
<p>In terms of design, MUI strictly adheres to Google's renowned Material Design. MUI's customization capabilities are extensive, catering to a wide range of internal and external scenarios. Many well-known open-source projects use MUI for front-end development. For most functionalities, MUI provides comprehensive support.</p>
<p>In addition to common features like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colors</li>
<li>Border radii</li>
<li>Dark mode / Light mode</li>
</ul>
<p>MUI supports complete configurations of fonts, font sizes, colors, and margins, making it a powerful tool as a project with ten years of development.</p>
<p>Regarding CSS support, MUI has its custom system, utilizing emotionjs for style adjustments in the overall layout. This may come with a learning curve and may not be as developer-friendly for direct development, requiring documentation consultation for certain style modifications.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="richness-of-features">Richness of Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#richness-of-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features" title="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features">​</a></h3>
<p>MUI's component types are highly complex, divided into several dimensions:</p>
<p>These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>MUI Core: Basic functional components of MUI, including a multitude of foundational components and a style system.</li>
<li>MUI X: High-performance and complex components of MUI, including high-performance tables, charts, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are developing a highly complex system, you can use MUI's full suite solution. However, MUI X is a paid component library, and a subscription fee may be required.</p>
<p>MUI is a heavyweight repository with extensive code and a long maintenance history. Its high customizability makes it suitable for large projects. In the MUI repository, you can find a wealth of features.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-choose">How to Choose<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#how-to-choose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to Choose" title="Direkter Link zu How to Choose">​</a></h2>
<p>✅ Advantages</p>
<p>If you want to develop large projects, have high customization requirements, and wish to use high-performance data components and chart components, especially in scenarios with high business complexity and are willing to subscribe to MUI X, it is recommended to use MUI for development. Its flexible configuration and plethora of components can fully meet your requirements.</p>
<p>❌ Disadvantages</p>
<p>If you need a lightweight framework and prefer to use a CSS-only solution for layout adjustments, it is not recommended here. MUI has a comprehensive proprietary design system, comes with a certain learning curve, and Material Design's aesthetics may not suit everyone. In such cases, exploring other open-source repositories might be more suitable.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="UI Library" term="UI Library"/>
        <category label="Shadcn UI" term="Shadcn UI"/>
        <category label="React" term="React"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elegant Use of nvm for Node.js Management on Mac in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024</id>
        <link href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js, as the foundation of frontend capabilities, is no longer just a "JS Server Runtime."]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Node.js, as the foundation of frontend capabilities, is no longer just a "JS Server Runtime." Numerous tool libraries, local package management, mock environments, and more are built on Node.js, making it truly the infrastructure of the frontend world.</p>
<p>The flourishing ecosystem has made it essential for everyone to install Node.js when building frontend projects. However, with the long history of products, versioning becomes a common issue—some projects require new versions, while others need older ones. Managing multiple versions of Node.js has been a persistent challenge for developers.</p>
<p>Currently, the open-source tool nvm addresses this issue. With simple command-line usage, developers can quickly switch between different versions of Node.js, allowing them to focus on development rather than wasting time on environment configuration.</p>
<p>The predominant machines for frontend development are still Macbooks. Therefore, this article will explain how to elegantly install and use nvm on Mac to efficiently manage Node.js versions.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="recommending-an-open-source-project-for-backend-development">Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#recommending-an-open-source-project-for-backend-development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development" title="Direkter Link zu Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that enables the rapid construction of internal tools using simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to scenarios built with component libraries, ILLA Cloud allows for 10x faster construction of the mentioned tools. Additionally, ILLA Cloud supports collaboration among multiple users, facilitating teamwork for rapid customization of backend capabilities.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="introduction-to-nvm">Introduction to nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#introduction-to-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Introduction to nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Introduction to nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>⏬ GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm</a></p>
<p>⭐ GitHub Stars: 72.4k</p>
<p>💪🏼 First Release Date: Dec 22, 2014</p>
<p>nvm is an open-source project that has been maintained for nearly 10 years. Positive reviews have kept this project robust and, through continuous maintenance, it has become a perfect solution for "Node.js version management."</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="installing-nvm">Installing nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#installing-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Installing nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Installing nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>Since we are using a Mac for development, I strongly recommend using <a href="https://brew.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Homebrew</a> for package management and then using <a href="https://brew.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Homebrew</a> to install nvm.</p>
<p>To install Homebrew, it is recommended to use the installation script. It requires minimal configuration and allows immediate use. Moreover, Homebrew makes it easy to uninstall repositories cleanly if needed.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; /bin/bash -c "$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)"</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>Running this command will install the latest version of Homebrew, automatically handling the installation of Xcode Command Tools in the MacOS environment.</p>
<p>Of course, all of this is automated. Below is an installation process example.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/homebrew-install.png" alt="homebrew_install" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>After a short wait, we can proceed with the installation of nvm using the installed Homebrew.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; brew install nvm</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>After confirming agreement, nvm will be completely installed. If you decide you don't want it anymore, you can use the following command to uninstall:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain"># delete nvm if you don't need it.</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; brew uninstall nvm</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="using-nvm">Using nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#using-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Using nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Using nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>Once nvm is installed, here are some commonly used commands to help you get started. These commands should fulfill your daily needs.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm list</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The "list" command displays various mainstream Node.js versions. You can install versions according to your needs, and it will also show the currently used Node.js version on your machine. It will display some codenames.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-list.png" alt="nvm_list" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>For example, "lts/gallim" is the version name for Node.js v16. To install using this codename, nvm will automatically install the latest version of v16. It's quite convenient. You can also use this command to check the currently used version.</p>
<p>Another command allows you to check the current Node.js version:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; node --version</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>After entering this command, you can verify whether the Node.js version has been successfully switched.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm install stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The second command installs a specific Node.js version; "stable" refers to a specific version number. You can also use the codename for a particular version. For example, to install "Node.js 18," you would use "nvm install 18." Here, I'm installing the "stable" version. nvm will automatically determine the latest Stable version and install it for me. After successful installation, it will automatically switch to the installed version.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/stable-install.png" alt="stable-install" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Where there's an installation command, there's also an uninstallation command. Use:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm uninstall stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>To delete the corresponding version.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-uninstall.png" alt="nvm-uninstall" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Once you've learned how to install and uninstall, the next important step is version switching.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm use stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The "use" command allows you to quickly switch between Node.js versions currently in use. You can also use the "stable" codename. This way, you can quickly switch between versions for different projects.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-use.png" alt="nvm-use" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>This article has explained the entire process for a beginner, from installing to using nvm. You can quickly try it out and better manage your Node.js versions.</p>
<p>Node.js version management is a long-discussed issue, and nvm is an excellent open-source project that effectively addresses this problem. Of course, no project is perfect. If you have other recommendations, feel free to leave a comment and let more people know about outstanding projects—that's the mission of open-source enthusiasts!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Chen</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/smallSohoSolo</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="nvm" term="nvm"/>
        <category label="nodejs" term="nodejs"/>
        <category label="mac" term="mac"/>
        <category label="javascript" term="javascript"/>
    </entry>
</feed>