<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>ILLA Cloud Blog</title>
        <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog</link>
        <description>ILLA Cloud Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>de</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2024 ILLA.</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build core app dashboard at lightning speed]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="what-is-the-core-app-dashboard">What is the Core App Dashboard?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#what-is-the-core-app-dashboard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu What is the Core App Dashboard?" title="Direkter Link zu What is the Core App Dashboard?">​</a></h2>
<p>The Core App Dashboard is the nerve center of any sophisticated application. At its essence, it is a centralized interface providing comprehensive insights and controls tailored to the specifics of an application, facilitating better decision-making and management.</p>
<p>Think of it as the dashboard in a car—it presents the driver with all the essential data at a glance, ensuring efficient navigation and vehicle performance. Similarly, a Core App Dashboard does the same, but for the application realm.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-should-we-use-the-core-dash-app">Why should we use the Core Dash app?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#why-should-we-use-the-core-dash-app" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why should we use the Core Dash app?" title="Direkter Link zu Why should we use the Core Dash app?">​</a></h2>
<p>The use of Core Dash apps, or more commonly known as core dashboard applications, has become increasingly prevalent in today's tech-driven world. These dashboards play a pivotal role in simplifying complex processes, providing insights, and enhancing user experience. Here's why you should consider using a Core Dash app:</p>
<p>Centralized Control: A core dashboard application offers a unified platform where users can access, monitor, and control various functionalities and features of an application. This centralization minimizes the need to jump between multiple interfaces, thus improving efficiency.</p>
<p>Real-time Data Visualization: Dashboards provide real-time data visualization, allowing users to quickly grasp the current status, trends, and performance metrics. This can aid in making informed decisions promptly.</p>
<p>Enhanced User Experience: A well-designed dashboard provides an intuitive user interface, making it easier for users to navigate and access the information they need. This contributes to a more seamless and enhanced user experience.</p>
<p>Customization: Core Dash apps can often be tailored to meet specific needs. Users can customize views, metrics, and even the layout to suit their preferences or job functions.</p>
<p>Improved Productivity: By consolidating essential data and functionalities in one place, dashboards reduce the time spent searching for information, leading to increased productivity.</p>
<p>Integrated Analytics: Many Core Dash apps come with integrated analytics tools that offer insights into user behavior, application performance, and other critical metrics. This data can be invaluable for driving growth and optimization.</p>
<p>Security: Dashboards can provide robust security features, including user access controls, encryption, and audit trails. This ensures that sensitive data is protected and only accessible to authorized users.</p>
<p>Collaboration: Some dashboards come with collaborative tools, enabling teams to work together more effectively, share insights, and communicate seamlessly within the platform.</p>
<p>Scalability: As organizations grow, their data and processes can become more complex. Core Dash apps are designed to be scalable, ensuring they remain effective and efficient even as demands increase.</p>
<p>Cost-Effective: By integrating multiple functionalities and data sources into one platform, dashboards can reduce the need for multiple standalone tools. This consolidation can lead to cost savings in both software procurement and training.</p>
<p>Alerts and Notifications: Dashboards can be set up to send alerts or notifications based on specific criteria or thresholds. This ensures that users are promptly informed about any critical events or changes.</p>
<p>Support for Decision-making: With all the relevant data and analytics at their fingertips, decision-makers can derive actionable insights, helping them make more informed and strategic decisions.</p>
<p>In summary, a Core Dash app provides a powerful and comprehensive tool for businesses and individuals alike. Whether it's for monitoring, analytics, collaboration, or decision-making, these dashboards offer a range of benefits that can significantly enhance efficiency, productivity, and overall user experience. If you're looking for a way to consolidate data, gain insights, and improve operational efficiency, a Core Dash app might be the solution you need.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="functions-of-the-core-app-dashboard">Functions of the Core App Dashboard<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#functions-of-the-core-app-dashboard" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Functions of the Core App Dashboard" title="Direkter Link zu Functions of the Core App Dashboard">​</a></h2>
<p>While the specific functionalities might differ based on the nature of the application, universally, a Core App Dashboard is expected to deliver the following capabilities:</p>
<p>Comprehensive Analytics: A bird's-eye view of the application's performance metrics, user activity, and other pivotal data, enabling users to understand and optimize app usage.</p>
<p>User Administration: A crucial feature for multi-user platforms, the dashboard provides tools for the seamless management of users—enabling add-ons, edits, deletions, and role definitions.</p>
<p>Configurational Controls: Whether it's changing the interface's aesthetics or adjusting the application's backend mechanics, the dashboard allows for intuitive, centralized control over various settings.</p>
<p>Notification Hub: This consolidates all alerts, ensuring users never miss out on essential updates, messages, or tasks.</p>
<p>Task Management: Some dashboards integrate task management tools to enable users to allocate, track, and manage projects and responsibilities.</p>
<p>Integration and Extensions: Dashboards might provide interfaces for integrating third-party tools or extending the application's capabilities.</p>
<p>Utilizing the Core App Dashboard: What to Keep in Mind</p>
<p>Harnessing the potential of a Core App Dashboard necessitates understanding and addressing a few critical considerations:</p>
<p>Intuitive Design: A cluttered or convoluted dashboard can deter users. Ensuring a clean, intuitive, and user-friendly design is paramount.</p>
<p>Robust Security: Given the control and insights a dashboard offers, its security cannot be compromised. Regular updates, strong encryption, and multi-factor authentication can enhance security.</p>
<p>Scalability: As applications evolve, dashboards should scale accordingly. This includes accommodating additional data, users, and functionalities.</p>
<p>Customization: Every organization or user has unique needs. Offering customization options ensures the dashboard remains relevant and effective.</p>
<p>Regular Updates: The digital realm is dynamic. Dashboards should regularly update to incorporate new features, fix bugs, and enhance performance.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-build-a-core-dashboard-using-illa-cloud">How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#how-to-build-a-core-dashboard-using-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?" title="Direkter Link zu How to build a core dashboard using ILLA Cloud?">​</a></h2>
<p>In the ever-evolving digital realm, the ability to visualize and act upon data quickly is crucial. A well-structured core app dashboard can be your central hub for all pivotal information. Combining this with the innovative prowess of ILLA Cloud can make your dashboard not just functional but transformative. Here's how you can embark on this transformative journey:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/core-app-dashboard/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-1-getting-started-with-illa-cloud">Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-1-getting-started-with-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Step 1: Getting Started with ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p>Your first stop is the official ILLA Cloud website. Register and create an account. With this step, you open the gateway to a dashboard replete with tools tailored for intuitive application development.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-2-creating-a-new-project">Step 2: Creating a New Project<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-2-creating-a-new-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 2: Creating a New Project" title="Direkter Link zu Step 2: Creating a New Project">​</a></h3>
<p>Spot the "Create New Project" button? Click on it. Now, christen your project with a name and sprinkle in a description. Given our focus, you'd want to select a core app dashboard as your project type.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-3-designing-the-user-interface">Step 3: Designing the User Interface<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-3-designing-the-user-interface" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 3: Designing the User Interface" title="Direkter Link zu Step 3: Designing the User Interface">​</a></h3>
<p>Harness the strength of ILLA Cloud's low-code environment. Crafting a user interface becomes a game of drag-and-drop. Be it buttons, charts, or widgets, position them as you deem fit and give them a makeover to resonate with your brand's identity.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-4-integrating-data-sources">Step 4: Integrating Data Sources<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-4-integrating-data-sources" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 4: Integrating Data Sources" title="Direkter Link zu Step 4: Integrating Data Sources">​</a></h3>
<p>ILLA Cloud makes data integration a breeze. Using the no-code API connector, you can seamlessly fetch data from various repositories, be it intricate databases, versatile external APIs, or humble spreadsheets. Your dashboard now thrives with real-time data.ILLA Cloud supports a myriad of data sources to ensure it caters to a wide range of business needs.For example,</p>
<p>Airtable: Known for its spreadsheet-database hybrid functionalities, businesses can leverage Airtable's structured data with ILLA Cloud.</p>
<p>Google Sheets: Many organizations use Google Sheets due to its collaboration features. Directly integrate these sheets into your dashboard for an efficient workflow.</p>
<p>MySQL &amp; PostgreSQL: These popular relational database management systems hold vast amounts of structured data. ILLA Cloud’s connectors ensure this data can be visualized seamlessly.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-5-creating-data-automation-workflows">Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-5-creating-data-automation-workflows" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows" title="Direkter Link zu Step 5: Creating Data Automation Workflows">​</a></h3>
<p>Accuracy is key. With ILLA Cloud's data automation workflows and the robust Event Handler feature, say goodbye to inconsistencies. Set the stage for meticulous data validation, apt transformation, and synchronized updates. The Event Handler acts as an event processing function, allowing you to create dynamic triggering mechanisms in the workflow. Simply put, its logic operates on the principle of 'when something happens, then something else will happen.' This ensures that your dashboard always responds in real-time and reflects the absolute truth."</p>
<p>This revision emphasizes the importance of the Event Handler within the context of ensuring data accuracy and real-time responsiveness.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-6-operations-automation">Step 6: Operations Automation<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-6-operations-automation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 6: Operations Automation" title="Direkter Link zu Step 6: Operations Automation">​</a></h3>
<p>Routine tasks can be automated. Let ILLA Cloud's operation automation features take the helm. Design workflows that are proactive, initiating actions based on set criteria. The result? A reduction in manual tasks and a boost in overall efficiency.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="step-7-testing-and-deployment">Step 7: Testing and Deployment<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#step-7-testing-and-deployment" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Step 7: Testing and Deployment" title="Direkter Link zu Step 7: Testing and Deployment">​</a></h3>
<p>Before you unveil your masterpiece, test it. Use the ILLA Cloud environment to ensure every cog in your dashboard machine runs smoothly. Once you're content with its performance, roll out your dashboard to the desired environment, and let your stakeholders revel in its capabilities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/core-app-dashboard-2#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Building a core app dashboard might seem daunting, but with ILLA Cloud, it's akin to weaving a story—with data as your language. This guide laid down a structured path, taking you from initiation to deployment, ensuring your journey is seamless. The core app dashboard you create with ILLA Cloud won't just be a repository of data; it'll be a hub of insights, driving informed decisions and fostering growth. Dive into the world of ILLA Cloud, and make app development an experience, not just a task.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>low code</category>
            <category>core app dashboard</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to build a custom low code CRM in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[With the evolution of low-code platforms, an increasing number of businesses are turning to these platforms to build their operational systems. The main advantage of low-code platforms lies in their ability to rapidly iterate. This rapid iteration is key to swiftly responding to market changes, which in turn leads to quick market share acquisition. Gaining market share rapidly is essential for fast capital acquisition, and this swift capital influx fuels further rapid iteration. This cycle positions low-code platforms as the preferred choice for businesses to develop their operational systems in the coming years.Customer Relationship Management (CRM), a system essential for every business, stands as a significant application scenario for low-code platforms. This article will explore how to build a CRM system using a low-code platform.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the evolution of low-code platforms, an increasing number of businesses are turning to these platforms to build their operational systems. The main advantage of low-code platforms lies in their ability to rapidly iterate. This rapid iteration is key to swiftly responding to market changes, which in turn leads to quick market share acquisition. Gaining market share rapidly is essential for fast capital acquisition, and this swift capital influx fuels further rapid iteration. This cycle positions low-code platforms as the preferred choice for businesses to develop their operational systems in the coming years.</p>
<p>Customer Relationship Management (CRM), a system essential for every business, stands as a significant application scenario for low-code platforms. This article will explore how to build a CRM system using a low-code platform.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-build-your-own-crm">Why Build Your Own CRM?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#why-build-your-own-crm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Build Your Own CRM?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Build Your Own CRM?">​</a></h2>
<p>While every business requires a CRM system, the ones currently available in the market are either too complex or overly simplistic, making it hard to meet specific business needs. As a result, many businesses opt to build their own CRM systems.</p>
<p>Using low-code tools to build a CRM system allows for rapid iteration and swift response to market changes. This cycle cements the future of low-code platforms as the go-to solution for businesses developing operational systems.</p>
<p>The flexible capabilities of low-code allow for quick, from-the-ground-up construction of fully customized CRM tools tailored to a company's unique requirements.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-of-low-code-platforms">Advantages of Low-Code Platforms<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#advantages-of-low-code-platforms" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Low-Code Platforms" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages of Low-Code Platforms">​</a></h2>
<p>The primary advantage of low-code platforms is their ability to facilitate rapid iteration. This rapid iteration is crucial for quick response to market changes, which leads to swift market share and capital acquisition, feeding back into more rapid iteration. This cycle ensures that low-code platforms will remain the preferred choice for businesses building operational systems in the near future.</p>
<p>Building a CRM with low-code means focusing solely on business logic without worrying about operational costs or design styles. It empowers everyone to develop customized systems for their company and team.</p>
<p>Moreover, these systems are aesthetically pleasing and easily modifiable.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="building-crm-with-illa-cloud">Building CRM with ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#building-crm-with-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Building CRM with ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Building CRM with ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Cloud is a low-code platform that helps businesses quickly build their operational systems. It offers a wide range of components, enabling the rapid construction of business systems.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/crm.webp" alt="crm" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>The system built with ILLA Cloud offers several features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Customer management</li>
<li>Progress tracking</li>
<li>Data report management</li>
</ul>
<p>As a low-code tool, ILLA Cloud allows for unlimited customization, enabling the creation of bespoke features unique to a company.</p>
<p>With drag-and-drop simplicity, ILLA Cloud enables rapid construction of custom UIs, allowing users to create a fully-functional low-code CRM in just minutes. This platform boasts an extensive array of common components, coupled with the ability to pull data from any database or data source. Therefore, choosing ILLA Cloud for building a low-code CRM is an exceptionally sound decision.</p>
<p>The platform's user-friendly interface simplifies the CRM creation process, making it accessible even to those with minimal technical expertise. The vast selection of components ensures that every necessary feature can be easily integrated into the CRM system, tailored to specific business requirements.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the seamless integration with various databases and data sources empowers businesses to consolidate and utilize their data efficiently, enhancing the CRM's effectiveness. This capability is crucial for businesses aiming to maintain a comprehensive and up-to-date customer database, which is at the core of any successful CRM system.</p>
<p>In summary, ILLA Cloud's combination of ease-of-use, comprehensive component selection, and robust data integration capabilities makes it a top-tier choice for businesses looking to implement a low-code CRM solution.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages-of-illa-cloud">Advantages of ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#advantages-of-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages of ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages of ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Cloud enables quick Web UI construction through drag-and-drop, eliminating the need for complex web technology skills. This accessibility allows anyone to create their own business systems.</p>
<p>It requires no operational skills, as all products are fully hosted on the ILLA Cloud, eliminating operational costs.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud supports collaborative team updates without any additional tools.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/team.gif" alt="team" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA also integrates complete AI capabilities. If there's a need to send text messages to customers, users can directly use the latest AI Agent within the product.</p>
<p>We believe that building AI-Driven Business Tools is the future's preferred method.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/low-code-crm/send.gif" alt="send" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Flexibility has always been a strength of low-code tools, and we offer industry-leading solutions to help users quickly create their corresponding products. We hope that low-code can assist every developer in building their own low-code CRM.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/low-code-crm#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Every company should have its own low-code CRM, as customized needs and capabilities are key to flexible operations. We hope everyone can rapidly build business tools using low-code tools.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>low code crm</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I created a tool that helps non-front-end engineers quickly build beautiful Web UIs.]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/backend-create-web-ui</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Despite my background as a Backend Engineer, I frequently found myself immersed in creating numerous data dashboards and admin panels to cater to my colleagues' diverse needs. From showcasing multifaceted business data to visualizing CI/CD tasks and crafting a special Admin Panel for a Christmas event, I managed to accomplish all these in just 14 days.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone, I'm Owen, a full-stack engineer with previous experience at TikTok. My role there involved developing the platform, known for its engaging short video content, and ensuring a delightful user experience.</p>
<p>Despite my background as a Backend Engineer, I frequently found myself immersed in creating numerous data dashboards and admin panels to cater to my colleagues' diverse needs. From showcasing multifaceted business data to visualizing CI/CD tasks and crafting a special Admin Panel for a Christmas event, I managed to accomplish all these in just 14 days.</p>
<p>This barrage of disparate UI-related tasks presented significant challenges in my daily workflow. Ultimately, this led to my resignation. But, this experience inspired me to devote myself entirely to a new venture: assisting server engineers of various programming backgrounds to efficiently build the tools I mentioned earlier.</p>
<p>Check out the project:</p>
<ul>
<li>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Builder</a></li>
<li>ILLA Cloud: <a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud Website</a></li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/backend-create-web-ui/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>ILLA is an innovative open-source, low-code tool that I've both developed and used. It empowers you to effortlessly create websites using a user-friendly drag-and-drop interface. Within minutes, you can assemble a stunning dashboard or admin panel. It's a myth that server engineers can't craft UIs – with ILLA, you no longer have to depend on others to quickly develop visually appealing UIs.</p>
<p>Moreover, ILLA seamlessly integrates with RestAPI, MySQL, PostgreSQL, and other leading databases, allowing for straightforward CRUD operations without the need to develop a microservice for simple data manipulation.</p>
<p>Thanks to ILLA, I can now rapidly provide my colleagues with the desired data dashboards. Whether it's swiftly assembling a dashboard for a unique event or devising an engaging task assignment system for interns, it's all simplified.</p>
<p>I encourage you to try it out. Join me in becoming a more content and efficient engineer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>internal tools</category>
            <category>data dashboard</category>
            <category>admin panel</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Low Code vs Traditional Development: Optimal Efficiency in Choice]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[With the continuous evolution of development practices, the advent of low-code tools has introduced innovative solutions to various development scenarios. This has alleviated the need to initiate projects from scratch, saving considerable time for more pivotal business endeavors. However, it's crucial to recognize that while low code accelerates development, it does so at the expense of some flexibility. As a result, not all solutions are well-suited for low-code development. Let's delve deeper into the analysis of scenarios that favor low-code tools versus those where traditional code development remains more appropriate. Throughout this exploration, the key comparison of low code versus traditional development remains paramount, emphasizing the critical importance of choosing the most efficient approach.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the continuous evolution of development practices, the advent of low-code tools has introduced innovative solutions to various development scenarios. This has alleviated the need to initiate projects from scratch, saving considerable time for more pivotal business endeavors. However, it's crucial to recognize that while low code accelerates development, it does so at the expense of some flexibility. As a result, not all solutions are well-suited for low-code development. Let's delve deeper into the analysis of scenarios that favor low-code tools versus those where traditional code development remains more appropriate. Throughout this exploration, the key comparison of low code versus traditional development remains paramount, emphasizing the critical importance of choosing the most efficient approach.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="when-launching-a-transient-business-initiative">When Launching a Transient Business Initiative<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#when-launching-a-transient-business-initiative" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu When Launching a Transient Business Initiative" title="Direkter Link zu When Launching a Transient Business Initiative">​</a></h2>
<p>In the dynamic landscape of frequent holidays and special occasions, creating distinct online experiences becomes imperative. Each company may have its unique marketing days, requiring engaging activities. Crafting these online marketing campaigns inevitably poses a development challenge, necessitating substantial resource allocation. While the need for visually captivating designs is evident, the overall complexity may not justify significant development costs, especially when the lifecycle is limited to 1-2 weeks. In such cases, opting for low-code tools emerges as a financially prudent decision. Here, we advocate for a specific low-code solution.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="addressing-user-facing-components-webflow">Addressing User-Facing Components: Webflow<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#addressing-user-facing-components-webflow" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Addressing User-Facing Components: Webflow" title="Direkter Link zu Addressing User-Facing Components: Webflow">​</a></h3>
<p>Webflow, with its intuitive drag-and-drop interface and designer-friendly adjustments, facilitates the creation of visually stunning landing pages. This approach allows users to interact with an aesthetically pleasing website, and remarkably, only requires the expertise of a single designer. Furthermore, Webflow offers an array of templates that can be easily customized, enabling the swift construction of an exquisite website.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/webflow.png" alt="webflow" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="managing-business-operations-illa-cloud">Managing Business Operations: ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#managing-business-operations-illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Managing Business Operations: ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu Managing Business Operations: ILLA Cloud">​</a></h3>
<p>Regardless of the frontend technology used, an effective management tool is indispensable for overseeing business operations.</p>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a>, as an out-of-the-box low-code tool, empowers developers to rapidly construct internal tools using straightforward JavaScript, eliminating the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to scenarios relying on component libraries, ILLA Cloud boasts a 10x faster construction speed for the aforementioned tools. Additionally, ILLA Cloud supports collaborative editing among multiple team members, fostering efficient teamwork.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>The synergy of these two tools expedites the creation of business requirements in marketing scenarios. This synergistic approach minimizes the need for extensive development resources while addressing the demand for quick response and deployment. Consequently, it propels the business iteration speed to new heights.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="when-initiating-a-novel-business-venture">When Initiating a Novel Business Venture<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#when-initiating-a-novel-business-venture" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu When Initiating a Novel Business Venture" title="Direkter Link zu When Initiating a Novel Business Venture">​</a></h2>
<p>The commencement of a project necessitates a thorough evaluation of its characteristics. For comprehensive toC products such as social platforms, gaming applications, or IM services, the recommendation leans towards traditional development methodologies. This ensures a high degree of flexibility in adapting to evolving requirements.</p>
<p>For ventures centered around retail or services, the utilization of Shopify for frontend presentation proves advantageous. This choice guarantees widespread distribution of products while curbing development costs. Furthermore, Shopify supports customization, catering to diverse business needs effectively.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional/shopify.png" alt="shopify" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>In instances where a swift development of an app or website is paramount, direct coding may offer a faster solution. Therefore, the selection of an appropriate solution heavily relies on the unique attributes of the scenario.</p>
<p>If the backend functionality of Shopify falls short of requirements, the integration of ILLA Cloud can bridge the gap, providing a platform for customized management.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/lowcode-vs-traditional#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>In the decision-making process for selecting development tools, a multifaceted approach is recommended. While direct coding provides unparalleled flexibility, it does come at the cost of development speed. The strategic integration of low-code tools and SaaS solutions can yield substantial gains in productivity.</p>
<p>For operations demanding flexibility and essential to the core business, traditional development methods remain the preferred choice. The agility and control afforded by traditional development methods result in products that are highly tailored to specific needs.</p>
<p>Ultimately, there is no one-size-fits-all solution; the best choice is the one that aligns most closely with the unique requirements of the scenario at hand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>low code</category>
            <category>traditional development</category>
            <category>javascript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, should I choose MUI?]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Every company has its own exclusive online business, and as the business continues to update and iterate, the complexity of the business will continuously increase over time.After the business complexity reaches a high level, internal teams need to view various data to make decisions for future strategies. Therefore, we need a flexible tool to create personalized data dashboards to meet the diverse customization needs of internal team members, especially the boss, and help the team iterate quickly.Using efficient tools to leave work early every day.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains highly prosperous. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from various perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make more informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-a-component-library">Why Choose a Component Library?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#why-choose-a-component-library" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?">​</a></h2>
<p>In general, every company building web applications tends to select a component library. These libraries address a significant amount of repetitive work, offering readily usable components such as Select, Input, CheckBox, and more. These components, customizable through styles or pre-existing attractive styles, enable the rapid creation of beautiful websites without the need to build extensive foundational features from scratch.</p>
<p>To summarize, component libraries are typically used in two scenarios:</p>
<ul>
<li>External tools: Directly targeted at company users, usually adhering to the company's style, more aesthetically pleasing, and responsive.</li>
<li>Internal tools: Aimed at internal use by company employees, focusing on aesthetic design while prioritizing rapid functionality implementation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next, we will analyze two component libraries based on the following points:</p>
<ol>
<li>Design</li>
<li>Richness of Features</li>
<li>How to Choose in Different Scenarios</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios">Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios" title="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to building with a component library, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing within teams.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/mui-2024/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-of-mui">Features of MUI<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#features-of-mui" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI" title="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI">​</a></h2>
<p>Some detailed data about MUI:</p>
<ul>
<li>⭐ Github Stars: 90k</li>
<li>⏬ NPM Downloads: 3,263,852 downloads per week</li>
<li>💪🏼 First Release Date: Nov 6, 2014</li>
</ul>
<p>MUI, as a longstanding project maintained since 2014, boasts almost a decade of stability. Its high star count and weekly download numbers ensure that the community remains consistently active.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/mui-2024/mui.png" alt="mui" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="design">Design<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Design" title="Direkter Link zu Design">​</a></h3>
<p>In terms of design, MUI strictly adheres to Google's renowned Material Design. MUI's customization capabilities are extensive, catering to a wide range of internal and external scenarios. Many well-known open-source projects use MUI for front-end development. For most functionalities, MUI provides comprehensive support.</p>
<p>In addition to common features like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colors</li>
<li>Border radii</li>
<li>Dark mode / Light mode</li>
</ul>
<p>MUI supports complete configurations of fonts, font sizes, colors, and margins, making it a powerful tool as a project with ten years of development.</p>
<p>Regarding CSS support, MUI has its custom system, utilizing emotionjs for style adjustments in the overall layout. This may come with a learning curve and may not be as developer-friendly for direct development, requiring documentation consultation for certain style modifications.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="richness-of-features">Richness of Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#richness-of-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features" title="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features">​</a></h3>
<p>MUI's component types are highly complex, divided into several dimensions:</p>
<p>These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>MUI Core: Basic functional components of MUI, including a multitude of foundational components and a style system.</li>
<li>MUI X: High-performance and complex components of MUI, including high-performance tables, charts, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are developing a highly complex system, you can use MUI's full suite solution. However, MUI X is a paid component library, and a subscription fee may be required.</p>
<p>MUI is a heavyweight repository with extensive code and a long maintenance history. Its high customizability makes it suitable for large projects. In the MUI repository, you can find a wealth of features.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-choose">How to Choose<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/mui-2024#how-to-choose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to Choose" title="Direkter Link zu How to Choose">​</a></h2>
<p>✅ Advantages</p>
<p>If you want to develop large projects, have high customization requirements, and wish to use high-performance data components and chart components, especially in scenarios with high business complexity and are willing to subscribe to MUI X, it is recommended to use MUI for development. Its flexible configuration and plethora of components can fully meet your requirements.</p>
<p>❌ Disadvantages</p>
<p>If you need a lightweight framework and prefer to use a CSS-only solution for layout adjustments, it is not recommended here. MUI has a comprehensive proprietary design system, comes with a certain learning curve, and Material Design's aesthetics may not suit everyone. In such cases, exploring other open-source repositories might be more suitable.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>UI Library</category>
            <category>Shadcn UI</category>
            <category>React</category>
            <category>javascript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elegant Use of nvm for Node.js Management on Mac in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Node.js, as the foundation of frontend capabilities, is no longer just a "JS Server Runtime." Numerous tool libraries, local package management, mock environments, and more are built on Node.js, making it truly the infrastructure of the frontend world.The flourishing ecosystem has made it essential for everyone to install Node.js when building frontend projects. However, with the long history of products, versioning becomes a common issue—some projects require new versions, while others need older ones. Managing multiple versions of Node.js has been a persistent challenge for developers.Currently, the open-source tool nvm addresses this issue. With simple command-line usage, developers can quickly switch between different versions of Node.js, allowing them to focus on development rather than wasting time on environment configuration.The predominant machines for frontend development are still Macbooks. Therefore, this article will explain how to elegantly install and use nvm on Mac to efficiently manage Node.js versions.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Node.js, as the foundation of frontend capabilities, is no longer just a "JS Server Runtime." Numerous tool libraries, local package management, mock environments, and more are built on Node.js, making it truly the infrastructure of the frontend world.</p>
<p>The flourishing ecosystem has made it essential for everyone to install Node.js when building frontend projects. However, with the long history of products, versioning becomes a common issue—some projects require new versions, while others need older ones. Managing multiple versions of Node.js has been a persistent challenge for developers.</p>
<p>Currently, the open-source tool nvm addresses this issue. With simple command-line usage, developers can quickly switch between different versions of Node.js, allowing them to focus on development rather than wasting time on environment configuration.</p>
<p>The predominant machines for frontend development are still Macbooks. Therefore, this article will explain how to elegantly install and use nvm on Mac to efficiently manage Node.js versions.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="recommending-an-open-source-project-for-backend-development">Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#recommending-an-open-source-project-for-backend-development" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development" title="Direkter Link zu Recommending an Open Source Project for Backend Development">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that enables the rapid construction of internal tools using simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to scenarios built with component libraries, ILLA Cloud allows for 10x faster construction of the mentioned tools. Additionally, ILLA Cloud supports collaboration among multiple users, facilitating teamwork for rapid customization of backend capabilities.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="introduction-to-nvm">Introduction to nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#introduction-to-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Introduction to nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Introduction to nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>⏬ GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm</a></p>
<p>⭐ GitHub Stars: 72.4k</p>
<p>💪🏼 First Release Date: Dec 22, 2014</p>
<p>nvm is an open-source project that has been maintained for nearly 10 years. Positive reviews have kept this project robust and, through continuous maintenance, it has become a perfect solution for "Node.js version management."</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="installing-nvm">Installing nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#installing-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Installing nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Installing nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>Since we are using a Mac for development, I strongly recommend using <a href="https://brew.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Homebrew</a> for package management and then using <a href="https://brew.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Homebrew</a> to install nvm.</p>
<p>To install Homebrew, it is recommended to use the installation script. It requires minimal configuration and allows immediate use. Moreover, Homebrew makes it easy to uninstall repositories cleanly if needed.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; /bin/bash -c "$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)"</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>Running this command will install the latest version of Homebrew, automatically handling the installation of Xcode Command Tools in the MacOS environment.</p>
<p>Of course, all of this is automated. Below is an installation process example.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/homebrew-install.png" alt="homebrew_install" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>After a short wait, we can proceed with the installation of nvm using the installed Homebrew.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; brew install nvm</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>After confirming agreement, nvm will be completely installed. If you decide you don't want it anymore, you can use the following command to uninstall:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain"># delete nvm if you don't need it.</span><br></span><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; brew uninstall nvm</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="using-nvm">Using nvm<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#using-nvm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Using nvm" title="Direkter Link zu Using nvm">​</a></h2>
<p>Once nvm is installed, here are some commonly used commands to help you get started. These commands should fulfill your daily needs.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm list</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The "list" command displays various mainstream Node.js versions. You can install versions according to your needs, and it will also show the currently used Node.js version on your machine. It will display some codenames.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-list.png" alt="nvm_list" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>For example, "lts/gallim" is the version name for Node.js v16. To install using this codename, nvm will automatically install the latest version of v16. It's quite convenient. You can also use this command to check the currently used version.</p>
<p>Another command allows you to check the current Node.js version:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; node --version</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>After entering this command, you can verify whether the Node.js version has been successfully switched.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm install stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The second command installs a specific Node.js version; "stable" refers to a specific version number. You can also use the codename for a particular version. For example, to install "Node.js 18," you would use "nvm install 18." Here, I'm installing the "stable" version. nvm will automatically determine the latest Stable version and install it for me. After successful installation, it will automatically switch to the installed version.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/stable-install.png" alt="stable-install" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Where there's an installation command, there's also an uninstallation command. Use:</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm uninstall stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>To delete the corresponding version.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-uninstall.png" alt="nvm-uninstall" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Once you've learned how to install and uninstall, the next important step is version switching.</p>
<div class="language-shell codeBlockContainer_USIv theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_PMfr"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-shell codeBlock_IHkF thin-scrollbar" style="color:#F8F8F2;background-color:#282A36"><code class="codeBlockLines_THA1"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token plain">&gt; nvm use stable</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup_uxJT"><button type="button" aria-label="Code in die Zwischenablage kopieren" title="Kopieren" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_LZ6a" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_H1v1"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_J5e4"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div>
<p>The "use" command allows you to quickly switch between Node.js versions currently in use. You can also use the "stable" codename. This way, you can quickly switch between versions for different projects.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/nvm-use/nvm-use.png" alt="nvm-use" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/nvm-use-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>This article has explained the entire process for a beginner, from installing to using nvm. You can quickly try it out and better manage your Node.js versions.</p>
<p>Node.js version management is a long-discussed issue, and nvm is an excellent open-source project that effectively addresses this problem. Of course, no project is perfect. If you have other recommendations, feel free to leave a comment and let more people know about outstanding projects—that's the mission of open-source enthusiasts!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nvm</category>
            <category>nodejs</category>
            <category>mac</category>
            <category>javascript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, should I choose Shadcn UI?]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains vibrant. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from various perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make more informed choices.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains vibrant. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from various perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make more informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-a-component-library">Why Choose a Component Library?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#why-choose-a-component-library" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?">​</a></h2>
<p>In general, companies choose a component library when building web applications to streamline repetitive tasks. Component libraries offer a range of out-of-the-box components like Select, Input, CheckBox, etc. These components, with customizable styles or built-in attractive styles, enable rapid development of aesthetically pleasing websites without starting from scratch.</p>
<p>In summary, we typically use component libraries in two scenarios:</p>
<ul>
<li>External tools: Directly facing company users, usually aligned with the company's style, more aesthetically pleasing, and responsive.</li>
<li>Internal tools: Aimed at internal use by company employees, emphasizing design aesthetics and rapid functionality implementation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next, we will analyze the Shadcn UI component library based on the following points:</p>
<ol>
<li>Design</li>
<li>Richness of Features</li>
<li>How to Choose in Different Scenarios</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios">Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#other-choices-for-internal-tool-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios" title="Direkter Link zu Other Choices for Internal Tool Scenarios">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is an out-of-the-box low-code tool that allows quick construction of internal tools with simple JS, without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to building with a component library, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing within teams.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/shadcn-ui-2024/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-of-shadcn-ui">Features of Shadcn UI<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#features-of-shadcn-ui" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features of Shadcn UI" title="Direkter Link zu Features of Shadcn UI">​</a></h2>
<p>Some detailed data about Shadcn:</p>
<ul>
<li>⭐ Github Stars: 37k</li>
<li>⏬ NPM Downloads: 23,962 downloads per week</li>
<li>💪🏼 First Release Date: Mar 8, 2023</li>
</ul>
<p>Shadcn UI is a relatively new project that gained 37k stars in less than a year, indicating its rapid recognition in the open-source community.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/shadcn-ui-2024/shadcn-ui.png" alt="shadcn-ui" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="design">Design<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Design" title="Direkter Link zu Design">​</a></h3>
<p>In terms of design, Shadcn UI leans towards a business style with a clean UI, suitable for internal tools and serious application scenarios. Shadcn UI supports custom themes, but it seems to offer customization only for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colors</li>
<li>Border radii</li>
<li>Dark mode / Light mode</li>
<li>Predefined "Default" and "New York" styles</li>
</ul>
<p>In terms of fine-grained control, such as font and font size, it appears to lack flexibility. However, for internal tool scenarios, this level of control may be sufficient, but for external tools, it might be somewhat limiting.</p>
<p>In terms of CSS, Shadcn UI supports both traditional CSS and CSS-in-JS, using <a href="https://stitches.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stitches</a> for the CSS-in-JS solution. Traditional CSS is supported by default, but additional configuration might be needed for less and sass, and it's not out-of-the-box.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="richness-of-features">Richness of Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#richness-of-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features" title="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features">​</a></h3>
<p>The library's feature richness completely satisfies daily development needs, with most capabilities supported and comprehensive callbacks. Shadcn UI supports crucial capabilities, including but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>SSR</li>
<li>Accessibility</li>
<li>Animation</li>
</ul>
<p>However, for more advanced requirements like extremely rich charts and high-performance tables, it seems not to be supported. With the continuous development of the project, it is expected that the project will evolve over time.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-choose">How to Choose<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-ui-2024#how-to-choose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to Choose" title="Direkter Link zu How to Choose">​</a></h2>
<p>✅ Advantages</p>
<p>If you are a curious open-source enthusiast, not requiring highly customized UI, and without complex data processing needs, Shadcn UI is recommended for development. It is lightweight, with simpler configuration, ready to use out-of-the-box, allowing direct development without worrying about details.</p>
<p>❌ Disadvantages</p>
<p>If you have a high need for UI and component customization and plan to use Shadcn UI for large projects, it is not recommended. Shadcn UI's customization capabilities are not as robust, and it does not provide out-of-the-box charts and high-performance data components. In such cases, you may need to look for other open-source projects to supplement these features.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>shadcn-ui</category>
            <category>react</category>
            <category>javascript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadcn vs MUI: A Comparative Analysis of Strengths and Weaknesses]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains thriving. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from several perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make informed choices.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2024 has arrived, and the ecosystem of React component libraries remains thriving. This article will dissect two currently popular component libraries from several perspectives, providing an objective analysis to help users make informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-a-component-library">Why Choose a Component Library?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#why-choose-a-component-library" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose a Component Library?">​</a></h2>
<p>In general, companies choose a component library when building web applications to streamline repetitive work. Component libraries offer ready-to-use components such as Select, Input, CheckBox, etc., allowing users to create beautiful websites quickly without the need to build extensive foundational features from scratch.</p>
<p>To summarize, component libraries are typically used in two scenarios:</p>
<ul>
<li>External Tools: Directly facing company users, often with a company's distinct style, emphasizing aesthetics and responsiveness.</li>
<li>Internal Tools: For internal use by company employees, focusing on aesthetic design and rapid functionality implementation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Next, we will analyze two component libraries based on the following criteria:</p>
<ol>
<li>Design</li>
<li>Richness of Features</li>
<li>How to Choose for Different Scenarios</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="other-options-for-internal-tool-scenarios">Other Options for Internal Tool Scenarios<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#other-options-for-internal-tool-scenarios" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Other Options for Internal Tool Scenarios" title="Direkter Link zu Other Options for Internal Tool Scenarios">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is a ready-to-use low-code tool that allows for the quick construction of internal tools using simple JavaScript without the need to create new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to building scenarios with component libraries, ILLA Cloud enables 10x faster tool construction and supports collaboration among team members for simultaneous editing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/shadcn-ui-vs-mui/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-of-shadcn-ui">Features of Shadcn UI<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#features-of-shadcn-ui" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features of Shadcn UI" title="Direkter Link zu Features of Shadcn UI">​</a></h2>
<p>Some detailed data about Shadcn:</p>
<ul>
<li>⭐ Github Stars: 37k</li>
<li>⏬ NPM Downloads: 23,962 downloads per week</li>
<li>💪🏼 First Release Date: Mar 8, 2023</li>
</ul>
<p>Shadcn UI is a relatively new project that gained impressive recognition, achieving 37k stars in less than a year. It seems that outstanding open-source projects can easily gain widespread approval.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/shadcn-ui-vs-mui/shadcn-ui.png" alt="shadcn-ui" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="design">Design<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Design" title="Direkter Link zu Design">​</a></h3>
<p>Shadcn UI leans towards a business style in its design, featuring a clean UI suitable for internal tools and serious application scenarios. Shadcn UI also supports custom themes, although it seems limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Colors</li>
<li>Rounded corners</li>
<li>Dark mode / Light mode</li>
<li>Predefined "Default Style" and "New York Style"</li>
</ul>
<p>In terms of design details such as font and font size, the control appears limited, satisfying basic design needs. However, for external tool scenarios, it may have some limitations.</p>
<p>Shadcn UI supports both CSS and CSS-in-JS solutions. The CSS-in-JS solution uses <a href="https://stitches.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stitches</a>, and while CSS defaults to traditional CSS, additional configuration may be needed for less and sass, and it is not out-of-the-box.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="richness-of-features">Richness of Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#richness-of-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features" title="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features">​</a></h3>
<p>The library's richness of features is sufficient for daily development needs, supporting and providing complete callbacks for most capabilities. Shadcn UI supports essential capabilities, including but not limited to SSR, accessibility, and animation. For more advanced requirements like extremely rich charts and high-performance tables, it seems not fully supported, but ongoing project development is likely to address these needs.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="features-of-mui">Features of MUI<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#features-of-mui" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI" title="Direkter Link zu Features of MUI">​</a></h2>
<p>Some detailed data about MUI:</p>
<ul>
<li>⭐ Github Stars: 90k</li>
<li>⏬ NPM Downloads: 3,263,852 downloads per week</li>
<li>💪🏼 First Release Date: Nov 6, 2014</li>
</ul>
<p>As an established project, MUI has been maintained since 2014, boasting almost 10 years of stability. The high number of stars and weekly downloads ensures a continuously active community.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/shadcn-ui-vs-mui/mui.png" alt="mui" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="design-1">Design<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#design-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Design" title="Direkter Link zu Design">​</a></h3>
<p>In terms of design, MUI strictly adheres to Google's well-known Material Design. MUI offers extensive customization capabilities to meet most internal and external scenarios, with many well-known open-source projects using MUI for frontend development. For most functionalities, MUI provides comprehensive support.</p>
<p>In addition to common features like colors, rounded corners, and dark/light modes, MUI supports complete customization of fonts, font sizes, colors, padding, and margins. As a project with ten years of development, MUI's functionality is powerful.</p>
<p>In terms of CSS support, MUI has its custom system, using emotionjs for style adjustment in the overall layout. This may involve a learning curve and may not be as developer-friendly, requiring documentation consultation for some style modifications.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="richness-of-features-1">Richness of Features<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#richness-of-features-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features" title="Direkter Link zu Richness of Features">​</a></h3>
<p>MUI categorizes its components into several dimensions:</p>
<ul>
<li>MUI Core: Basic functional components and a style system.</li>
<li>MUI X: High-performance and complex components, including high-performance tables, charts, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>For developing a complex system, you can use MUI's comprehensive solution. However, MUI X is a paid component library, requiring a subscription fee.</p>
<p>MUI is a heavyweight repository with extensive code and a long maintenance history, offering high customizability, making it suitable for large projects. The repository contains numerous features.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-choose">How to Choose<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/shadcn-vs-mui#how-to-choose" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to Choose" title="Direkter Link zu How to Choose">​</a></h2>
<p>If you are a curious open-source enthusiast who does not need highly customized UI for product development, and there are no complex data processing requirements, Shadcn UI is recommended. It is more lightweight, simpler to configure, but less powerful. However, it is sufficient for internal tool scenarios.</p>
<p>If you need a component library for developing large and complex projects, require intricate charts, high-performance data components, and are willing to invest in a fee without looking for additional solutions, you can choose MUI. Its powerful capabilities make it an excellent choice for developing medium to large projects.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>UI Library</category>
            <category>Shadcn UI</category>
            <category>React</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Open-Source Low-Code Platforms in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[2024 has arrived, and the development of low-code tools remains vibrant. Many companies are utilizing low-code tools to enhance development efficiency. This article will analyze popular low-code tools from various perspectives, aiding readers in making informed choices.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2024 has arrived, and the development of low-code tools remains vibrant. Many companies are utilizing low-code tools to enhance development efficiency. This article will analyze popular low-code tools from various perspectives, aiding readers in making informed choices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-low-code-tools">Why Choose Low-Code Tools?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#why-choose-low-code-tools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Low-Code Tools?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Low-Code Tools?">​</a></h2>
<p>The emergence of low-code tools primarily addresses the issue of low development efficiency. These tools assist developers in rapidly constructing complete projects without starting from scratch, significantly boosting development efficiency. Development using low-code tools requires no coding; instead, developers can drag and drop components to build pages. This allows developers to focus more on implementing business logic without concerning themselves with page construction. Moreover, there is no need for any maintenance work; deploying the code to a server is sufficient, allowing developers to concentrate on business logic implementation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="why-choose-open-source">Why Choose Open Source?<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#why-choose-open-source" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Open Source?" title="Direkter Link zu Why Choose Open Source?">​</a></h2>
<p>As a development tool, open-source low-code tools offer several advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>Editable for customization</li>
<li>Deployable independently</li>
<li>Community collaboration for faster issue resolution</li>
<li>Abundant community template resources</li>
</ul>
<p>Choosing an open-source low-code tool can make our work twice as efficient. Open-source low-code tools are not just tools but ecosystems. We believe open source can make software more powerful, flexible, and reliable.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://illacloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ILLA Cloud</a> is a ready-to-use low-code tool enabling the swift construction of internal tools using simple JavaScript, without the need for new projects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Web &amp; App Admin Panel</li>
<li>Data Dashboard</li>
<li>Customized B2B Tools</li>
</ul>
<p>Compared to scenarios built with component libraries, ILLA Cloud allows for 10x faster tool construction and supports collaborative editing among team members.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/top5-low-code-2024/dashboard.png" alt="dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>Examples include:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://illacloud.com/solutions-crm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CRM</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.illacloud.com/solutions-dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Dashboard</a></li>
<li><a href="https://illacloud.com/solutions-image-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Text to Image Generator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://illacloud.com/solutions-ai-voice-generator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AI Voice Generator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://illacloud.com/solutions-cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CMS</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.illacloud.com/solutions-admin-panel" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Admin Panel</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="appsmith">Appsmith<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#appsmith" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Appsmith" title="Direkter Link zu Appsmith">​</a></h2>
<p>Appsmith is an open-source low-code tool with the motto "Build the tools you can’t buy off the shelf." It is a developer-friendly tool driven by JS and supports quick UI panel construction through drag-and-drop.</p>
<p>Just a few steps are needed to build a complete project:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bring in data from any data source</li>
<li>Drag and drop widgets to build UI</li>
<li>Customize and control with code</li>
</ul>
<p>Appsmith's development team hails from India, making it a promising project.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="tooljet">Tooljet<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#tooljet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Tooljet" title="Direkter Link zu Tooljet">​</a></h2>
<p>The Tooljet team, also from India, focuses on being a rapid internal tool development platform. Tooljet has the following features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lightning Fast Development</li>
<li>Budget Friendly</li>
<li>Boost Productivity</li>
</ul>
<p>Tooljet's product has significant potential and is worth keeping an eye on. With continuous accumulation over time, their product strength is sure to grow.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="budibase">Budibase<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#budibase" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Budibase" title="Direkter Link zu Budibase">​</a></h2>
<p>Budibase's team is from Europe, aiming to "Save 100s of hours building apps that make workflow." Budibase's features include:</p>
<ul>
<li>One platform. Many solutions.</li>
<li>Apps made easier. Workflows made faster.</li>
<li>Scale with confidence</li>
</ul>
<p>With continuous accumulation over time, Budibase's product strength is bound to increase.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-5-best-open-source-low-code-platforms-in-2024#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>These are the most promising open-source low-code tools in 2024, each with its own characteristics. Different scenarios call for different problem-solving approaches, and we hope readers can choose the most efficient solutions for development in suitable situations. Speed up your work, go home early using low-code tools.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>low-code</category>
            <category>open-source</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quickly create a personalized data dashboard for your boss]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Every company has its own exclusive online business, and as the business continues to update and iterate, the complexity of the business will continuously increase over time.After the business complexity reaches a high level, internal teams need to view various data to make decisions for future strategies. Therefore, we need a flexible tool to create personalized data dashboards to meet the diverse customization needs of internal team members, especially the boss, and help the team iterate quickly.Using efficient tools to leave work early every day.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every company has its own exclusive online business, and as the business continues to update and iterate, the complexity of the business will continuously increase over time.</p>
<p>After the business complexity reaches a high level, internal teams need to view various data to make decisions for future strategies. Therefore, we need a flexible tool to create personalized data dashboards to meet the diverse customization needs of internal team members, especially the boss, and help the team iterate quickly.</p>
<p>Using efficient tools to leave work early every day.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-issues-in-the-construction">Some issues in the construction<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard#some-issues-in-the-construction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some issues in the construction" title="Direkter Link zu Some issues in the construction">​</a></h2>
<p>The business of each company is distributed across different systems, and there are some connections between these systems. Some data needs to be queried using databases:</p>
<ul>
<li>Postgresql</li>
<li>Mysql</li>
<li>MongoDB</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>Some data comes from different types of microservices, possibly obtained from a specific API:</p>
<ul>
<li>User Detail API</li>
<li>Product Detail API</li>
<li>...</li>
</ul>
<p>The most challenging thing is that some data requires merging and secondary processing of both database and API data.</p>
<p>These issues make it very troublesome to build a personalized data dashboard. If starting development from scratch, we need to adapt to different data sources, leading to a steep increase in engineering costs.</p>
<p>Therefore, we need a flexible tool for displaying data dashboards, as "development" is not the most important; "display" is.</p>
<p>This tool needs some objective advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rich charts to display data from different dimensions.</li>
<li>Support for various mainstream data sources.</li>
<li>Simple installation and usage.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="how-to-solve">How to solve<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard#how-to-solve" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu How to solve" title="Direkter Link zu How to solve">​</a></h2>
<p>Here, I recommend a user-friendly open-source project called ILLA Cloud. ILLA Cloud is a low-code tool specifically designed to address scenarios with personalized requirements.</p>
<p>📙 Official website: <a href="https://illa.cloud/?utm_source=juejin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://illa.cloud</a></p>
<p>⏬ Github repository: <a href="https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/illacloud/illa-builder</a></p>
<p>⭐ Github Stars: 9k</p>
<p>Below is a demo using fake data, depicting the sales situation of a product in a company, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Monthly sales growth trends</li>
<li>Monthly revenue</li>
<li>Total revenue obtained</li>
<li>Number of purchasers</li>
<li>Detailed information about each purchasing user</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/build-dashboard/data-dashboard.png" alt="data_dashboard" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<p>This chart uses several components:</p>
<ul>
<li>Data Grid</li>
<li>Chart</li>
<li>Statistic</li>
<li>Menu</li>
</ul>
<p>It was quickly built through drag and drop. The data sources come from:</p>
<ul>
<li>Supabase: A Serverless Postgresql</li>
<li>API</li>
</ul>
<p>ILLA supports various data sources, allowing quick retrieval of data from a wide range of mainstream sources.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/build-dashboard/integration.png" alt="integration" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="ai-driven">AI-driven<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard#ai-driven" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu AI-driven" title="Direkter Link zu AI-driven">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA not only provides a dashboard but also allows the queried data to be processed further using LLM (Language Model). For example, a set of messy data can be processed into another format as required, enabling alignment of data from multiple sources.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="advantages">Advantages<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard#advantages" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Advantages" title="Direkter Link zu Advantages">​</a></h2>
<p>Building a beautiful dashboard is quick and easy using drag and drop within a few minutes.</p>
<p>Moreover, compared to various traditional BI tools, ILLA Cloud:</p>
<ul>
<li>Supports data querying from both databases and APIs</li>
<li>Simple installation, directly usable on the web page without any downloads</li>
<li>For secondary data processing, uses Javascript for direct and simple processing</li>
<li>Supports various mainstream charts, meeting most requirements</li>
<li>The Transformer feature effectively solves the problem of merging and processing data between multiple sources, eliminating worries about data format issues</li>
</ul>
<p>As an open-source project, ILLA Cloud also supports secondary development, with an active community for collaboration with other developers. No need to worry about maintenance issues.</p>
<p>Additionally, ILLA Cloud can not only build data dashboards but also quickly create exclusive management dashboards, accelerating your business iteration.</p>
<p>As a low-code tool, ILLA Cloud also supports collaboration among multiple people, allowing them to build dashboards together.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.illacloud.com/illa-website/blog/build-dashboard/collaboration.png" alt="collaboration" class="img_CfaS"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/build-dashboard#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>After using ILLA Cloud, there's no need to worry about the boss's personalized requirements. Within a few minutes, you can build a personalized data dashboard for the boss, becoming a highly efficient employee. Why not give it a try now!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>data dashboard</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 7 Redis GUI Tools in 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023</link>
            <guid>https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Looking for the best Redis GUI tool for your application? Read this blog post to learn about the top 7 Redis GUI tools in 2023 and how to use them. Find out why ILLA Cloud is the best Redis GUI tool in our opinion.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for the best Redis GUI tool for your application? Read this blog post to learn about the top 7 Redis GUI tools in 2023 and how to use them. Find out why ILLA Cloud is the best Redis GUI tool in our opinion.</p>
<p>Redis is a popular open-source, in-memory data structure store that can be used as a database, cache, message broker, and more. Redis supports various data types like strings, lists, sets, hashes, and streams. Redis also offers many features like transactions, replication, clustering, pub/sub, Lua scripting, and more.</p>
<p>However, working with Redis can be challenging without a graphical user interface (GUI) to help you visualize and interact with your data. A Redis GUI tool can help you browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys, run commands and queries, monitor performance and metrics, and more.</p>
<p>Many Redis GUI tools are available in the market, each with its own features, pros and cons, and price. This blog post will review the top 7 Redis GUI tools in 2023 and compare them based on their functionality, usability, compatibility, and cost. We will also show you how to use ILLA Cloud, the best Redis GUI tool, to build a Redis GUI for your application.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud">ILLA Cloud<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#illa-cloud" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud">​</a></h2>
<p>ILLA Cloud is an open-source low-code platform for building internal tools. It is a powerful and flexible UI library for building web applications that connect to your databases and APIs. You can use ILLA Cloud to build anything from simple forms and tables to complex applications with advanced features.</p>
<p>ILLA Cloud supports Redis as one of its data sources. You can connect to your Redis server or cluster using ILLA Cloud and access your data using a graphical interface. You can also run commands and queries using SQL and JavaScript. You can use template syntax to inject dynamic values into your components and queries. You can also customize and control your components with JavaScript.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="illa-cloud-has-many-advantages-over-other-redis-gui-tools-some-of-them-are">ILLA Cloud has many advantages over other Redis GUI tools. Some of them are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#illa-cloud-has-many-advantages-over-other-redis-gui-tools-some-of-them-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud has many advantages over other Redis GUI tools. Some of them are:" title="Direkter Link zu ILLA Cloud has many advantages over other Redis GUI tools. Some of them are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is free and open-source. You can use ILLA Cloud without paying any fees or licenses. You can also contribute to the project on GitHub and help improve it.</li>
<li>It is cross-platform and cloud-based. You can use ILLA Cloud on any device and operating system. You can also deploy it on your own server or use the ILLA Cloud service.</li>
<li>It supports multiple data sources. You can connect to various databases and APIs using ILLA Cloud, such as PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Stripe, Google Sheets, AWS S3, and more. You can also integrate with any data source connected through APIs.</li>
<li>It has a drag-and-drop interface. You can build a user interface for your application by dragging and dropping components like tables, charts, forms, buttons, and more. You don’t need to write any HTML or CSS code.</li>
<li>It has a rich set of components. You can use dozens of components in ILLA Cloud to meet your needs in different scenarios. You can also customize them with JavaScript.</li>
<li>It supports JavaScript inside widgets, queries, and other components. Using JavaScript, you can add logic, transform data, and define complex workflows. You can also use template syntax to inject dynamic values into your components and queries.</li>
<li>It has a collaborative feature. You can work with other developers on the same project by sharing links. You can also chat with them in real time and give feedback.</li>
<li>It has a friendly community. You can join the Discord community of ILLA Cloud and get support from other users and developers. You can also share feedback, ask questions, and get updates.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="to-use-illa-cloud-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps">To use ILLA Cloud to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#to-use-illa-cloud-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu To use ILLA Cloud to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:" title="Direkter Link zu To use ILLA Cloud to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sign up for a free account on the ILLA Cloud website.</li>
<li>Create a new project and choose Redis as your data source.</li>
<li>Enter your Redis connection details (hostname or IP address, port number, password, and database number).</li>
<li>Click on Connect button to connect to your Redis server or cluster.</li>
<li>Once connected, you will see your Redis keys on the left panel. You can browse, filter, and search them by name, type, or value. You can also edit or delete them by right-clicking on them.</li>
<li>To run commands or queries on your Redis data, click on the Query tab on the top panel. You can write SQL or JavaScript in the editor. You can use template syntax to inject dynamic values into your queries. You can also use auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can run your queries by clicking the Run button or pressing Ctrl+Enter. You will see the results on the right panel. You can also export the results as CSV or JSON files.</li>
<li>To build a user interface for your application, click on the Builder tab on the top panel. You will see a grid-style canvas where you can drag and drop components from the left panel. You can choose from various components like tables, charts, forms, buttons, etc. You can also customize and control your components with JavaScript. You can use template syntax to inject dynamic values into your components. You can also bind your components to your queries and data sources.</li>
<li>To preview your application, click on the Preview button on the top right corner. You will see how your application looks and works in a browser. You can also test your components and queries and see the results.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it! You have built a Redis GUI for your application using ILLA Cloud. You can now use it to visualize and interact with your Redis data.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="redisinsight">RedisInsight<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#redisinsight" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu RedisInsight" title="Direkter Link zu RedisInsight">​</a></h2>
<p>RedisInsight is a desktop manager for Redis that provides an intuitive and efficient UI for Redis and Redis Stack. It supports all Redis deployments, such as Redis Open Source, Redis Stack, Redis Enterprise Software, Redis Enterprise Cloud, or Amazon ElastiCache.</p>
<p>RedisInsight allows you to browse and interact with Redis data using a graphical interface. You can also run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can also explore the latest capabilities offered by Redis, such as documents, graphs, time series, and more.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-redisinsight-are">Some of the advantages of RedisInsight are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-redisinsight-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of RedisInsight are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of RedisInsight are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is free and easy to use. You can download RedisInsight for free and install it on your Linux, Windows, or macOS machine. You can also check out the GitHub project and provide feedback.</li>
<li>It supports multiple operating systems and Redis deployments. You can use RedisInsight on any device and operating system. You can also connect to any Redis server or cluster using RedisInsight.</li>
<li>It has a graphical interface for Redis data. Using a graphical interface, you can browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys. You can also display data in various formats like JSON, hexadecimal, MessagePack, and more. You can also use the Tree view to group data and enhance the navigation.</li>
<li>It has a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You can run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can also use the Workbench feature to run commands and queries using a Monaco Editor.</li>
<li>It supports the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You can query, visualize, and interactively work with complex data models such as documents, graphs, time series, etc. You can also explore queryable JSON documents, full-text search, probabilistic data structures, and more.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redisinsight-are">Some of the drawbacks of RedisInsight are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redisinsight-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of RedisInsight are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of RedisInsight are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not open-source. You cannot contribute to or modify the project according to your needs.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using RedisInsight.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using RedisInsight.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="redis-desktop-manager-respapp">Redis Desktop Manager (RESP.app)<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#redis-desktop-manager-respapp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Redis Desktop Manager (RESP.app)" title="Direkter Link zu Redis Desktop Manager (RESP.app)">​</a></h2>
<p>Redis Desktop Manager is a cross-platform desktop GUI for Redis. It lets you connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters and manage your data using a graphical interface. You can also run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-redis-desktop-manager-are">Some of the advantages of Redis Desktop Manager are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-redis-desktop-manager-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redis Desktop Manager are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redis Desktop Manager are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is cross-platform and desktop-based. You can use Redis Desktop Manager on Linux, Windows, or macOS machines. You can also install it as a snap package or a docker image.</li>
<li>It supports multiple Redis servers and clusters. You can connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters using Redis Desktop Manager. You can also import and export connections using JSON files.</li>
<li>It has a graphical interface for Redis data. Using a graphical interface, you can browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys. You can also display data in various formats like JSON, hexadecimal, MessagePack, and more. You can also use the Tree view to group data and enhance the navigation.</li>
<li>It has a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You can run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. Using a terminal-like interface, you can also use the Console feature to run commands and queries.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redis-desktop-manager-are">Some of the drawbacks of Redis Desktop Manager are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redis-desktop-manager-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redis Desktop Manager are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redis Desktop Manager are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not free or open-source. You have to pay a subscription fee to use Redis Desktop Manager. The free version has limited features and functionality.</li>
<li>It does not support the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You cannot query, visualize, or interact with complex data models such as documents, graphs, time series, etc.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using Redis Desktop Manager.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using Redis Desktop Manager.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="medis">Medis<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#medis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Medis" title="Direkter Link zu Medis">​</a></h2>
<p>Medis is a beautiful and easy-to-use Mac database management application for Redis. It lets you connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters and manage your data using a graphical interface. You can also run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-medis-are">Some of the advantages of Medis are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-medis-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Medis are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Medis are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is beautiful and easy-to-use. Medis has a sleek and intuitive design that makes it easy to use. It also has dark mode support that makes it look even better.</li>
<li>It is Mac-based and desktop-based. You can use Medis on any Mac machine. You can also install it from the Mac App Store or download it from GitHub.</li>
<li>It supports multiple Redis servers and clusters. You can connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters using Medis. You can also import and export connections using JSON files.</li>
<li>It has a graphical interface for Redis data. Using a graphical interface, you can browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys. You can also display data in various formats like JSON, hexadecimal, MessagePack, and more. You can also use the Tree view to group data and enhance the navigation.</li>
<li>It has a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You can run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. Using a terminal-like interface, you can also use the Terminal feature to run commands and queries.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-medis-are">Some of the drawbacks of Medis are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-medis-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Medis are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Medis are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not free or open-source. You have to pay a subscription fee to use Medis. The free version has limited features and functionality.</li>
<li>It is only available for Mac. You cannot use Medis on other operating systems or devices.</li>
<li>It does not support the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You cannot query, visualize, or interact with complex data models such as documents, graphs, time series, and more.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using Medis.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using Medis.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="to-use-medis-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps">To use Medis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#to-use-medis-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu To use Medis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:" title="Direkter Link zu To use Medis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Download Medis from the Mac App Store or GitHub.</li>
<li>Install Medis on your Mac machine.</li>
<li>Launch Medis and click on Add Connection button.</li>
<li>Enter your Redis connection details (host name or IP address, port number, password, and database number).</li>
<li>Click on Connect button to connect to your Redis server or cluster.</li>
<li>Once connected, you will see your Redis keys on the left panel. You can browse, filter, and search them by name, type, or value. You can also edit or delete them by right-clicking on them.</li>
<li>To run commands or queries on your Redis data, click on CLI tab on the bottom panel. You can write commands or queries in the editor. You can use auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can run your commands or queries by clicking on Execute button or pressing Ctrl+Enter. You will see the results on the right panel.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it! You have built a Redis GUI for your application using Medis. You can now use it to visualize and interact with your Redis data.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="redis-commander">Redis Commander<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#redis-commander" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Redis Commander" title="Direkter Link zu Redis Commander">​</a></h2>
<p>Redis Commander is a free and open-source Redis management tool written in Node.js. It allows you to connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters and manage your data using a web-based interface. You can also run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-redis-commander-are">Some of the advantages of Redis Commander are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-redis-commander-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redis Commander are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redis Commander are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is free and open-source. You can use Redis Commander without paying any fees or licenses. You can also contribute to the project on GitHub and help improve it.</li>
<li>It is web-based and cross-platform. You can use Redis Commander on any device and operating system. You need to install it on your server and access it through a web browser.</li>
<li>It supports multiple Redis servers and clusters. You can connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters using Redis Commander. You can also import and export connections using JSON files.</li>
<li>It has a web-based interface for Redis data. Using a web-based interface, you can browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys. You can also display data in various formats like JSON, hexadecimal, MessagePack, and more. You can also use the Tree view to group data and enhance the navigation.</li>
<li>It has a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You can run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redis-commander-are">Some of the drawbacks of Redis Commander are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redis-commander-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redis Commander are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redis Commander are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not very stable or reliable. Redis Commander may have bugs or issues affecting its performance or functionality. It may also crash or freeze sometimes.</li>
<li>It does not support the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You cannot query, visualize, or interact with complex data models such as documents, graphs, time series, and more.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using Redis Commander.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using Redis Commander.</li>
</ul>
<p>To use Redis Commander to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="download-redis-commander-from-github-or-npm">Download Redis Commander from GitHub or npm.<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#download-redis-commander-from-github-or-npm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Download Redis Commander from GitHub or npm." title="Direkter Link zu Download Redis Commander from GitHub or npm.">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Install Redis Commander on your server using Node.js.</li>
<li>Launch Redis Commander by running redis-commander command in your terminal.</li>
<li>Access Redis Commander through your web browser by entering <a href="http://localhost:8081/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://localhost:8081</a> in your address bar.</li>
<li>Click on Add Redis Server button to add your Redis connection details (host name or IP address, port number, password, and database number).</li>
<li>Click on Connect button to connect to your Redis server or cluster.</li>
<li>Once connected, you will see your Redis keys on the left panel. You can browse, filter, and search them by name, type, or value. You can also edit or delete them by right-clicking on them.</li>
<li>To run commands or queries on your Redis data, click on Console tab on the top panel. You can write commands or queries in the editor. You can use auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can run your commands or queries by clicking on Execute button or pressing Ctrl+Enter. You will see the results on the right panel.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it! You have built a Redis GUI for your application using Redis Commander. You can now use it to visualize and interact with your Redis data.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="redsmin">Redsmin<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#redsmin" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Redsmin" title="Direkter Link zu Redsmin">​</a></h2>
<p>Redsmin is a cloud-based Redis management service that provides a real-time interface for Redis and Redis Stack. It supports all Redis deployments, such as Redis Open Source, Redis Stack, Redis Enterprise Software, Redis Enterprise Cloud, or Amazon ElastiCache.</p>
<p>Redsmin allows you to browse and interact with Redis data using a web-based interface. You can also run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can also monitor the performance and metrics of your Redis server or cluster using a dashboard.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-redsmin-are">Some of the advantages of Redsmin are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-redsmin-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redsmin are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Redsmin are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is cloud-based and cross-platform. You can use Redsmin on any device and operating system. You must install a proxy daemon on your server and access it through a web browser.</li>
<li>It supports multiple Redis servers and clusters. You can connect to multiple Redis servers and clusters using Redsmin. You can also import and export connections using JSON files.</li>
<li>It has a web-based interface for Redis data. Using a web-based interface, you can browse, filter, edit, and delete your Redis keys. You can also display data in various formats like JSON, hexadecimal, MessagePack, and more. You can also use the Tree view to group data and enhance the navigation.</li>
<li>It has a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You can run commands and queries using a built-in CLI with auto-completion and syntax highlighting features.</li>
<li>It supports the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You can query, visualize, and interact with complex data models such as documents, graphs, and time series. You can also explore queryable JSON documents, full-text search, probabilistic data structures, and more.</li>
<li>It has a dashboard for monitoring performance and metrics. You can monitor your Redis server's or cluster's performance and metrics using a dashboard. You can see commands processed in real-time and inspect slow commands. You can also troubleshoot performance issues and debug your Redis server.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redsmin-are">Some of the drawbacks of Redsmin are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-redsmin-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redsmin are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Redsmin are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not free or open-source. You have to pay a subscription fee to use Redsmin. The free version has limited features and functionality.</li>
<li>It requires a proxy daemon installation. You must install a proxy daemon on your server to connect to Redsmin. This may affect your security or performance.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using Redsmin.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using Redsmin.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="to-use-redsmin-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps">To use Redsmin to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#to-use-redsmin-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu To use Redsmin to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:" title="Direkter Link zu To use Redsmin to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sign up for a free account on the Redsmin website.</li>
<li>Download and install the proxy daemon on your server using Node.js.</li>
<li>Launch the proxy daemon by running redsmin command in your terminal.</li>
<li>Enter your Redsmin API key when prompted.</li>
<li>Access Redsmin through your web browser by entering <a href="https://app.redsmin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://app.redsmin.com</a> in your address bar.</li>
<li>Click on Add Redis Server button to add your Redis connection details (hostname or IP address, port number, password, and database number).</li>
<li>Click on Connect button to connect to your Redis server or cluster.</li>
<li>Once connected, you will see your Redis keys on the left panel. You can browse, filter, and search them by name, type, or value. You can also edit or delete them by right-clicking on them.</li>
<li>To run commands or queries on your Redis data, click on the Console tab on the top panel. You can write commands or queries in the editor. You can use auto-completion and syntax highlighting features. You can run your commands or queries by clicking on Execute button or pressing Ctrl+Enter. You will see the results on the right panel.</li>
<li>To explore the latest capabilities offered by Redis, click on the corresponding tabs on the top panel. You can choose from various modules, such as RedisJSON, RedisGraph, and RedisTimeSeries. Using a web-based interface, you can query, visualize, and interact with complex data models.</li>
<li>To monitor your Redis server's or cluster's performance and metrics, click on the Dashboard tab on the top panel. You can see commands processed in real-time and inspect slow commands. You can also troubleshoot performance issues and debug your Redis server.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it! You have built a Redis GUI for your application using Redsmin. You can now use it to visualize and interact with your Redis data.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="webdis">Webdis<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#webdis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Webdis" title="Direkter Link zu Webdis">​</a></h2>
<p>Webdis is a simple web server that exposes Redis commands as HTTP endpoints with JSON output. It allows you to connect to your Redis server and access your data using a web browser or any HTTP client. You can also run commands and queries using HTTP requests.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-advantages-of-webdis-are">Some of the advantages of Webdis are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-advantages-of-webdis-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Webdis are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the advantages of Webdis are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is simple and lightweight. Webdis is a simple web server that requires no installation or configuration. It is also very fast and consumes little memory.</li>
<li>It is open-source and free. You can use Webdis without paying any fees or licenses. You can also contribute to the project on GitHub and help improve it.</li>
<li>It supports multiple operating systems and Redis deployments. You can use Webdis on Linux, Windows, or macOS machines. You can also connect to any Redis server or cluster using Webdis.</li>
<li>It has a web-based interface for Redis data. You can browse and interact with Redis data using a web browser or any HTTP client. You can also display data in JSON format.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="some-of-the-drawbacks-of-webdis-are">Some of the drawbacks of Webdis are:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#some-of-the-drawbacks-of-webdis-are" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Webdis are:" title="Direkter Link zu Some of the drawbacks of Webdis are:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>It is not very secure or reliable. Webdis does not support authentication or encryption for your Redis connection. It may also expose your Redis data to unauthorized access or modification.</li>
<li>It does not support the latest capabilities offered by Redis. You cannot query, visualize, or interact with complex data models such as documents, graphs, time series, and more.</li>
<li>It does not support multiple data sources. You cannot connect to other databases or APIs using Webdis.</li>
<li>It does not have a built-in CLI for running commands and queries. You have to use HTTP requests to run commands and queries on your Redis data.</li>
<li>It does not have a drag-and-drop interface for building user interfaces. You cannot build a user interface for your application using Webdis.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="to-use-webdis-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps">To use Webdis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#to-use-webdis-to-build-a-redis-gui-for-your-application-you-need-to-follow-these-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu To use Webdis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:" title="Direkter Link zu To use Webdis to build a Redis GUI for your application, you need to follow these steps:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Download Webdis from GitHub or compile it from the source code.</li>
<li>Launch Webdis by running webdis the command in your terminal.</li>
<li>Access Webdis through your web browser by entering <a href="http://localhost:7379/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://localhost:7379</a> in your address bar.</li>
<li>Enter your Redis command or query in the URL path after the slash. For example, <a href="http://localhost:7379/GET/foo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://localhost:7379/GET/foo</a> will get the value of the key foo.</li>
</ul>
<p>See the result of your command or query in JSON format in your browser.
That’s it! You have built a Redis GUI for your application using Webdis. You can now use it to access and interact with your Redis data.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_dXVO" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://illacloud.github.io/illa-website/de/blog/top-7-redis-gui-tools-in-2023#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zu Conclusion" title="Direkter Link zu Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>In this blog post, we have reviewed the top 7 Redis GUI tools in 2023 and compared them based on their functionality, usability, compatibility, and cost. We have also shown you how to use each tool to build a Redis GUI for your application.</p>
<p>We hope this blog post has helped you find the best Redis GUI tool for your needs and preferences. However, if you ask us, we recommend ILLA Cloud as the best Redis GUI tool.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>redis</category>
            <category>gui</category>
            <category>tools</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>